<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>purpose on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/purpose/</link><description>Recent content in purpose on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 08:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/purpose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You Have Time</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/you-have-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 08:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/you-have-time/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-you-have-time.jpg" alt="You Have Time" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m taking a break from &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">my hatred of all things&lt;/a> news to take a step back and write about &lt;em>why&lt;/em> I&amp;rsquo;ve been so negative in these recent posts about the news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not against entertainment. I think it serves a valuable role in our lives. I like watching a football game or hearing about things that are none of my business. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I just no longer fool myself into thinking that it matters.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s just entertainment. This isn&amp;rsquo;t life or death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I read books so I can grow into a better person, that takes time. When I &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/">ride my bike&lt;/a> to work every day instead of driving a car, that takes time. When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/">I read&lt;/a>, spend time with my family, volunteer, that all takes time. And our first reaction to changing things up in order &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">to live out our values is&lt;/a>: I don&amp;rsquo;t have time. I disagree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You have time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I said that right. &lt;strong>You have tons of time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you don&amp;rsquo;t have time to consume the news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you never watch TV for anything ever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you don&amp;rsquo;t get a full night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you never do anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve feeding or sheltering your family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You have time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My time waster is the news. I used to spend literally hours a day reading and thinking about it. Yours might be different. Whatever it is, see it for what it is, put things in perspective, and focus on what really matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is not: When will I have enough time to do what matters?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is: &lt;strong>When will I stop doing what doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter so I&amp;rsquo;ll have enough time to do what matters?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That mindset change will change your life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Escaping with the News</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-escaping-with-the-news.jpg" alt="Escaping with the News" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I was having a great time at a party at my house recently, when a friend of mine who is quite conservative started talking to me about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012_Benghazi_attack">the Benghazi incident of September 2012&lt;/a>. He went on and on about how outrageous it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I respond, &amp;ldquo;I just don&amp;rsquo;t see how any of this is important or relevant to my life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With an outraged tone, he responds with eyes wide open in outrage, &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t think &lt;em>Benghazi&lt;/em> is important???&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To my life? No, I don&amp;rsquo;t. In fact I can take that a step further: &lt;strong>the news, especially political news is designed to get people to get outraged over things that are not in their power to change or influence.&lt;/strong> This state of frustration and anger puts them in a place where they are willing to buy more things in the advertisements, which is good for the provider of the outrageous news. But for the person who is consuming it, it is the very definition of a waste of time: spending time on something one doesn&amp;rsquo;t find enjoying, can&amp;rsquo;t do anything about, and causes them to act in ways that are outside of their values. This is insanity!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to propose we ask a question about every news article that we consume from now on: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>How will my life change as a result of me knowing this information?&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I propose the answer is, for the most part, &amp;ldquo;none at all&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To illustrate, let&amp;rsquo;s comment on some CNN and Fox News headlines as of the date of first writing this, July 26, 2014:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Story&lt;/th>
&lt;th>How will my life change as a result of me knowing this information&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/26/world/meast/mideast-crisis/index.html?hpt=hp_t1">Rockets fired; Israel-Hamas truce appears over&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. The rockets likely won&amp;rsquo;t make it to North Texas. There is no election today to influence our political establishment, and political leadership in the U.S. seem to be aligned (for the most part).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/26/world/africa/libya-us-embassy-evacuation/index.html?hpt=hp_t2">U.S. evacuates embassy in Tripoli&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am in North Texas, not Tripoli. I have nothing to be afraid of by whatever is happening there.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/joe-paterno-feared-wrongly-accusing-sandusky-son-says/?intcmp=latestnews">Joe Paterno Feared Wrongly Accusing Sandusky, Son Says&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am not nor do I have any friends who are a part of this case. While it is a tragedy, me knowing about the state of mind of one of the participants of the case, who is now dead, will have no bearing on the outcome of the case whatsoever.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/officials-cite-marijuana-as-reason-for-rise-in-denver-homeless/?intcmp=latestnews">Officials cite marijuana as reason for rise in Denver homeless&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I live in North Texas, not Denver. I do not use marijuana. I suppose if I did this news article wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change my mind about it. There is no marijuana vote on the Texas ballot today for me to vote on.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2014/07/26/some-in-cia-torture-report-denied-chance-to-read-it/?intcmp=latestnews">Some in CIA &amp;lsquo;torture&amp;rsquo; report denied chance to read it&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am not subject to torture or defining what torture is in the coming months as far as I know. In fact if I were to be tortured, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that this report would have anything to do with how I would be treated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/colorado-business-owner-fights-back-after-falling-victim-to-caller-id-spoofing/?intcmp=latestnews">Colorado business owner fights back after falling victim to &amp;lsquo;caller ID spoofing'&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I have managed to live my life for 35 years without knowing what the term &amp;ldquo;caller id spoofing&amp;rdquo; means. Even if there were a risk, I suppose I would hear about it from the phone company. The fact that it&amp;rsquo;s on a news site tells me that it is a rare occurrence. Besides, I don&amp;rsquo;t even own a business so there is absolutely no chance of anything in this article affecting my life.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/fast-food-workers-vow-civil-disobedience-in-wage-fight/?intcmp=latestnews">Fast food workers vow civil disobedience in wage fight&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I don&amp;rsquo;t work at McDonald&amp;rsquo;s. I also don&amp;rsquo;t eat there very often. I suppose if their wages do go up, the price of a Happy Meal will eventually go up, thus creating an unexpected surprise on the rare occasion that I go to McDonalds. But we&amp;rsquo;re quite a ways from this: they are &lt;em>vowing &lt;/em>civil disobedience. Nothing has actually happened. This affects my life in no way whatsoever.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Let me give you a little guarantee: If you play this game for a few days on the news sites you are visiting, you will very quickly be awakened to the reality that this all is a complete and total waste of your time. &lt;strong>You are a pawn in someone else&amp;rsquo;s game to get you to buy stuff.&lt;/strong> There actually isn&amp;rsquo;t news on almost every day. And when there is it can be summed up in a ten second brief description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let&amp;rsquo;s stop investing so much time in &amp;ldquo;news&amp;rdquo; and make some &lt;em>real&lt;/em> news in our own lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Our Culture's Script</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/our-cultures-script/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/our-cultures-script/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-our-cultures-script.jpg" alt="Our Culture Script" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We want our lives to be &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">a work of art&lt;/a> and reflect the beauty and meaning of our values. Most of us in search of meaning in our lives will naturally absorb our culture&amp;rsquo;s script for us:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>To create a beautiful work of art, you must feel good. To feel good, first you must make good money. You need to go to school and then get a good, stable job.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Once you get the job, start maximizing convenience. Pay for things you no longer want to do, including mowing the lawn, making meals, washing your car, fixing your house, going to the store. You work hard so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do these things.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Also, make sure you are as comfortable as possible. Get a nice big house you can be comfortable in, a nice, new car with leather seats that feel great, and stop at the ice cream store and give yourself a treat that makes you feel like a kid again. You deserve it because you work hard.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>You won&amp;rsquo;t be happy unless other people respect and want to be like you. So when you get a car, get something that will show everyone how hard you have worked. When you go on vacation, make sure it&amp;rsquo;s something totally awesome that will show how you have great taste and can afford the finer things in life. You want to be the best you can be. You&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard for this.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>You need to be happy. That&amp;rsquo;s what life is about. So make as much money as possible and spend that mainly on three things: convenience so you can focus on the things that really matter, comfort so you won&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by annoyances and pain and can focus on enjoying life, and respect so you can be validated that you have done something meaningful with your life.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with this? Well, nothing if it works. The problem is, when we think through this approach we don&amp;rsquo;t actually see anyone reaping its benefits. Instead we see millionaires that need more. Actors who are on drugs. Affairs. It&amp;rsquo;s an absolute mess out there. There&amp;rsquo;s never an end. There&amp;rsquo;s never enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t a good way to create a life of meaning and value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to sell stuff though.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This script does nothing about the biggest human problem: &lt;strong>no matter how much you have today, you always need more.&lt;/strong> Once you realize that, the above description becomes silly. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uEY58fiSK8E">You&amp;rsquo;ll never have too much convenience&lt;/a>. No matter how much comfort you have, you know people who have more and that makes you feel…uncomfortable. There will always be someone who gets more respect than you do. Your needs are &lt;em>insatiable.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is unavoidable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution? &lt;strong>Accept insatiability as a fact of life,&lt;/strong> dealing with it on a regular basis, and you will have a shot at sanity. How do you do this? Keep reading to find out.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>