<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>leadership on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/leadership/</link><description>Recent content in leadership on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 08:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Progression of Responsibility</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-progression-of-responsibility.jpg" alt="Progression of Responsibility" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>While reading &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zxdulv">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, I&amp;rsquo;m coming up with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/">a lot of great ideas&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">improvements for my organization&lt;/a>. Much of the book so far has been about how to properly execute portfolio management within an enterprise to make sure that (1) you maximize ROI, and (2) you don&amp;rsquo;t manage your existing proven products with an investment horizon of this year or this quarter the same way that you would manage innovation products that have a longer investment horizon. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something occurred to me though. In order to gain entry into the higher level strategic decisions, one must first master the lower level ones. Here&amp;rsquo;s a progression I can see, that I wish I knew about ten years ago:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Personal Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you take on work in an efficient, organized way? Do you have a system for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/" title="Getting Things Done Action Plan">getting things done&lt;/a>, a system for communicating with others, for follow-up, for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">what to do when things get difficult&lt;/a>? Do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/" title="Two Questions You Should Ask About Your Commitments">when you&amp;rsquo;re overcommitting&lt;/a>?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Planning Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you understand why we are doing what we are doing on this project? Do you measure things in terms of how they will profit your company or on some other, less meaningful way? Do you have a way to create value for your stakeholders quickly by strategically prioritizing certain things over others? Do you know what the short-term and long-term risks to the product and what can be done about them?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Management Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/" title="Measure for Reality">how to measure success&lt;/a>? Have you linked the measurement to profitability of the company? Are you able to iteratively create improvements to measurements in a fluid, changing situation? Are people motivated by your leadership and understand the parameters that you&amp;rsquo;ve set out that measures your team&amp;rsquo;s success?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Executive Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> are you able to create profitability for the various products in your portfolio in a way that respects their lifecycle? Are your established, older products increasing in quality and customer satisfaction? Have your newer innovative products succeeded in creating new markets, as measured by appropriate metrics? Has your team leadership received the appropriate amount of direction (not too detailed to constrain innovation and not too broad to create chaos)? Have you had innovation experiments that have failed in the past three months, that had minimal investment yet provided a valuable lesson for the leadership team?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Right now I&amp;rsquo;m at #3. It&amp;rsquo;s fun reading about #4 in the book, but I do realize the trap of trying to live in a place that is beyond your current capability:** If you live in a later stage than you&amp;rsquo;re at right now, you end up ignoring the key elements that are needed to progress to the next stage.** So I can start thinking a lot about portfolio management or how we would manage innovative products differently than our established products. But if I get too caught up in that, I avoid the reality for me right now: I need to find a measurement of success that leads to profitability of my company for every project that I&amp;rsquo;m doing, be able to communicate that to others, and manage its improvement with a team. That will be my focus over the next year or so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone comes to me about how we need to do a better job planning yet don&amp;rsquo;t have an established workflow for how they manage their own work, I quickly get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone wants to be a manager of a group but can&amp;rsquo;t see what that group is doing strategically and the trade-offs that exist in the group, I get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to master your current responsibilities before you can progress to others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Son's Choice Between Negativity and Taking Action</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action.jpg" alt="Negativity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My son has felt negative about everything lately which has created for him a vicious cycle of disdain and despair. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/embrace-difficulty/" title="Embrace Difficulty">He is a lot like me&lt;/a>, so whenever we learn a lesson about him, it usually has something to do with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">how I&amp;rsquo;m wired as well&lt;/a>. He and I sat in bed a few nights ago and I walked him through this very basic method of how leaders have a choice to make:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I talked about how he and I are gifted with the ability to think deeply about things and thus we see things that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.** We have the responsibility of being able to see problems that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.** Something that bothers him is how his cub scout pack meetings spend too much time talking to the parents and that leaves him feeling like the meeting isn&amp;rsquo;t his. When I asked one of his good friends about cub scouts, his friend said, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m cursed as well about seeing problems everywhere. I talked to a police officer one time that told me that every room he goes into, even if it&amp;rsquo;s a church sanctuary, he automatically tries to ascertain who in that room is a potential threat. That man has a similar curse: he sees problems that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then asked Samuel why he thought President Obama wanted to be President. &amp;ldquo;Because he wanted to be famous.&amp;rdquo; I told him how there are better ways of being famous. The truth is Mr. Obama became President Obama because he saw problems that others didn&amp;rsquo;t see and cared enough about them to get in public life. &lt;strong>A leader always starts with a perception of something wrong in the world.&lt;/strong> If nothing was wrong, there would be no leaders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it&amp;rsquo;s a given that a potential leader sees problems. It is our curse. The question now, is: what are we going to do about it? There are two choices:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A potential leader &lt;em>could&lt;/em> choose the path of negativity, disdain, and ultimately despair.&lt;/strong> This is the path of the critic, the internet troll, or the quitter. This is the path my son was on and one I&amp;rsquo;ve been on many times. I can see what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the situation, and my response is to continue to criticize or believe that nothing will ever change and quit. It&amp;rsquo;s even easier to do this when &lt;em>I&amp;rsquo;m the only one who sees the problems!&lt;/em> Well of course you&amp;rsquo;re the only one who sees the problems; perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re the one who is supposed to do something about it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Or a potential leader &lt;em>could&lt;/em> choose the path of taking action, improvement, patience, and love.&lt;/strong> In other words &lt;strong>a potential leader could choose the path of leadership.&lt;/strong> This is the path I encouraged Samuel to take. The question isn&amp;rsquo;t what problems do you see with cub scout pack meetings; the question is what are you going to do about those problems? When you see a problem with a group of people, the loving thing you can do is, within your power, help solve that problem with them! It&amp;rsquo;s not to despair and quit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes problems are so deep and impenetrable that there is nothing you can do about them. At that point the best thing to do &lt;em>is&lt;/em> quit. However, most times the problems are there and as a leader we can work to make them better. That&amp;rsquo;s the path of leadership, the path of people who are cursed with the ability to recognize problems that others don&amp;rsquo;t see and choose to take action to solve those problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Focus with the Amazon Kindle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-focus-with-the-amazon-kindle.jpg" alt="Focus with the Kindle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/" title="Life is Art">focusing on what matters&lt;/a> lately by &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">making good choices&lt;/a> with how and what you consume. Some things are just a complete waste of time like the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">local news&lt;/a>. Other things have a good alternative, like &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/">reading the Economist&lt;/a> instead of going to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">news sites&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I wrote last time, though, in this mobile world that isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. You have to make sure your smartphone is serving you and not enslaving you. And beyond that I&amp;rsquo;m convinced &lt;strong>to lead a life of growth and meaning you need to read.&lt;/strong> Probably more than you are right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do we do that? The solutions that come to mind immediately are: on our smartphone, a paper book, or a tablet. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about a better way to read books: through the Amazon Kindle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years back &lt;a href="http://www.chrisdikes.com/">my friend Chris&lt;/a> asked me what I thought about the Kindle, and my opinion to him as of July 16, 2010 was: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>It seems like having a book would be better.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Well, thankfully Chris didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to my awful advice and bought one, told me about it, changed my mind, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s so great about the Kindle:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distractionless:&lt;/strong> yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a feature and not a bug. I like it that there aren&amp;rsquo;t pop ups telling me all about the emails I&amp;rsquo;m not reading or the cool Facebook posts that I need to be looking into. I&amp;rsquo;m here to read. The Kindle helps me read.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Battery Life:&lt;/strong> I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be preoccupied with powering the stupid thing while I&amp;rsquo;m using it. I can read. I have to charge it every once and a while. It&amp;rsquo;s not like the power sucking smartphone or tablet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Position Independent:&lt;/strong> this may seem small to some, but I like reading while I&amp;rsquo;m laying down. And I get comfortable holding a book in one hand. Then I read fast and get to the other side of the book. So I have to move to read the other section. It seems like a small thing, and admittedly a first-world problem, but I love how I can read the Kindle with one hand laying on the same side for as long as it is comfortable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sleep Friendly Lighting:&lt;/strong> I have the Kindle paperwhite that doesn&amp;rsquo;t blast light into my eyes and keep me up. I can do a little nighttime reading with a very small amount of light. It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t distract my wife.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Borrower Capable:&lt;/strong> I have learned to take advantage of my library&amp;rsquo;s borrower privileges on the Kindle. This is easy once you figure it out. I do admit to buying more books than I would have before, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing as long as I read them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Keeps Your Place:&lt;/strong> I pick up the book and read exactly where I left off. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it. I just go.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Read More:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve read much more than before. If I&amp;rsquo;m interested in a topic, I can get a book on that topic and read through it quickly while I have a passion and interest in the book.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Portable:&lt;/strong> I admit to not doing it very often, but if I want to, I can read on my smartphone or even my computer to continue my reading.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I highly recommend going for a Kindle. You need to read to meet your goals, and in my mind there is no better way to do so than with the Kindle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Problem Owner is Solution Owner</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/problem-owner-is-solution-owner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 08:07:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/problem-owner-is-solution-owner/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-problem-owner-is-solution-owner.jpg" alt="Problem Owner" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The room was standing room only. I was playing &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o1tj2zJ2Wvg">Welcome to the Jungle&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; as loud as my company-issued laptop would play. There was a considerable buzz in the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/speaking/">speaking at a conference session&lt;/a> entitled &amp;ldquo;The New Diagnostic Utility.&amp;rdquo; This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a Get Rich Quick with Flipping Real Estate conference session. This was The Diagnostic Utility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What was so jarring about this experience was the lackluster response I had gotten to this tool up until this point. The idea came &lt;a href="www.linkedin.com/in/nicolemillspmp">from a colleague&lt;/a> that dealt with diagnosing environmental issues in sites. She and her team were excited about it. I understood the need. But no one else seemed to be enthused. Why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The conference I was at was full of people who install our software at restaurants all over North America. They had issues that needed to be diagnosed. The title &amp;ldquo;The Diagnostic Utility&amp;rdquo; was translated to them like &amp;ldquo;Save Yourself Hours of Time Making Sure You Did Everything Right&amp;rdquo;. This was the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/safety-net/">safety net&lt;/a> they needed. Their attendance and enthusiasm confirmed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is probably the most valuable lesson I&amp;rsquo;ve learned this year: &lt;strong>a solution is only effective when it is &lt;em>in the hands&lt;/em> of the one that has a problem.&lt;/strong> Not the one that &lt;em>knows&lt;/em> about the problem. Not even the one who is &lt;em>losing money&lt;/em> on the problem. &lt;strong>The one who has the problem.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when your kid doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to get to school on time, the solution is waking up earlier, but it&amp;rsquo;s only effective when your kid &lt;em>wants&lt;/em> to be on time to school to avoid a consequence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a project is proposed but the people who own that process don&amp;rsquo;t believe there&amp;rsquo;s a problem, you don&amp;rsquo;t do the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you&amp;rsquo;re getting frustrated that a customer isn&amp;rsquo;t responsive enough to your solution, perhaps they don&amp;rsquo;t see there is a problem and perhaps you need to find another customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was the case for The New Diagnostic Utility. Once I found the right audience, everything fell into place.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>