<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>salary on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/salary/</link><description>Recent content in salary on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 08:00:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/salary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Increase Income by Negotiating</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/increase-income-by-negotiating/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/increase-income-by-negotiating/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-increase-income-by-negotiating.jpg" alt="Increase Income by Negotiating" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When one &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/">gets serious&lt;/a> about meeting their financial goals, the obvious immediate focus is &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/">to lower expenses&lt;/a>. If you want to get out of debt, stop going to Starbucks. And find a way to be content with not having it anymore. But there is another side of the equation as well: your income.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in 2010 when I shifted my personal finance perspective, I decided to get serious about my income as well as my expenses. And I thankfully found the book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0931213207/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0931213207&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=W6BC6IOM726IEVJK">Negotiating Your Salary: How to Make $1000 a Minute&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://www.salarynegotiations.com/">Jack Chapman&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book changed my thinking in three important ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Everything is negotiable.&lt;/strong> Stop looking at things as fixed. They aren&amp;rsquo;t. You need to create more value for your company, and they will be willing to pay you more. Negotiate for the value that you are creating, and by all means &lt;em>work your butt off&lt;/em> to create the value. But don&amp;rsquo;t just passively go through life accepting whatever is given to you. Negotiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Be intentional.&lt;/strong> Don&amp;rsquo;t let performance reviews happen to you. Be intentional. Be clear about your goals and work with management to accomplish them. Don&amp;rsquo;t just accept what they&amp;rsquo;re telling you, but press in and make sure that they respect you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stop talking.&lt;/strong> When negotiating, the one who talks is the one who is losing. Be simple about your goals and stop talking. This is the part that I struggle with the most. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/speaking/">I can&amp;rsquo;t stop talking&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This turned a perceived static situation I had no control over into a dynamic situation where I increased my value to my employer and in return over time increased my income. It takes a while, but if your goals are realistic and if you work hard, you&amp;rsquo;ll get there. I know as a manager I love managing people who are intentional and motivated to work hard to create an outcome. I&amp;rsquo;ll always take that person over an unmotivated lazy person who is fine with their salary.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>