<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>distraction on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/distraction/</link><description>Recent content in distraction on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 08:00:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/distraction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sanitize Your Smartphone with Republic Wireless</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 08:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless.jpg" alt="Sanitize Smartphone" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The invention of the iPhone will probably be one of the key technological events of my lifetime. It changed the game from quirky Blackberry kind-of-phones, to a new experience that delivered a whole set of new capabilities in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. It has changed &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">the businesses I serve&lt;/a> and will continue to change our lives for years to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I finally got an iPhone it took over my life. This coincided with the birth of my children, so I spent a lot of time on the iPhone while they were at the park, or sleeping, or messing around at our house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Then I realized that I will never get those moments back.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized that the promise of convenience and greater efficiency does not line up with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">my personal goals&lt;/a> because my personal goals are to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">live a life of meaning, love, and connection&lt;/a>, especially with my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To put it more simply, &lt;strong>I was on my phone and ignoring my family.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What to do about this? I considered going away from a smartphone. That didn&amp;rsquo;t seem possible because there were times where it really did serve me. I tried to make a few rules like, &amp;ldquo;Stop ignoring my children&amp;rdquo;, but those didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work when the siren song of Facebook and email came singing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, I was spending over a thousand dollars a year on this habit that wasn&amp;rsquo;t serving me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Then I learned about a better way: Republic Wireless.&lt;/strong> With Republic Wireless, I bought a phone for $300* and now spend $10 a month on my mobile phone. I get data through Wi-Fi, which, by the way, exists at home and at work. I don&amp;rsquo;t get data on the way home from work. If I&amp;rsquo;m traveling, I get the option to change to the $25 a month plan that has data. I can even change it back to the $10 plan when I get home and only pay for the $25 plan prorated for the amount of days I used it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that I don&amp;rsquo;t instinctively go for the phone when I&amp;rsquo;m out and about. It&amp;rsquo;s a tool; it&amp;rsquo;s not my master. It also means if I need it to direct me somewhere I can type in directions before I leave when I&amp;rsquo;m on Wi-Fi, and the smartphone will get me there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like I have the best of both worlds. Combine that with my $10/month landline, I now have no excuse to be on my phone…ever. &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s an accessory. It&amp;rsquo;s not my whole life.&lt;/strong> Now I can live with the best elements of it and leave the rest alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in freeing your life from the insane addiction from the smartphone, you can get $10 off of Republic Wireless (as well as give me $10 off on my bill) by going &lt;a href="http://rwshar.es/6lhy">here&lt;/a>. Enjoy!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can get them even cheaper for $99 for an off-contract phone. Do the math and you&amp;rsquo;ll save a bundle while being able to spend less time on your phone. It&amp;rsquo;s a win-win!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Facing the Ultimate Distraction and Often Losing</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/facing-the-ultimate-distraction-and-often-losing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 08:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/facing-the-ultimate-distraction-and-often-losing/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-facing-the-ultimate-distraction-and-often-losing.jpg" alt="Distraction" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It was around 2008, and I heard about this new way to interact with people in your world. We were at a family gathering, and I started talking about this great application I had found called Facebook. My sister-in-law was delighted that we had finally caught up with her and that we were all going to join in this wonderful new thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those were the days when we were all so clueless about social media that Facebook had to cue us to post stuff, with &amp;ldquo;Michael is . . . &amp;quot; and then you wrote your thought into the text area. So the posts were things like &amp;ldquo;is enjoying my &lt;a href="http://www.nosdiet.com/">s-day&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; on August 23, 2008 and &amp;ldquo;is getting ready to go to India&amp;rdquo; on September 25, 2008 (almost exactly six years ago).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been great. I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed connected to people and shared in the lives of others in a way that I would not have before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a confession to make though:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a very conflicted relationship with Facebook. To understand, let&amp;rsquo;s filter the last few posts I&amp;rsquo;ve written on through the lens of what it promises and what it delivers:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Category&lt;/th>
&lt;th>What it Promises&lt;/th>
&lt;th>What it Delivers&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">Traditional News&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Your world doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter as much as all of these important people doing important things. Know about them so you can influence them&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A visceral and frustrated passion for things over which you have no control&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/">Sports News&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The game will be much more fun if you know EVERYTHING there is to know about it. So know the gossip and facts behind everything you are watching so your hobby can become your life!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Paying way too much attention to sports is a substitute for real growth and changes in your life.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">Local News&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is YOUR WORLD, these are YOUR NEIGHBORS, this stuff can happen to you. So you better pay attention before your lack of attention can cost you dearly.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None of this affects your life, it&amp;rsquo;s just used as a distraction.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Facebook&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This really is your world. We&amp;rsquo;re serious this time. This really does affect you. Why would it not? These are your friends! So pay attention so you can live a more informed life pertaining to your world around you&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This replaces smalltalk which in reality will hurt your relationships with others, not help&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Hopefully that illustrates it for you. The promise of Facebook is so alluring: this is a situation in which being informed can really pay off. After all, this is your life! The problem is there is not a very easy way to filter out the noise within Facebook to get to the reality. And the second problem is that even when people are informed about your life through Facebook, when you finally meet face to face &lt;em>there is nothing to talk about!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You read that correctly. &lt;strong>Facebook, rather than making you &lt;em>more social&lt;/em> actually makes you less social.&lt;/strong> You already know the things about people that you used to talk to them about to gain interest. So over time you talk to people in smalltalk less and less. Over time you are less and less social.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is my conflicted relationship with Facebook. On the one hand I like being in tune with friends and family. On the other hand, that comes at the price of a lot of checking and time. I&amp;rsquo;ve considered over and over giving it up all together. But as my brother says, &lt;a href="http://weknowmemes.com/2011/11/quitting-facebook-is-the-adult-version-of-running-away-from-home/">leaving Facebook is the adult&amp;rsquo;s equivalent of running away from home&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wish I had some answers for you on this one. On paper this is something I should give up, but somehow I keep coming back to it over and over again. Maybe in a year I&amp;rsquo;ll have a good balance. But right now I don&amp;rsquo;t and I just wish the whole thing would go away. Maybe that means I&amp;rsquo;m ready for a break.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rubbernecking with the Locals</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-rubbernecking-with-the-locals.jpg" alt="Local News" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bumper to bumper traffic. Lights ahead. An ambulance speeds by in the shoulder lane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We inch by for a few minutes, and finally make it to the accident. Then something inevitable happens:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>OMG what happened!?!?! I need to brake and see what happened! Are they going to be OK? Do I know them? Is there&amp;hellip;BLOOD?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rubbernecking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is exactly what is happening in the local news. I&amp;rsquo;d like to give you a test to take right now:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Go to your &lt;a href="http://www.wfaa.com">local news site&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Count how many articles that fulfill this criteria:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>You will remember them a month from now&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You didn&amp;rsquo;t hear about them from another source&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They will affect your life in some way&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I just did this as of this writing, on September 5. I counted zero articles. I think that you might come up with a similar amount.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s going on here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We like knowing that no matter how bad things are for us, or how crappy our day is, there are at least a few people on the news that have it worse.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What value does this serve us? Logically speaking, absolutely none. This is a worthless activity. It isn&amp;rsquo;t even &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/">entertaining like sports&lt;/a>. It has no significance in the lifes and livelihood of all but a very small number of people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I&amp;rsquo;m trying to wean myself off of my local news addiction. I&amp;rsquo;m not replacing it with anything. I&amp;rsquo;m just stopping. I&amp;rsquo;ve had varying degrees of success over the past few months, because I love reading the local news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s worthless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to fully believe that one day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sports News: Soap Operas for People Who Make Fun of Soap Operas</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 08:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas.jpg" alt="Sports News" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In the past I used to listen to &lt;em>The Ticket&lt;/em> every day on the way to and from work. I would follow the local teams through ups and downs. When the Dallas Cowboys won their only playoff game in the last almost twenty years, I was turning on The Ticket to hear their analysis. When the Mavericks won their World Championship a few years ago, I celebrated with my friends on the Ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I realized something:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sports News is even more worthless than &amp;ldquo;Real&amp;rdquo; News.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, you are hearing me correctly. I &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">just finished&lt;/a> outlining everything wasteful and dumb about CNN and Fox News, but I&amp;rsquo;m saying sports news is even worse than that. The difference: at least in &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; news we are talking about people&amp;rsquo;s lives and well being. In sports we are talking about a game using the same medium and tone that we talk about people&amp;rsquo;s lives and well being.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of observations really hit this home for me:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sports news &lt;em>loves&lt;/em> the soap opera story.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s funny to think that way, too, since so many sports fans are uber-masculine and would never admit to enjoying soap operas as entertainment. A few examples (as you read these in the tone of an airhead woman in her early twenties talking about a soap opera):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>_OMG did you hear about** &lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/dallas/mlb/story/_/id/11471420/ron-washington-quits-manager-texas-rangers">Ron Washington&lt;/a>?** He RESIGNED today as manager of the Rangers for personal reasons. Jon Daniels says it ISN&amp;rsquo;T about drugs. But who knows? I wonder how the players are feeling?_&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>OMG did you hear about the &lt;a href="http://insider.espn.go.com/blog/nfl/rumors/post/_/id/24032/will-refs-pocket-flags-in-regular-season">number of penalties being called in NFL preseason&lt;/a>? I wonder if, like, the NFL will call those during the REGULAR SEASON!?!?! This might like change the whole game.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>OMG, did you &lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/blog/denver-broncos/post/_/id/8501/wes-welker-roundup-everything-you-need-to-know-about-his-suspension">hear that Wes Welker&lt;/a> is SUSPENDED for FOUR GAMES for taking drugs? I wonder what drugs they are????&amp;hellip;!?!?!?!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is all of this about?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just like the news, this is about sucking people into intrigue over things that don&amp;rsquo;t matter so they&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting there when the advertising comes on. &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s about selling you stuff you normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t buy.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does the nature of Ron Washington&amp;rsquo;s resignation matter? No.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there any effect that you can have on the number of NFL penalties by reading the article? No. No effect. You. Are. Wasting. Your. Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does it matter what Wes Welker did or did not do? To him and his family, it means he makes a few hundred thousand less from multiple millions. To us, it means nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It means nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let that sink in, sports fans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is entertainment. It&amp;rsquo;s not your life. It&amp;rsquo;s not your family. It&amp;rsquo;s not your livelihood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s a business run by people who make a lot of money tricking you into thinking it matters.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that in perspective, by all means go to a game or watch it on TV and enjoy. But leave it at that, and find better things to do with your time. Over time, even that will begin to fade away.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Escaping with the News</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-escaping-with-the-news.jpg" alt="Escaping with the News" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I was having a great time at a party at my house recently, when a friend of mine who is quite conservative started talking to me about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012_Benghazi_attack">the Benghazi incident of September 2012&lt;/a>. He went on and on about how outrageous it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I respond, &amp;ldquo;I just don&amp;rsquo;t see how any of this is important or relevant to my life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With an outraged tone, he responds with eyes wide open in outrage, &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t think &lt;em>Benghazi&lt;/em> is important???&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To my life? No, I don&amp;rsquo;t. In fact I can take that a step further: &lt;strong>the news, especially political news is designed to get people to get outraged over things that are not in their power to change or influence.&lt;/strong> This state of frustration and anger puts them in a place where they are willing to buy more things in the advertisements, which is good for the provider of the outrageous news. But for the person who is consuming it, it is the very definition of a waste of time: spending time on something one doesn&amp;rsquo;t find enjoying, can&amp;rsquo;t do anything about, and causes them to act in ways that are outside of their values. This is insanity!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to propose we ask a question about every news article that we consume from now on: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>How will my life change as a result of me knowing this information?&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I propose the answer is, for the most part, &amp;ldquo;none at all&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To illustrate, let&amp;rsquo;s comment on some CNN and Fox News headlines as of the date of first writing this, July 26, 2014:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Story&lt;/th>
&lt;th>How will my life change as a result of me knowing this information&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/26/world/meast/mideast-crisis/index.html?hpt=hp_t1">Rockets fired; Israel-Hamas truce appears over&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. The rockets likely won&amp;rsquo;t make it to North Texas. There is no election today to influence our political establishment, and political leadership in the U.S. seem to be aligned (for the most part).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/26/world/africa/libya-us-embassy-evacuation/index.html?hpt=hp_t2">U.S. evacuates embassy in Tripoli&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am in North Texas, not Tripoli. I have nothing to be afraid of by whatever is happening there.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/joe-paterno-feared-wrongly-accusing-sandusky-son-says/?intcmp=latestnews">Joe Paterno Feared Wrongly Accusing Sandusky, Son Says&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am not nor do I have any friends who are a part of this case. While it is a tragedy, me knowing about the state of mind of one of the participants of the case, who is now dead, will have no bearing on the outcome of the case whatsoever.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/officials-cite-marijuana-as-reason-for-rise-in-denver-homeless/?intcmp=latestnews">Officials cite marijuana as reason for rise in Denver homeless&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I live in North Texas, not Denver. I do not use marijuana. I suppose if I did this news article wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change my mind about it. There is no marijuana vote on the Texas ballot today for me to vote on.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2014/07/26/some-in-cia-torture-report-denied-chance-to-read-it/?intcmp=latestnews">Some in CIA &amp;lsquo;torture&amp;rsquo; report denied chance to read it&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am not subject to torture or defining what torture is in the coming months as far as I know. In fact if I were to be tortured, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that this report would have anything to do with how I would be treated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/colorado-business-owner-fights-back-after-falling-victim-to-caller-id-spoofing/?intcmp=latestnews">Colorado business owner fights back after falling victim to &amp;lsquo;caller ID spoofing'&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I have managed to live my life for 35 years without knowing what the term &amp;ldquo;caller id spoofing&amp;rdquo; means. Even if there were a risk, I suppose I would hear about it from the phone company. The fact that it&amp;rsquo;s on a news site tells me that it is a rare occurrence. Besides, I don&amp;rsquo;t even own a business so there is absolutely no chance of anything in this article affecting my life.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/fast-food-workers-vow-civil-disobedience-in-wage-fight/?intcmp=latestnews">Fast food workers vow civil disobedience in wage fight&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I don&amp;rsquo;t work at McDonald&amp;rsquo;s. I also don&amp;rsquo;t eat there very often. I suppose if their wages do go up, the price of a Happy Meal will eventually go up, thus creating an unexpected surprise on the rare occasion that I go to McDonalds. But we&amp;rsquo;re quite a ways from this: they are &lt;em>vowing &lt;/em>civil disobedience. Nothing has actually happened. This affects my life in no way whatsoever.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Let me give you a little guarantee: If you play this game for a few days on the news sites you are visiting, you will very quickly be awakened to the reality that this all is a complete and total waste of your time. &lt;strong>You are a pawn in someone else&amp;rsquo;s game to get you to buy stuff.&lt;/strong> There actually isn&amp;rsquo;t news on almost every day. And when there is it can be summed up in a ten second brief description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let&amp;rsquo;s stop investing so much time in &amp;ldquo;news&amp;rdquo; and make some &lt;em>real&lt;/em> news in our own lives.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>