<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Budget Cycling on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/budget-cycling/</link><description>Recent content in Budget Cycling on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 08:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/budget-cycling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Lean Startup Cycle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 08:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-lean-startup-cycle.jpg" alt="Lean Startup Cycle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermann_Hauser">Herman Hauser&lt;/a> created a team to create the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARM_architecture">ARM processor&lt;/a>, now the processor that runs most of the mobile devices you know and love, &lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/features/358750/whatever-happened-to-hermann-hauser">he remarked&lt;/a>*:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When we decided to do a microprocessor, in hindsight, I think I made two great decisions. I trusted the team and gave them two things that Intel and Motorola had never given their people: the first was no money and the second was no people. They had to keep it simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When you start a project the normal course of action is to try to get as many people as possible so you will be able to have enough resources to accomplish the goal. In &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1HdjuUt">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>, the authors advocate another way, what they call &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_startup">the Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Working out what we need to &lt;em>learn&lt;/em> by creating a value hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Decide what to &lt;em>measure&lt;/em> in order to test that hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design an experiment, called the &lt;em>minimum viable product&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Build&lt;/em> the minimum viable product to gather the necessary data from real customers to determine if we have a good product/market fit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The authors continue:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trick is to invest a minimum of work to go through this cycle. Since we are operating in conditions of extreme uncertainty, we expect that our value hypothesis will be incorrect. At this point we &lt;em>pivot&lt;/em>, coming up with a new value hypothesis based on what we have learned, and go through this process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I love this idea. Instead of wasting years of time and money on an idea, let&amp;rsquo;s realize that we don&amp;rsquo;t know everything and use the scientific method to get us to the right idea. Let&amp;rsquo;s not be afraid of failure; you can&amp;rsquo;t have innovation without failure. &lt;strong>The key to innovation isn&amp;rsquo;t avoiding failure; the key is reacting to failure earlier than the competition.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method also calls into question the annual budget cycle. If all you have is once chance a year to respond to reality, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up clamoring for more people and avoid the simple, early, scientific method laid out above. A better way is to start small, provide some runway to solve a problem, and scale only when the solution shows its value in the real world.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I got this quote from Lean Enterprise as well, but cite the original source as they did.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>