<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>art on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/art/</link><description>Recent content in art on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 08:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Life is Art</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-life-is-art.jpg" alt="Life is Art" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Earlier this year, I was pretty excited about some &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">drastic changes&lt;/a> we had made in our lifestyle. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m excited about something, I must tell someone and my friend at a dinner party at my house was no exception. I excitedly pointed out all the ways that simplicity has led us to a life of greater contentment and tranquility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could sense my friend becoming increasingly uncomfortable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Well, not everyone can live that way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend assumed that I view life as a science; that there are certain rules that &lt;em>must&lt;/em> be followed and a right and wrong way to do things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I completely disagree with that notion. To me &lt;strong>life is more like a work of art.&lt;/strong> You have a canvas on which to paint decisions, consequences, and ultimately meaning. Every life is as different as every work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a painter presents her painting, she is expressing herself in a unique way that is unlike anyone else. The painter has &lt;em>her&lt;/em> way of painting. To her it &lt;em>feels&lt;/em> like the right way, because, of course, she did it that way. Another painter may do it totally differently. A wonderful and mysterious thing happens in the gallery: &lt;strong>each painter admires the brilliance and beauty in the other&amp;rsquo;s work of art.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I am creating a work of art that I hope to be beautiful and meaningful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the entrepreneur who spends her nights and weekends creating a groundbreaking service that improves the lives of millions of people. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the philanthropist who travels the world to find a way to cure malaria worldwide. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the video game developer who works for two solid years to create a game that captures the imagination of a teenager who stays out of trouble because he has something to do when he&amp;rsquo;s out of school. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of a hospice nurse who works the night shift helping dying patients find dignity and meaning in their final days. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m creating a life of tranquility, meaning, and purpose. I do this through simplifying life in every facet, achieving in the marketplace through a fearless pursuit of adding value, and creating margin in my life to build a legacy with those around me, especially my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my work of art. This is the journey I will share with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It isn&amp;rsquo;t the only way.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I want it to be beautiful, and I want to share it with you because I hope we can inspire each other to make our lives a beautiful work of art.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>