<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>control on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/control/</link><description>Recent content in control on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ultimate Test of Tolerance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance.jpg" alt="Tolerance" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I am fortunate to be married &lt;a href="http://reclaimed.house">to someone&lt;/a> who shares many of &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">my values and passions&lt;/a>. For the things we disagree with, though, I have to find a way &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">to not control her&lt;/a> and to let her be her own person. This is the ultimate expression of tolerance: she is welcome in my personal space, influences my future, and is free to &amp;ldquo;ruin&amp;rdquo; it with her own dreams and values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key to making it work is giving her freedom and working hard to connect so values and goals can be shared as much as possible. It won&amp;rsquo;t always work, but if it does, then it is the start of a lifestyle of this, which opens up so many wonderful relationships in all areas of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We like to think of tolerance as something that happens with people who are drastically different than us. With people from other political parties, religions, or backgrounds. I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years that tolerance really begins with those who are closest to me: &lt;strong>do I try to control them or do I let them freely be themselves?&lt;/strong> That&amp;rsquo;s ultimately the question that is asked of all of our relationships. The less we control, the better the relationships are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Releasing Control</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 08:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-releasing-control.jpg" alt="Releasing Control" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thank God we&amp;rsquo;re in marriage counseling so my wife can finally get her crap together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A thought that most people have when they enter the marriage counselor&amp;rsquo;s office. I came into the office that day of &lt;a href="http://www.drlescarter.com/">Les Carter&lt;/a>, with &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">my wonderful wife&lt;/a>, ready for some change. I had a list of things. She was this. She was that. Why can&amp;rsquo;t she just…?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we started I heard a similar tone from my wife. She had a similar list, where only the subject had changed. He is this. He is that. Why can&amp;rsquo;t he just…?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;OK, OK,&amp;rdquo; I thought. &amp;ldquo;I can play this game. So the one with the highest score at the end wins. I will &lt;em>definitely&lt;/em> have a higher score at the end of this one, honey, don&amp;rsquo;t you worry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Les wasn&amp;rsquo;t playing that game. Les gave us a nugget of wisdom that is now a mantra for us:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The more you try to control, the less you are in control. The less you try to control, the more you are in control&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Les was touching on a key element of success: &lt;strong>&lt;em>it&amp;rsquo;s not about creating the perfect level of control so you can have everything your way.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s about serving, helping, and loving others. It&amp;rsquo;s about making others around you successful. Somehow when this happens, you end up having more success and control than ever. But it&amp;rsquo;s never about the control itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be applied in many ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>When you want&lt;/th>
&lt;th>You must&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a good marriage&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Chill out and let your spouse have some space&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>To be a good parent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Give them freedom to be themselves, which does include structure, but also includes having their own personalities and interests&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A project at work to succeed&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Enable those around you to be the best they can be and believe in them as you let them work&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Financial security&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Accept that there will be ups and downs and you won&amp;rsquo;t know when those will be, so it&amp;rsquo;s best to be a long-term investor who doesn&amp;rsquo;t bail whenever the market is in trouble&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>When has giving up control given you more control in your life?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>