<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>economist on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/economist/</link><description>Recent content in economist on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 08:00:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/economist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Economist Keeps it Real</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-economist-keeps-it-real.jpg" alt="Economist" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Over the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to see &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">the absolute insanity&lt;/a> of following the news on normal news sites like CNN or Fox News. You might be thinking that I have no clue what is going on in the world. I do value being an educated person who knows about world events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a secret weapon that helps me get this insight into the world without driving myself crazy day to day. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://www.subscriptionaddiction.com/magazines/subscription/the-economist-magazine-magazine.jsp">a paper subscription&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/">The Economist magazine&lt;/a>. Here are seven things I love about having a paper subscription to The Economist:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>International.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not focused on Americans only. I get more of an insight into the world than the typical American news outlets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Soap Opera Free.&lt;/strong> It doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to get me sucked into idiotic stories about how people are going to react to this or that, or worse what a celebrity was doing last Friday night. I want to be an educated man who knows world events…not a celebrity gossip connoisseur. The subscription keeps everything serious and leaves the rest out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distraction Free.&lt;/strong> When I read the magazine, I don&amp;rsquo;t see emails popping up. My kids don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m playing video games. They know I&amp;rsquo;m reading a serious news magazine. And when I put it down, I do something else. I don&amp;rsquo;t get sucked into ten hours of mindless video watching. &lt;strong>This is a feature and not a bug.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not Republican or Democrat.&lt;/strong> I love it that I get out of the false American dichotomy of Republican and Democrat with the magazine. It has no interest in getting me to be &lt;em>more&lt;/em> one way or another. It just calls it like it sees it. Which is probably more of a Libertarian bent but honestly it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tell sometimes. And that&amp;rsquo;s how I would like to take my news. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be told what to think. I want some facts and fair analysis and I want to think about it myself.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weekly.&lt;/strong> I don&amp;rsquo;t think that the appropriate news cadence should be any more frequent than once a week. If something is important I&amp;rsquo;m going to find out about it. I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend every day reading the news. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much. So the fact that the Economist is weekly is perfect for me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Guilt Free to Skip.&lt;/strong> This isn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; of the magazine as much as it is for me. If I had a weekly subscription and didn&amp;rsquo;t read &lt;em>any&lt;/em> of it, I still think it would be worth it. Why? Because it kept me from the hours per day of distraction I had been getting by going to news sites. So the Economist can be skipped just fine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Diversified.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not just a political magazine. It also has stuff on business, technology, science. It has special features that bring you up to speed on a topic in depth.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I have subscribed to the Economist for months now and absolutely love it. I highly recommend you ditch your current news habit and buy an Economist subscription. I did some searching and found a deeply discounted deal &lt;a href="http://www.subscriptionaddiction.com/magazines/subscription/the-economist-magazine-magazine.jsp">here&lt;/a>. Try it and you&amp;rsquo;ll be hooked. If you run into me personally, I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to give you a copy so you can see what I&amp;rsquo;m saying; just ask.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>