<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>negativity on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/negativity/</link><description>Recent content in negativity on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 08:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/negativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Son's Choice Between Negativity and Taking Action</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action.jpg" alt="Negativity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My son has felt negative about everything lately which has created for him a vicious cycle of disdain and despair. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/embrace-difficulty/" title="Embrace Difficulty">He is a lot like me&lt;/a>, so whenever we learn a lesson about him, it usually has something to do with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">how I&amp;rsquo;m wired as well&lt;/a>. He and I sat in bed a few nights ago and I walked him through this very basic method of how leaders have a choice to make:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I talked about how he and I are gifted with the ability to think deeply about things and thus we see things that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.** We have the responsibility of being able to see problems that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.** Something that bothers him is how his cub scout pack meetings spend too much time talking to the parents and that leaves him feeling like the meeting isn&amp;rsquo;t his. When I asked one of his good friends about cub scouts, his friend said, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m cursed as well about seeing problems everywhere. I talked to a police officer one time that told me that every room he goes into, even if it&amp;rsquo;s a church sanctuary, he automatically tries to ascertain who in that room is a potential threat. That man has a similar curse: he sees problems that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then asked Samuel why he thought President Obama wanted to be President. &amp;ldquo;Because he wanted to be famous.&amp;rdquo; I told him how there are better ways of being famous. The truth is Mr. Obama became President Obama because he saw problems that others didn&amp;rsquo;t see and cared enough about them to get in public life. &lt;strong>A leader always starts with a perception of something wrong in the world.&lt;/strong> If nothing was wrong, there would be no leaders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it&amp;rsquo;s a given that a potential leader sees problems. It is our curse. The question now, is: what are we going to do about it? There are two choices:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A potential leader &lt;em>could&lt;/em> choose the path of negativity, disdain, and ultimately despair.&lt;/strong> This is the path of the critic, the internet troll, or the quitter. This is the path my son was on and one I&amp;rsquo;ve been on many times. I can see what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the situation, and my response is to continue to criticize or believe that nothing will ever change and quit. It&amp;rsquo;s even easier to do this when &lt;em>I&amp;rsquo;m the only one who sees the problems!&lt;/em> Well of course you&amp;rsquo;re the only one who sees the problems; perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re the one who is supposed to do something about it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Or a potential leader &lt;em>could&lt;/em> choose the path of taking action, improvement, patience, and love.&lt;/strong> In other words &lt;strong>a potential leader could choose the path of leadership.&lt;/strong> This is the path I encouraged Samuel to take. The question isn&amp;rsquo;t what problems do you see with cub scout pack meetings; the question is what are you going to do about those problems? When you see a problem with a group of people, the loving thing you can do is, within your power, help solve that problem with them! It&amp;rsquo;s not to despair and quit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes problems are so deep and impenetrable that there is nothing you can do about them. At that point the best thing to do &lt;em>is&lt;/em> quit. However, most times the problems are there and as a leader we can work to make them better. That&amp;rsquo;s the path of leadership, the path of people who are cursed with the ability to recognize problems that others don&amp;rsquo;t see and choose to take action to solve those problems.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>