<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kindle on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/kindle/</link><description>Recent content in kindle on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:00:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/kindle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Focus with the Amazon Kindle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-focus-with-the-amazon-kindle.jpg" alt="Focus with the Kindle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/" title="Life is Art">focusing on what matters&lt;/a> lately by &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">making good choices&lt;/a> with how and what you consume. Some things are just a complete waste of time like the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">local news&lt;/a>. Other things have a good alternative, like &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/">reading the Economist&lt;/a> instead of going to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">news sites&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I wrote last time, though, in this mobile world that isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. You have to make sure your smartphone is serving you and not enslaving you. And beyond that I&amp;rsquo;m convinced &lt;strong>to lead a life of growth and meaning you need to read.&lt;/strong> Probably more than you are right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do we do that? The solutions that come to mind immediately are: on our smartphone, a paper book, or a tablet. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about a better way to read books: through the Amazon Kindle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years back &lt;a href="http://www.chrisdikes.com/">my friend Chris&lt;/a> asked me what I thought about the Kindle, and my opinion to him as of July 16, 2010 was: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>It seems like having a book would be better.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Well, thankfully Chris didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to my awful advice and bought one, told me about it, changed my mind, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s so great about the Kindle:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distractionless:&lt;/strong> yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a feature and not a bug. I like it that there aren&amp;rsquo;t pop ups telling me all about the emails I&amp;rsquo;m not reading or the cool Facebook posts that I need to be looking into. I&amp;rsquo;m here to read. The Kindle helps me read.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Battery Life:&lt;/strong> I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be preoccupied with powering the stupid thing while I&amp;rsquo;m using it. I can read. I have to charge it every once and a while. It&amp;rsquo;s not like the power sucking smartphone or tablet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Position Independent:&lt;/strong> this may seem small to some, but I like reading while I&amp;rsquo;m laying down. And I get comfortable holding a book in one hand. Then I read fast and get to the other side of the book. So I have to move to read the other section. It seems like a small thing, and admittedly a first-world problem, but I love how I can read the Kindle with one hand laying on the same side for as long as it is comfortable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sleep Friendly Lighting:&lt;/strong> I have the Kindle paperwhite that doesn&amp;rsquo;t blast light into my eyes and keep me up. I can do a little nighttime reading with a very small amount of light. It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t distract my wife.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Borrower Capable:&lt;/strong> I have learned to take advantage of my library&amp;rsquo;s borrower privileges on the Kindle. This is easy once you figure it out. I do admit to buying more books than I would have before, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing as long as I read them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Keeps Your Place:&lt;/strong> I pick up the book and read exactly where I left off. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it. I just go.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Read More:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve read much more than before. If I&amp;rsquo;m interested in a topic, I can get a book on that topic and read through it quickly while I have a passion and interest in the book.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Portable:&lt;/strong> I admit to not doing it very often, but if I want to, I can read on my smartphone or even my computer to continue my reading.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I highly recommend going for a Kindle. You need to read to meet your goals, and in my mind there is no better way to do so than with the Kindle.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>