<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lean startup on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/lean-startup/</link><description>Recent content in lean startup on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 09:30:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/lean-startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning from Ebola Healthcare Workers with Enterprise Problem Solving</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 09:30:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving.jpg" alt="Learning from Ebola" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In a large enterprise it can be difficult to implement large meaningful change. On many days I have ended up frustrated while sitting down to a margarita during &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">one of my quarterly retrospectives&lt;/a>. How do I get through all the opinions and politics to create real, lasting change? After reading about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">the Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a>, I have a new way of thinking about it, which starts with healthcare workers in West Africa &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/news/international/21625813-ebola-epidemic-west-africa-poses-catastrophic-threat-region-and-could-yet">fighting Ebola&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When these brave individuals arrive to risk their lives and help others, they are met with a striking contrast to the first world. As you have probably learned, there are entire tribes of people in West Africa who celebrate the recently deceased within an elaborate ceremony where the entire tribe drinks after the deceased loved one in a shared cup. Science certainly had nothing to do with it, but science does tell us that when the deceased person has Ebola, this is a surefire way of getting the whole village infected. Couple this with the cultural norm that those who are sick should travel large distances to medicine men who will heal them, and you have an epidemic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, faced with such a terrible situation of men, women, and children dying every day due to a horrible disease, what do I imagine is the reaction of these healthcare workers? Do they pound their fists and whine, &amp;ldquo;We could change this situation if these people weren&amp;rsquo;t being so &lt;em>stupid?&amp;quot;&lt;/em> Do they clock in and out, thinking that the problem is just too large and that they will just collect a paycheck so that they can support their family? In other words, is their primary approach to the situation that of &lt;em>frustration&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think they certainly feel frustration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, these people are professional scientists, and they probably follow &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_method">a much different formula&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First, they start with a hypothesis.&lt;/strong> They ask themselves, maybe if we visit the tribal leaders we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to convince them that this practice is dangerous and that will stop the spread of this disease. If the leaders cannot be convince, then they may say that the tribes are a lost cause and that maybe they should lock down the entrances to the cities. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are hundreds of ideas that they come up, all without despair, but with a genuine hope that something can be done to improve the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Next, they test the most promising hypothesis.&lt;/strong> The team may decide to educate the tribal leaders. They then create a short-term way to test their hypothesis. They decide to go to one village and talk to the tribal leaders then pay an informant to record the activities of the next funeral, which is likely to happen in the coming days. They try this with ten villages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Finally, they measure the results of the test.&lt;/strong> Out of the ten villages, only two changed their practices. While many of us might view this as a failure, the scientists see this as success. We now know what &lt;em>wouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> be helpful. Now we can come up with a better hypothesis and start the process all over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method is what got us technology, medicine, and progress. &lt;strong>Why aren&amp;rsquo;t we using it in the enterprise?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The One Metric that Matters</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 08:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-one-metric-that-matters.jpg" alt="Metric that Matters" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The more I measure &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">the more successful I am&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve known this for a while, but I realize that the lack of measurement is still the thing that is holding my career back. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about how measurement is key to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">The Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a> of using the scientific method to find innovation in your organization. So I&amp;rsquo;m hooked with this idea, but I desperately want to implement it in a good way. I want to have a breakthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Lean Enterprise&lt;/em> book cites the &lt;em>Lean Analytics&lt;/em> book concept of &lt;strong>The One Metric That Matters (OMTM):&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>OMTM is a single metric that we prioritize as the most important to drive decisions depending on the stage of our product lifecycle and our business model…We focus on One Metric that Matters to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Answer the most pressing question we have by linking it to the assumptions in the hypothesis we want to test&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create focus, conversation, and thought to identify problems and simulate improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide transparency and a shared understanding across the team and wider organization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support a culture of experimentation by basing it on rates or ratios, not averages or totals, relevant to our historical data set&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When I started out my current project in 2008, my boss for a very short time was &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-hughes/3/720/3a3">Jeff Hughes&lt;/a>, who is a genius at innovating software. The project I was doing was related to software quality, so Jeff gave me a metric for the first year: make defect containment go up, as defined by the percentage of software defects found inside the company related to the software defects found by our customers. He gave me the one metric that matters, and with that direction I was able to take the project in the direction it needed to go. At first we thought that we were going to stick with testing just customer situations, but we ended up having a mixture of customer situations and vanilla, or regression, situations. Without that &amp;ldquo;one metric that matters&amp;rdquo;, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the freedom to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fast forward to last year, I started a project to improve the installation experience for all of our products that get installed in restaurants. Everyone seemed to want this to be better so I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop and create the one metric that matters. I rushed ahead and started on the solution. My one metric that mattered internally was lowered cycle time from a release to working software. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to define where we were before I started, and how my changes had improved the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This led to a lot of unnecessary drama. People would question &lt;em>why&lt;/em> we were taking a particular approach. People would question whether an improvement was warranted in the first place (even after agreeing that it was warranted before). It&amp;rsquo;s easy to point fingers and talk about how people don&amp;rsquo;t understand or care, but they do understand and they do care. I just didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to create a metric that would measure what outcome I&amp;rsquo;m trying to create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is not a lesson &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">I will soon forget&lt;/a>. I hope that I will be able to fundamentally transform my approach to include measurement as one of the key aspects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Lean Startup Cycle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 08:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-lean-startup-cycle.jpg" alt="Lean Startup Cycle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermann_Hauser">Herman Hauser&lt;/a> created a team to create the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARM_architecture">ARM processor&lt;/a>, now the processor that runs most of the mobile devices you know and love, &lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/features/358750/whatever-happened-to-hermann-hauser">he remarked&lt;/a>*:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When we decided to do a microprocessor, in hindsight, I think I made two great decisions. I trusted the team and gave them two things that Intel and Motorola had never given their people: the first was no money and the second was no people. They had to keep it simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When you start a project the normal course of action is to try to get as many people as possible so you will be able to have enough resources to accomplish the goal. In &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1HdjuUt">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>, the authors advocate another way, what they call &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_startup">the Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Working out what we need to &lt;em>learn&lt;/em> by creating a value hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Decide what to &lt;em>measure&lt;/em> in order to test that hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design an experiment, called the &lt;em>minimum viable product&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Build&lt;/em> the minimum viable product to gather the necessary data from real customers to determine if we have a good product/market fit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The authors continue:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trick is to invest a minimum of work to go through this cycle. Since we are operating in conditions of extreme uncertainty, we expect that our value hypothesis will be incorrect. At this point we &lt;em>pivot&lt;/em>, coming up with a new value hypothesis based on what we have learned, and go through this process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I love this idea. Instead of wasting years of time and money on an idea, let&amp;rsquo;s realize that we don&amp;rsquo;t know everything and use the scientific method to get us to the right idea. Let&amp;rsquo;s not be afraid of failure; you can&amp;rsquo;t have innovation without failure. &lt;strong>The key to innovation isn&amp;rsquo;t avoiding failure; the key is reacting to failure earlier than the competition.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method also calls into question the annual budget cycle. If all you have is once chance a year to respond to reality, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up clamoring for more people and avoid the simple, early, scientific method laid out above. A better way is to start small, provide some runway to solve a problem, and scale only when the solution shows its value in the real world.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I got this quote from Lean Enterprise as well, but cite the original source as they did.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>