<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vacations on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/vacations/</link><description>Recent content in vacations on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 08:02:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/vacations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solve Problems by Isolating Them</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/solve-problems-by-isolating-them/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 08:02:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/solve-problems-by-isolating-them/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-solve-problems-by-isolating-them.jpg" alt="Isolate Problems" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out there is a [My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out there is a &lt;a href="http://www.legolanddiscoverycenter.com/dallasfw/">Legoland Discovery center&lt;/a> nearby. The other day they went to a birthday party there. The kids had an absolute blast. Legos, legos everywhere. It was totally awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also turns out that we have a &lt;a href="https://www.sixflags.com/overtexas">Six Flags&lt;/a> nearby. Fast roller coasters. Every amusement park craziness imaginable. We spent last summer doing that, and let me tell you, mom and I really got sick of it. But the kids absolutely loved it. They even wanted to do it again this summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So DFW area: lego land: check. amusement park: check. &lt;a href="http://california.legoland.com/">lego amusement park&lt;/a>? That will be a trip to California and $4000 please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how &lt;strong>the solution to a problem gets a lot more complicated and a lot more expensive when you combine it with another problem.&lt;/strong> I come across this a lot at work. I ruthlessly go through a project and eliminate anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t needed, because I want to ship it as quickly as possible and I know every little thing just adds to the time and complexity and makes the project that much more unrealistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So are we going to the LegoLand California Resort? If we do it, it will be with [My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>