<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>debt on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/debt/</link><description>Recent content in debt on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 08:00:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/debt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Failure Masquerading as Success</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 08:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-failure-masquerading-as-success.jpg" alt="Failure Masquerading as Success" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the grades I should have had in high school. My parents didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything saved up for college when I turned 18*. By living at home, under my mom&amp;rsquo;s insurance, and getting support from my dad, I was able to end my Junior year of college with a few thousand dollars of student loans and no credit card debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. I &lt;em>needed&lt;/em> to have a successful college life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I began believing that there was a real risk that I was going to look back at my college life as a failure. People in college are supposed to experience community, friends, fun, unfettered learning. Living with mommy and having a job was seriously impeding those goals. I had only one year to make things right. So I did what any idiotic 20-year-old would do: I quit my job waiting tables at an upscale restaurant in Dallas, moved into a dorm, and maxed out my student loans and credit cards to make it happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the next fourteen months I had a lot of fun. I hung out with interesting people, was in walking distance to most of my life, and expanded my mind through books and interesting classes. Based on the terms I had set out for myself, the year was a success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest with you: I spent many years paying off the tens of thousands of dollars I borrowed in that fourteen month period. The years of debt repayment that followed brought home an important truth:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>what felt like success for those fourteen months was really failure masquerading as success.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When success is real it flows to all areas of life, not just on the area that has the focus. It also flows into the future, not just the present.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When financial success turns a healthy, compatible, and loving marriage into a hate-fest, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success at work turns colleagues from respect and honor to anger and disdain, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success in marriage creates isolated, ignored children, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success on my project this quarter leads to years of rework and confusion, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I believe success does have tradeoffs. There are &lt;em>failures&lt;/em> that always &lt;em>accompany&lt;/em> success: having dinner with your family might mean someone else who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to do that will get promoted instead of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that a wise definition of success has collateral damage.&lt;/strong> I believe a life of peace and balance is possible. Anything else quickly becomes failure masquerading as success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Has failure ever masqueraded as success in your life?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What they did do though is tell me over and over again how important it was for me to go to college, something I am thankful for to this day&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>