<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>commitments on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/commitments/</link><description>Recent content in commitments on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 08:00:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/commitments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two Questions You Should Ask About Your Commitments</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 08:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-two-questions-about-commitments.jpg" alt="Commitments" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Lately we have been too busy, and we have had to figure out &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/" title="Achievable Contentment">what is working for us&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">what isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/a>. Usually when we get this way, our entire lives are filtered through two questions. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share them with you to think about what the answers are in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, make a list of the things in your life that you&amp;rsquo;re committed to. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, now for each of those things ask, &lt;strong>&lt;em>How would I feel if this wasn&amp;rsquo;t in my life? Relieved&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>? Then perhaps it should be a candidate for either changing or removing it from your life. How you feel when imagining something is gone is the best way to know if you really want to do something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now for the second question: &lt;strong>What would be the reaction of others if you &lt;em>did&lt;/em> say no?&lt;/strong> This is a tricky one, because it shows the long-term health of your relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can tell my wife, &amp;ldquo;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that. Let&amp;rsquo;s think of an alternative.&amp;rdquo; She would respond with love, acceptance, and we would work something out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell my church from college that. If you had asked me at the time to imagine it being gone, I would have sworn up and down to you that I loved it, etc. But then if you would have asked me if I was &lt;em>free&lt;/em> to reject it, if I was being honest I would have to say no.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So &lt;strong>rid yourself of everything you are relieved to get rid of. Only keep that which you can freely and openly reject.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>