<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marriages on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/marriages/</link><description>Recent content in Marriages on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/marriages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ultimate Test of Tolerance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance.jpg" alt="Tolerance" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I am fortunate to be married &lt;a href="http://reclaimed.house">to someone&lt;/a> who shares many of &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">my values and passions&lt;/a>. For the things we disagree with, though, I have to find a way &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">to not control her&lt;/a> and to let her be her own person. This is the ultimate expression of tolerance: she is welcome in my personal space, influences my future, and is free to &amp;ldquo;ruin&amp;rdquo; it with her own dreams and values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key to making it work is giving her freedom and working hard to connect so values and goals can be shared as much as possible. It won&amp;rsquo;t always work, but if it does, then it is the start of a lifestyle of this, which opens up so many wonderful relationships in all areas of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We like to think of tolerance as something that happens with people who are drastically different than us. With people from other political parties, religions, or backgrounds. I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years that tolerance really begins with those who are closest to me: &lt;strong>do I try to control them or do I let them freely be themselves?&lt;/strong> That&amp;rsquo;s ultimately the question that is asked of all of our relationships. The less we control, the better the relationships are.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>