<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>measurement on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/measurement/</link><description>Recent content in measurement on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 08:00:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/measurement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The One Metric that Matters</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 08:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-one-metric-that-matters.jpg" alt="Metric that Matters" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The more I measure &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">the more successful I am&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve known this for a while, but I realize that the lack of measurement is still the thing that is holding my career back. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about how measurement is key to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">The Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a> of using the scientific method to find innovation in your organization. So I&amp;rsquo;m hooked with this idea, but I desperately want to implement it in a good way. I want to have a breakthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Lean Enterprise&lt;/em> book cites the &lt;em>Lean Analytics&lt;/em> book concept of &lt;strong>The One Metric That Matters (OMTM):&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>OMTM is a single metric that we prioritize as the most important to drive decisions depending on the stage of our product lifecycle and our business model…We focus on One Metric that Matters to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Answer the most pressing question we have by linking it to the assumptions in the hypothesis we want to test&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create focus, conversation, and thought to identify problems and simulate improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide transparency and a shared understanding across the team and wider organization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support a culture of experimentation by basing it on rates or ratios, not averages or totals, relevant to our historical data set&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When I started out my current project in 2008, my boss for a very short time was &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-hughes/3/720/3a3">Jeff Hughes&lt;/a>, who is a genius at innovating software. The project I was doing was related to software quality, so Jeff gave me a metric for the first year: make defect containment go up, as defined by the percentage of software defects found inside the company related to the software defects found by our customers. He gave me the one metric that matters, and with that direction I was able to take the project in the direction it needed to go. At first we thought that we were going to stick with testing just customer situations, but we ended up having a mixture of customer situations and vanilla, or regression, situations. Without that &amp;ldquo;one metric that matters&amp;rdquo;, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the freedom to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fast forward to last year, I started a project to improve the installation experience for all of our products that get installed in restaurants. Everyone seemed to want this to be better so I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop and create the one metric that matters. I rushed ahead and started on the solution. My one metric that mattered internally was lowered cycle time from a release to working software. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to define where we were before I started, and how my changes had improved the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This led to a lot of unnecessary drama. People would question &lt;em>why&lt;/em> we were taking a particular approach. People would question whether an improvement was warranted in the first place (even after agreeing that it was warranted before). It&amp;rsquo;s easy to point fingers and talk about how people don&amp;rsquo;t understand or care, but they do understand and they do care. I just didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to create a metric that would measure what outcome I&amp;rsquo;m trying to create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is not a lesson &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">I will soon forget&lt;/a>. I hope that I will be able to fundamentally transform my approach to include measurement as one of the key aspects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Measure for Reality</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 08:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-measure-for-reality.jpg" alt="Measure for Reality" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Buffalo Ribeye, medium at &lt;a href="http://www.reata.net/fort-worth-restaurant.html">Reata&lt;/a> with a glass of cab. That&amp;rsquo;s what I get when I&amp;rsquo;m ready to celebrate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had finally sold our house and knew we needed to jump on the next one. On the first day of looking, we found a house with a lot of potential and decided we wanted to make an offer. When the offer was accepted, we got babysitting for the kids and headed to Reata to celebrate. Then I got a text. Look away, look away! Another one. My wife is more important than this phone. Another one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A friend of mine wanted me to come work with him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The offer was very attractive and tempting. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t take it for a number of reasons, one of which was that I felt like my work wasn&amp;rsquo;t finished at my current job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then the next two weeks were hell at work. Negativity. Failure. Struggle. Wondering to myself if there will every be anything but negativity, failure, and struggle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was fed up and needed to get honest with myself, so I went to &lt;a href="http://www.esparzastexas.com/home">Esparzas&lt;/a> and mapped out how I could get out of the situation I was in over a few margaritas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me let you in on a little secret of mine: every three months, I go to a restaurant, have at least two margaritas, and write out what I&amp;rsquo;m happy about, what I&amp;rsquo;m not happy about, and what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do about it. This particular day I was not happy about the fact that I turned down a great offer and didn&amp;rsquo;t have a wildly successful project at the time that made that decision feel worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem I uncovered that day over a few margaritas was that &lt;strong>we were doing some great things but those great things weren&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>measured&lt;/em> and &lt;em>reported on&lt;/em>.&lt;/strong> So to outsiders, especially senior management, those great things didn&amp;rsquo;t exist. What I needed to do was measure the outcomes we were creating, and then share those measurements with the stakeholders on the project. That would turn &amp;ldquo;is this ever going to work?&amp;rdquo; into &amp;ldquo;this is working but they have a few issues right now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a few months, we created a daily report that showed the project&amp;rsquo;s output &lt;em>every day&lt;/em> for the runs that happened &lt;em>every day&lt;/em>. This was a game changer for my project, and for my job. Now I look for any way to measure what outcomes I&amp;rsquo;m creating because I know no matter how good the outcome is, if it isn&amp;rsquo;t measured, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To wrap up the story, I made the right decision with staying with my company. The project just needed some advertised regular measurement. Once that was in place everything changed. And my friend left that job six months after he made that offer, due to strife. A year after that the project he was on was cancelled.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>