<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>culture on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/culture/</link><description>Recent content in culture on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 08:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finding Alignment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/finding-alignment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/finding-alignment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-finding-alignment.jpg" alt="Finding Alignment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of things on my plate right now, but let me be clear: I&amp;rsquo;m not going to stand in the way of what the business wants to do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been told this many times before. In the early days of trying to create alignment for initiatives that are important to our strategy, I would have taken it as a sign of support. Instead, I translate it into what this same person would say to her boss about this same subject.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Michael came and talked to me about [Awesome Initiative]. (Sigh) He says it&amp;rsquo;s going to really change things for us. Are we really going to waste our time with this crap or are we going to serve our customers? I&amp;rsquo;ll do whatever, but fair warning: this project has &amp;lsquo;disaster&amp;rsquo; written all over it, and you won&amp;rsquo;t get that feature you&amp;rsquo;ve been asking for either, you can kiss that goodbye for this year.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s quite a different story, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how to respond? I&amp;rsquo;ve been tempted in the past to write people off and try to do it anyways. I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years though that this is a mistake, because a sufficiently motivated individual &lt;em>can&lt;/em> and &lt;em>will&lt;/em> destroy your project if they don&amp;rsquo;t feel listened to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the keys are** respect** and** empathy**.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Respect&lt;/strong> can&amp;rsquo;t be faked. I can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>really&lt;/em> only respect my opinion, or those of the consultants I&amp;rsquo;m working with, and then merely try to get &lt;em>you&lt;/em> on board with &lt;em>my&lt;/em> project. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. People see past that. Instead, I need to walk into the relationship with the understanding and true belief that you are a smart person with real needs that may be solvable by what I&amp;rsquo;m working on. This is a discovery of where your needs meet my solutions. I&amp;rsquo;m open to changing my solution because I cannot possibly predict all of your needs without your iterative interaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Empathy&lt;/strong> is key because I really need to &lt;em>feel&lt;/em> what you&amp;rsquo;re feeling, from a business perspective, and even from a personal perspective. What makes you excited or happy? What are you afraid of? What is painful for you? How does that affect you? Is there anything I can do to help you with that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following this pattern has led me to understand that, at a generic level, different groups have a natural alignment and misalignment with DevOps:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Team&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Natural Alignment&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Natural Misalignment&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Development&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Faster Delivery of features&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Have to be engaged in operations, more &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; to do&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Operations&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Less fires, more consistency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Have to learn a new skillset and be a beginner&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Security&lt;/td>
&lt;td>More consistency, compliance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Automation can cause unknown vulnerabilities&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Business&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Faster ROI for development, lower cost for operations, and a scale model that works&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Takes ongoing investment in culture and tools&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>As I focus on respect and empathy I can find the natural alignment and mitigate the natural misalignment with each group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For developers&lt;/strong> we can help them deliver features faster and thus get a truly agile feedback loop. But we can also help them culturally begin to share the ownership of the operatability of their product with the operations team. The key is ensuring that their desire for consistency and velocity outweighs their disdain for caring about how it works in production. We do this by finding their pain points in operations, catch them &lt;em>blaming&lt;/em> operations for those pain points, then show them that they actually can do something about their problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For QA&lt;/strong> we can help them deliver features more safely by minimizing the amount of time they spend creating environments and ensuring that they have consistent, hardened environments. This is all exciting, but they must engage the other teams to define infrastructure and they must be willing to not be lazy and just &amp;ldquo;click the damn checkbox in IIS when they want something changed. Culturally they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have a problem with this, but in reality QA always gets changes at the end of a release or sprint and is under a time crunch to ensure quality. So we work with them to show them how much time they are spending on this and how we can use automation to get them focused on the important stuff: ensuring quality in a way that computers can&amp;rsquo;t or writing automation against production-like environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For Operations&lt;/strong> we can help them avoid the unexpected problems that come about without good automated configuration management. But to them, it comes at a cost. Many of the things that made them successful (incident resolution, working crazy hours, following directions) aren&amp;rsquo;t compatible with creating and engaging with automation. So they have to be fine with starting from scratch and building themselves back up. They have to see a payoff if they&amp;rsquo;re going to take that kind of career and time risk. The payoff in my mind is that they get to do more valuable work for the business by automating things and that value will translate into a more rewarding job for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For Security&lt;/strong> we can help them achieve the consistency and compliance at all levels that has alluded them. Yes they have controls defined and exercised in production. But they struggle with other teams thinking of them as a blocker to progress. Also, as we automate more, they&amp;rsquo;re afraid that we are going to take &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3022707/Worst-valet-Hapless-garage-attendant-destroys-300-000-Ferrari-599-GTO-bringing-round-owners-hit-accelerator-instead-brake.html">this nice shiny devops Ferrari and wreck it into a wall.&lt;/a> So we work on automating compliance and on developing a change management process that ensures proper control and separation of duties into production. We don&amp;rsquo;t fight them. We work with them to achieve &lt;em>their&lt;/em> goals. Once this happens, the perceived &amp;ldquo;blocker becomes a champion and driver of our changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For Management&lt;/strong> they get the benefits outlined above. But they also have to lead a cultural transformation. We can&amp;rsquo;t do it the easy way when that means &amp;ldquo;just running the command or &amp;ldquo;clicking that checkbox over there. We have to be committed to a repeatable, auditable process for change. So we need to train the people we have with new skills and be patient as they figure this out. We need to be OK with someone spending a little while on automating that thing, because the payoff will be huge over the next few years. And we need to be OK with absorbing the cost of tooling and vendor partnerships to realize the dream.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once we see the lay&amp;quot;way, it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to get everyone to the goal together. While I can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee that one won&amp;rsquo;t encounter the statement at the beginning of the post, I can guarantee that following this model will give someone something &lt;em>constructive&lt;/em> to do afterwards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disruption is Uncomfortable</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/disruption-is-uncomfortable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 08:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/disruption-is-uncomfortable/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-disruption-is-uncomfortable.jpg" alt="Disruption is Uncomfortable" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The other day we were doing an urgent Chef policy update in our production environment. It quickly became clear to all that this was uncomfortable. I had written extensive documentation to explain, as I saw it, how interact with Chef within our system. The person who was assigned the task, however, wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to make much sense of my documentation. So we had an awkward back and forth where he was asking me for the commands he should run and I was telling him that he should know what he is doing when running those commands. It was all very uncomfortable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I talked to a colleague about it who reminded me: &amp;ldquo;Hey Michael, you&amp;rsquo;re doing something disruptive here, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised when it is…disruptive&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then calmed down, got another colleague on my immediate Chef team on a call, and we figured out a better way to bring people on board with the process. We didn&amp;rsquo;t get angry. We didn&amp;rsquo;t go to lunch and talk about how idiotic that other team was. We realized that disruption is uncomfortable, so we can empathize with that and help people along.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this has been a major part of my job: helping people through the discomfort of change that DevOps presents to their status quo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Premature Optimization</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/premature-optimization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/premature-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-premature-optimization.jpg" alt="Premature Optimization" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I was talking to a colleague the other day who is working on a centralized initiative that has the potential to do a lot for our organization. He&amp;rsquo;s excited. He&amp;rsquo;s going to meetings, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/alignment/">getting alignment&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/funding/">getting funding&lt;/a>. In it all, leaders are asking him for a &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/">grand vision&lt;/a> that will bring all the disparate parts together into a coherent whole. He delivered that grand vision in the form of a plan that would bring a set of solutions together to satisfy what all stakeholders are asking for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in that situation myself in the past. It&amp;rsquo;s all very exciting. Every meeting you have has a sense of purpose and direction. You are &lt;em>finally&lt;/em> bringing this change to the organization that it so desperately needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, in the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve missed the reality that the only thing that is known is the next one or two things that need to be done to improve the current situation. The grand vision might be needed to bring the needed alignment and funding into the situation. But if that vision removes me from the stark reality that if I don&amp;rsquo;t act upon the improvement opportunities that stand before me &lt;em>right&lt;/em> now with a high level of urgency, I will not end up making the transformative change that I am promising to everyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I might still deliver a tool. I might even declare &amp;ldquo;Mission Accomplished&amp;rdquo; as I do. But without a flow of improvements that have the regular engagement of all stakeholders, the tool or initiative is destined to have little effect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People say it&amp;rsquo;s bad to prematurely optimize code. It&amp;rsquo;s just as bad to prematurely optimize solutions. Make your solutions fit the problem you&amp;rsquo;re facing today, and give enough vision to provide the direction needed to keep it going in the right direction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of Precendence</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-power-of-precendence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 08:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-power-of-precendence/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-power-of-precedence.jpg" alt="Power of Precedence" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The other day I a friend and colleague was working on a central initiative and asking me for help. He couldn&amp;rsquo;t get any traction on this initiative because all of the people who would need to approve of this initiative kept bringing up more and more issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The groups were caught &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/all-or-nothing-changes/">in a common trap&lt;/a> of any change: let&amp;rsquo;s make &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/">the Perfect State that Everyone Will Adhere To&lt;/a>. The stakes of the whole endeavor are raised when we arrive at that point. Everyone is now thinking to themselves, &amp;ldquo;This is my last chance to have any say in how this works; I better get all my concerns addressed before moving forward with it.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/my-advice-for-chef-in-large-corporations/">In a large enterprise&lt;/a>, this means that there will be tons of meetings, tons of confusion, and a lot of wasted time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I recommended to my friend to use the power of precedence to his advantage. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for the trap of making the Perfect State. Instead, find a team with a serious business problem that your solution will address. Use that team&amp;rsquo;s leverage within the organization to get your change operational. Repeat this process. Pretty soon you will have a lot of teams using solution, getting obvious value out of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this strategy, as concerns come along, the concerns are rightly within a business context and not some mental exercise. This keeps everyone focused on doing what we&amp;rsquo;re paid to do: increase profitability through increased efficiency, increased revenue due to faster speed of market, and lower risk. And, since you&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this in the real world, as concerns arise, you can say, &amp;ldquo;Let me show you how we do it.&amp;rdquo; You have precedence on your side. This isn&amp;rsquo;t an ivory tower exercise. You&amp;rsquo;re not hopping from one visio document to another to get everyone on board before you try something out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re doing &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">incremental experiments&lt;/a> which are leading you to increased profitability and lower risk. This is creating a flywheel of change for the organization, within which people can express their concerns and thus become a part of the process to greater profitability and decreased risk. This is what a functional change initiative looks like. Everything else, unfortunately, is usually theater.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Missing Compiler/Unit Test for Feelings</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-missing-compilerunit-test-for-feelings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-missing-compilerunit-test-for-feelings/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-missing-compilerunit-test-for-feelings.jpg" alt="Missing Unit Test" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As technical people we become fascinated early on by &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">the&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/">numerous&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/my-advice-for-chef-in-large-corporations/">tools&lt;/a> out there that make our jobs easier. A compiler or syntax checker is almost an afterthought these days: of course you would want some guidance on whether your code was in compliance with the language before running it. Unit tests are the same way; if I can run something and get a good answer on whether it is OK &lt;em>before&lt;/em> I put it in a shared environment, then &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/test-kitchen-required-not-optional/">that will save me tons of time&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, there isn&amp;rsquo;t a similar tool for how people feel about you. A technical person can fall into the trap of looking at more technical-oriented clues to how people feel, but these often fall short:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Team&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Natural Alignment&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Natural Misalignment&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Development&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Faster Delivery of features&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Have to be engaged in operations, more &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; to do&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Operations&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Less fires, more consistency&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Have to learn a new skillset and be a beginner&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Security&lt;/td>
&lt;td>More consistency, compliance&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Automation can cause unknown vulnerabilities&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Business&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Faster ROI for development, lower cost for operations, and a scale model that works&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Takes ongoing investment in culture and tools&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>The first step in keeping this kind of thing from happening to you is to care about people. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/technology-partnership/">Put them before yourself&lt;/a>. Follow the golden rule. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-technical-asshole-curse/">Don&amp;rsquo;t be an asshole&lt;/a>. The second step is to understand and embrace the true value in what people think about you when you&amp;rsquo;re not there. You can&amp;rsquo;t control this part, you can only influence it. If they think you&amp;rsquo;re an idiot or an asshole, work to show them that you have their best interests in mind and that you&amp;rsquo;re growing. Are you including them when we are solving problems, so &lt;em>they&lt;/em> own it and won&amp;rsquo;t blame you in disgust if something goes wrong?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That approach is fraught with difficulty, especially for someone with a technical background. There is no compiler for it. There is no unit test. There isn&amp;rsquo;t even a clear answer on how people exactly feel about you. The only thing you can do is care about it and try to influence it positively. In technology, caring about this is so uncommon that it ends up going a long way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Technical Asshole Curse</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-technical-asshole-curse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-technical-asshole-curse/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-technical-asshole-curse.jpg" alt="Technical Asshole Curse" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it happen over and over again, and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/all-or-nothing-changes/">I fight it in myself every day&lt;/a>. I call it the Technical Asshole Curse. We&amp;rsquo;ll illustrate the curse by following our friend Joe through his career.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s starts so innocently: Joe cares. He wants to make a difference. He reads up on the best way to do something, and stands up in the important notice and gives management a way out of this mess. Joe introduces test-driven development, or a better way to provision infrastructure, or &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/">a great new devops tool&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People take notice. Joe then gets promoted. People start coming to Joe for help on all things related to his expertise. Joe is now the go-to person for that topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s important to stop here and note an important truth that Joe doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite get: Joe is respected and given praise because of his &lt;em>hard skills&lt;/em>, not his &lt;em>soft skills&lt;/em>. In other words, people think he brings value to the organization because of his knowledge and not because of how he treats people. In fact, if people were honest with Joe, they would tell him that they are often uncomfortable with how Joe treats them. Sometimes Joe gets frustrated in meetings and talks over people. Other times Joe answers emails with no empathy or understanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Joe is unaware of these problems, because everyone is so enamored with the technical value that Joe is bringing to the table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As Joe&amp;rsquo;s career grows, the business builds a team around Joe to insulate him from those who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get him: other teams, top management, and especially the customers. Joe doesn&amp;rsquo;t care and thinks this is a good thing. But this is not a good thing: Joe is surrounded by people that think Joe is an asshole and that it&amp;rsquo;s their job to keep that fact from hurting the business. Joe&amp;rsquo;s colleagues go home from work and talk about how much they despise Joe, but how there is nothing they can do about it because Joe is so valuable to the company. The more they feel trapped, the more their secret resentment toward Joe grows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what happens over and over again when people only find their value in their technical contributions and ignore their interpersonal contributions. It&amp;rsquo;s a curse that happens to good people who stand up and make a difference, but fail to properly appreciate that the difference they seek combines an excellent approach with a group of people who feel great about working together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Businesses will rarely tell people that they&amp;rsquo;re an asshole. Rest assured: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rt86dc6EIoY">they will talk about it when the asshole isn&amp;rsquo;t present&lt;/a>. And many times the fix will do nothing to help the asshole get some help. Instead many times the fix will enable the asshole to become more of one, while the cycle of resentment and frustration descend into further and further depths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to be an asshole in technology. In order for your idea to get through, you have to care and you have to tell people that they are doing it all wrong. If you&amp;rsquo;re not careful, you end up thinking their feelings are an unnecessary detail. That will be so destructive for your career if you let it fester. Instead, take people to lunch. Find out what they care about and empathize with their problems. Let &lt;em>them&lt;/em> come up with the solutions and help them out. Make it OK to be wrong about stuff. In short, don&amp;rsquo;t be an asshole.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feelings > Compliance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/feelings-compliance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 08:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/feelings-compliance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-feelings-compliance.jpg" alt="Feelings" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>On the surface, leadership looks like an exercise in getting as many people compliant with one&amp;rsquo;s vision and direction. A naive leader will find themselves forcing others to comply to their policies, their direction, their demands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A while back I was in a meeting with a colleague going over the particulars of how I was going to implement a particular project. He started coming up with what I thought were dumb requirements, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think it would help things to fight him, so I dutifully wrote the requirements down and told him that I would implement them. We went back and forth a few times to make sure I had it, and I explained that I had it and that I was going to implement the requirements the way he wanted them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the outside, I was compliant to my colleague&amp;rsquo;s wishes. On the inside I was frustrated and wanted to exit the conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to dismiss how people feel when I work with them. I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize that their feelings about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing are more important than how much they outwardly follow my direction. If I interact with people and they come away from it feeling respected, listened to, and excited about what is possible, then I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about their compliance. On the other hand, if they are compliant but secretly think I&amp;rsquo;m an asshole, then they will probably do whatever they can to do the absolute minimum and will be happy when I fail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find it easier to &lt;em>start&lt;/em> with one&amp;rsquo;s feelings. How do you feel about this change, project, or challenge? What can we come up with together that will address some of those things? If we have that conversation, then they are less likely to be externally compliant yet secretly hostilite.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All or Nothing Changes</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/all-or-nothing-changes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 08:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/all-or-nothing-changes/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-all-or-nothing-changes.jpg" alt="All or Nothing Changes" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Feeling-Good-New-Mood-Therapy-ebook/dp/B009UW5X4C/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1452553054&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=feeling+good">Cognitive Behavioral Therapy&lt;/a> has taught me the danger in all or nothing thinking. If I enjoy my job, perhaps it isn&amp;rsquo;t a good idea to work 80 hours at it. If I fail at work, then &lt;em>all is not lost&lt;/em>. If I want to lose weight, perhaps the best thing to do is stop eating cookies. Maybe if I try to limit my processed food intake to zero I will freak out and eat three boxes of Oreos from the store. All or nothing thinking is the single most formidable thinking error component in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it&amp;rsquo;s only natural that I would fight it in change initiatives at work. When I get an idea for a change, I become obsessed. I read everything I can about it. I watch videos. I absorb the technology. Then I come up with a grand vision about how everything can be different. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if I sell people on &lt;em>that&lt;/em> grand vision, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen into a trap by handing the opponents of the change a huge weapon. If what you&amp;rsquo;re selling is perfection (or &amp;ldquo;all&amp;rdquo; in this case), then all it takes is for someone to demonstrate how your tool can&amp;rsquo;t possibly solve all the problems that we have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If instead you&amp;rsquo;re selling that a change will create a measurable impact for some of our major problems and opportunities, of course, the change can be scaled elsewhere. But let&amp;rsquo;s not focus on that right now. Let&amp;rsquo;s make something work. Let&amp;rsquo;s show everyone that this is for real. Let&amp;rsquo;s avoid &lt;em>nothing&lt;/em>. But let&amp;rsquo;s avoid &lt;em>all&lt;/em>, as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to create the perfect utopia I will brag about to my grandchildren, I can solve real problems. I can be flexible with my solution architecture. I can be more flexible with tools. I can solve real problems and create a platform for even greater change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Change never happens in the single inspirational speech. It happens every day, little by little, one problem at a time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of Culture in Cross-Discipline Change Initiatives</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-power-of-culture-in-cross-discipline-change-initiatives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 08:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-power-of-culture-in-cross-discipline-change-initiatives/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-power-of-culture-in-cross-discipline-change-initiatives.jpg" alt="Power of Culture" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When I started my career, I was rewarded for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">being creative&lt;/a>, stretching the boundaries, getting changes through the system to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/funding/">bring more revenue to my company&lt;/a>. I was a developer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When my SecOps colleague started his career, he was rewarded for keeping people like me from destroying the business with poorly planned implementations that make us vulnerable to attacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When my Operations colleague started her career, she was rewarded for taking the crazy ideas that the developer wanted to implement and translating them into something that &lt;em>will actually work&lt;/em>, subject to the rules that the SecOps person dictates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the natural state, we have all created value in our careers by trying to work around the flaws of the other groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To the developer, SecOps and Operations needlessly slow everything down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To SecOps, developers are dangerous and operations are unreliable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To Operations, SecOps are paranoid and developers don&amp;rsquo;t have a clue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I vastly underrated the power of these cultural scripts when first initiating our change initiatives around DevOps and automation.&lt;/strong> In fact, I mindlessly continued to follow my script. I went to SecOps with the attitude of &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rsquo;s this awesome change I want to do that will change our business, please approve of it.&amp;rdquo; They followed their cultural script with the response of &amp;ldquo;oh look here is a developer who just walked in with a weapon that can wipe out our entire business.&amp;rdquo; There is no partnership there; there is only conflict. And unfortunately, conflict is what I began with. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/my-advice-for-chef-in-large-corporations/">I&amp;rsquo;m still working to undo the damage&lt;/a> I did in those early days.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of the attitude I learned as a developer, I should have taken an attitude of a business person: &amp;ldquo;What are the problems that are or have the potential to drag down revenue and increase costs, and how can I help fix them?&amp;rdquo; It turns out that SecOps and Operations both have extremely valuable roles and they aren&amp;rsquo;t getting in the way of my awesome developer changes. They have problems just like the rest of us, and if I take the time to understand them, perhaps we can partner and solve them together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of coming to SecOps to try to get approval for the tool, why don&amp;rsquo;t I start with their compliance challenges and how we solve those? If I can use a tool to get their system more compliant, then that&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em>better&lt;/em> baseline from which we can do some other great things, like configuration management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of coming to Operations to merely implement the tool, why don&amp;rsquo;t I start with the problems they are having and iteratively help them solve those problems? Instead of just relying on the development teams, maybe I should start going to the Change Advisory Board meetings and then show up when the deployment happens. Then after that I can follow up and say, &amp;ldquo;For a couple of days of work, we can automate that. How does that sound?&amp;rdquo; All of the sudden I go from being a &lt;em>developer who doesn&amp;rsquo;t get it&lt;/em> to &lt;em>partner who will make my life easier&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the cultural roles shift away from conflict and towards cooperation, magical things will happen. I&amp;rsquo;m working like crazy to make that happen right now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Overdependent Organization</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-overdependent-organization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 08:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-overdependent-organization/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-overdependent-organization.jpg" alt="Overdependent Organization" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Years ago we went to a small church that met in a boys and girls club in our city. At one point I was leading the music on Sunday mornings, running our new visitor/assimilation program, attending a small group during the week, and leading the youth ministry of 10-20 students. This all happened while I had a full time computer programming job, our first child was born, and we were contributing 10% of my pre-tax income to the church.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I eventually got tired of all of this and decided it was time to move on. Within a month the church ended.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a banner saying, &amp;ldquo;Michael is leaving this church – we&amp;rsquo;re shutting down.&amp;rdquo; In fact the story is much different than that. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder what would have happened if I chose to leave a few years earlier. Would things have lasted so long? I&amp;rsquo;m inclined to think not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This experience has caused me to look at dependence on me in a different light. If I am &lt;em>the only reason&lt;/em> a project is staying afloat, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get out. Things that are worth doing don&amp;rsquo;t depend on one person to do them. They have followers, believers, excited people who will step up and fill in when you move on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I leave a project and see that it completely implodes, it&amp;rsquo;s a sign to me that I was shielding the organization from seeing the truth: that the initiative was fundamentally flawed and I was keeping it afloat. What I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to see is moving on from something that &lt;em>gets better&lt;/em> after I leave. I laid a foundation, and there was a true solution to a true problem that didn&amp;rsquo;t require my absolute attention. That&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate goal on anything I do at the moment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Proof of Concept</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/proof-of-concept/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 08:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/proof-of-concept/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-proof-of-concept.jpg" alt="Proof of Concept" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a classic scenario: a group of people &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/dont-start-with-tools/">want to use a tool&lt;/a> but before they can, they do a proof of concept (or POC) with the technology as a means of showing that it will do what it says it will do. In the past the proof of concept was purely a technical issue: how does the tool act when working with the various use cases we&amp;rsquo;ve identified? We create a sandbox and show the value at a demo or two, then we&amp;rsquo;re ready to move forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to stop there. But I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to take things further. The proof of concept should include at least two other aspects beyond technology:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Culture:&lt;/strong> can you &lt;strong>prove&lt;/strong> (through an experiment or two) that the people who will be involved with the new tool or change will be engaged as expected? It&amp;rsquo;s nice enough to have the person who is excited about the technology get it to provide value, but can an average person within the organization?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Security:&lt;/strong> how does your SecOps team feel about this change? Are they on board with it or resisting it? Will they cooperate to the extent that they can put it in production in a limited capacity?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/">our Chef initiative&lt;/a> both of these elements were concerns that were outside of the scope of our proof of concept. If I were to do things again, I would have put them in scope. That would have better clarified and added urgency to all elements that posed a risk to the change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A good test for a true proof of concept is whether you can get something running in production.&lt;/strong> If the answer is yes, then you are probably ready to go. If the answer is no, then watch out for what you&amp;rsquo;re buying and how easily you will be able to roll out the change you are promising.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building Alliances</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/building-alliances/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 08:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/building-alliances/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-building-alliances.jpg" alt="Building Alliances" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The other day I met with a friend and colleague about why a particular meeting went badly. The meeting was a few weeks back with a team that isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly thrilled about an initiative I&amp;rsquo;m championing. I knew this and basically did a demonstration of the proposed change, during which I was peppered with question after question. You know when you&amp;rsquo;re in a meeting and everyone is going along with it and the questions are constructive and getting everyone more excited about the possibilities? Well, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t that meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I&amp;rsquo;m following up with this friend, and he&amp;rsquo;s telling me that I should have met with him and his team before I met with the more hostile team. That way he could have known the context of my proposal and jumped in with his perspective in a way that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it &lt;em>the team vs. Michael&lt;/em> but made it more of a discussion. It was as if I put my chess piece unguarded on the other side of the board; I&amp;rsquo;m going to get killed. I need to have alliances if I&amp;rsquo;m going to effectively persuade people, especially those more naturally hostile to my proposal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was reminded of this recently when I read through &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lnxchk">Mandi Walls&lt;/a> really great and short book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Building-DevOps-Culture-Mandi-Walls-ebook/dp/B00CBM1WFC/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1452606188&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=building+a+devops+culture">Building a DevOps Culture&lt;/a>. She writes about the need to have a team of people around you that will help you roll out your DevOps initiatives:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This person, or team of people, will serve an important role, a combination of evangelist, tools expert, process subject-matter expert (SME), and buddy. They&amp;rsquo;re like your camp counselors. They&amp;rsquo;ll teach a little bit, answer questions, reassure the reluctant, and bring the marshmallows at the end of a long day. These folks are hard to find, and often aren&amp;rsquo;t who you think they are. The last person you want for a job like this is someone who&amp;rsquo;s smart but a complete jerk everyone hates but who happens to know how to use the tools. Find the people who everyone wishes were on their team, borrow some of their time, and form a working group to help other teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Mandi is right. At first I thought of myself as the champion of this thing. Then I very quickly met John who was better liked, more experienced, and more passionate about all of this than I am. John has delivered great results for both me and the company. He is so valuable to what we&amp;rsquo;re doing that I won&amp;rsquo;t use his last name, won&amp;rsquo;t link to his LinkedIn profile, and won&amp;rsquo;t even say whether I have changed his first name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John is the type of person I want on my team. Going forward if I am going into a potentially hostile situation or into a group of people who aren&amp;rsquo;t naturally inclined to go along with what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do, I&amp;rsquo;ll surround myself with liked, credible people who are able to fill in where I can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Technology &lt; Partnership</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/technology-partnership/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 08:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/technology-partnership/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-technology-partnership.jpg" alt="Technology Partnership" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Last year our organization &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/">made a major decision to use Chef&lt;/a> for our configuration management. People often ask me why we chose Chef over Puppet, SaltStack, or Ansible. I tell them that we chose Chef over the others because they have a better sales organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m only half kidding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve come to believe that the essence of success with change initiatives and tools is &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/dont-start-with-tools/">not about the underlying technology&lt;/a>. Chances are if you have a &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/funding/">funded popular tool&lt;/a> it&amp;rsquo;s going to have some cool technology. All of the above was cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead the essence of success with change initiatives is managing the organizational and cultural changes needed to make it to the other side. Chef is a great partner in helping us navigate our change through the various parties and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/my-advice-for-chef-in-large-corporations/">into a model that rapidly delivers value for our business&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve been extremely impressed with their organization at all levels and don&amp;rsquo;t think I would be where I am without their help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So don&amp;rsquo;t start with the tools. Start with the people, the culture, the process that will lead to safe, repeatable, high-velocity change. If you find a tool that will partner with you in that discovery, you probably have a world-class tool. If you start with the tool and ignore the other things, you might end up with a cool tool that no one wants or understands.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Before What</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/why-before-what/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 08:00:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/why-before-what/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-why-before-what.jpg" alt="Why Before What" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Recently a colleague and I were talking about his team&amp;rsquo;s agile transformation. He is excited about what&amp;rsquo;s to come but was challenged to bring everyone together in a meaningful way that leads to the change he wants to see. We talked about the importance of starting with a &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/who-is-with-you/">shared vision of a problem&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">iteratively working toward a solution&lt;/a>. It seems easier to just start with the end: &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going Agile!!!!&amp;rdquo; and watch everyone fall in line. Unfortunately it never happens that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was reminded of this while recently reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Building-DevOps-Culture-Mandi-Walls-ebook/dp/B00CBM1WFC/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1452565552&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=building+devops+culture">Building a DevOps Culture&lt;/a> by  &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lnxchk">Mandi Walls&lt;/a>. She writes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Proving change is necessary requires some legwork. It&amp;rsquo;s fine to want to change your organization because &amp;ldquo;everyone&amp;rdquo; is doing DevOps now, but you&amp;rsquo;re looking at months of work, new tools to learn and implement, teams to restructure. These costs must be outweighed by the benefits, so you have to be able to put real value on your processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Articulating upfront what your goals are will help you with other phases of your DevOps roll out.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is exactly the work I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing related to Chef over the past year. Recently we started talking about improving monitoring as well. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to say, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going with New Relic!&amp;rdquo; Or, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going with App Dynamics!&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve resisted that siren song, though, to really dig into what the problems are and what specific solutions fit the problems. When the problems are clear and measurable, the solutions have alignment and buy-in, and funding is easy. Without those core components, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid the issue is doomed. So I&amp;rsquo;m following Mandi&amp;rsquo;s advice and doing the hard work up front to define a shared vision of the problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't Start with Tools</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/dont-start-with-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/dont-start-with-tools/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-dont-start-with-tools.jpg" alt="Don't Start with Tools" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In the past whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to solve a technical problem, the first thing I would do is &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">find the right tool for the job&lt;/a>. I would then test that tool against the known use cases, share it with others in the organization, and see if excitement warrants further consideration. If we&amp;rsquo;re spending a lot of money, the vendor will get involved and help push everyone toward a decision to go with the tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The phase is so exciting, so full of promise&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And often completely misguided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of starting with the tool, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that I need to start with the business and the problems its leaders face. Once we all agree to the problems and have a clear, shared, measurable view of those problems, we can then determine the right tool for the job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently I was in a meeting about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/">Chef&lt;/a> with a colleague who is not very interested in adopting Chef for his project. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t see how Chef fits with his operational goals for next year. He was talking about his main pain points being the a greater need for operational visibility into his entire stack of hundreds of nodes. So I asked him, &amp;ldquo;what if we helped you solve that problem with a greater focus on monitoring?&amp;rdquo; He paused and said to me &amp;ldquo;I thought this meeting was about Chef.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once the meeting and discussion becomes about the tool, you&amp;rsquo;re no longer having the right conversation. Start with the problems, and find good solutions that fit those problems. Repeat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Putting Developers On Call</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/putting-developers-on-call/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 08:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/putting-developers-on-call/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-putting-developers-on-call.jpg" alt="Putting Developers On Call" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Recently I read through the short but sweet book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Building-DevOps-Culture-Mandi-Walls-ebook/dp/B00CBM1WFC/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1452554943&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=building+devops+culture">Building a DevOps Culture&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lnxchk">Mandi Walls&lt;/a>. In the book Mandi has an idea that I admit to having completely dismissed the moment I read it:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One of the early controversial aspects of what became DevOps was the assertion that Engineering should be doing on-call rotations. In fact, this idea was presented in a way that made it sound like your developers would want to be on call if they were truly dedicated to building the best possible product, because they were the ones responsible for the code.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>My immediate reaction was: &amp;ldquo;that would never work for us.&amp;rdquo; Whenever I have that kind of reaction, it&amp;rsquo;s a red flag. Never use the word never. So I asked myself why, thought about it, and dug a little deeper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main reason this would be a challenge for us is that for compliance reasons &lt;a href="http://www.sans.edu/research/security-laboratory/article/it-separation-duties">we keep developers out of production&lt;/a>. So even if the developers were on call, they would not be able to do much because they couldn&amp;rsquo;t access production.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;s a bummer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But wait, do they &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to access production to be on call? What if they were on call &lt;em>with&lt;/em> someone in operations that had the access. When there was an incident they could hop on to a screen sharing application and troubleshoot things together. In fact, this mirrors what happens when an incident is escalated: you have everyone get on a call and talk through an issue together, with operations having the power and control to make the changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If our developers were on call, they would accept more responsibility for creating a great product. They would then see the outcome of their good or bad design, and improve on it. Operations would feel like they&amp;rsquo;re not on an island trying to make something work with no context. The good things that could come out of such an initiative surely outweigh the problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that I&amp;rsquo;m sold on this being something that could help us, I&amp;rsquo;m now going to bring it up as something to try. It will be interesting to see if the idea has legs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who is with you?</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/who-is-with-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/who-is-with-you/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-who-is-with-you.jpg" alt="Who is With You" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There are three elements to every solution:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Knowing the problem well enough to know a few solutions and what you think is best&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bringing together everyone&amp;rsquo;s idea of a solution into one strategy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Execution&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to skip step #2. Why would you need that &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/surrounded/">if you are so smart&lt;/a> and already know the solutions?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is in order to &lt;em>really&lt;/em> do #3 you have &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/alignment/">to have alignment&lt;/a>. When you get to the end and have the solution, you should look around and see a crowd around you celebrating the accomplishment of &lt;em>their&lt;/em> problems with &lt;em>their&lt;/em> solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You are solving this together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you try to solve alone you will quickly realize that you spent a lot of energy going in the wrong direction.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Funding</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/funding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 08:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/funding/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-funding.jpg" alt="Funding" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We have a great idea. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/alignment/">We have alignment&lt;/a>. Everyone is excited. This is the right change for our organization!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there isn&amp;rsquo;t funding for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait! Someone says. We can work on it on the side. Maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll make maybe a little progress on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, you won&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We work in a business that exists to turn a profit. There are two ways to do this: increase revenue and reduce costs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those who have a compelling case that revenue will increase or costs will reduce will get the funding to pursue those objectives. It&amp;rsquo;s simple business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always use the funding question as a litmus test for viability of an idea. Are we willing to incur licensing and staffing expenses in order to create this outcome? If not then (1) I misread the cost or revenue realities of the business or (2) I didn&amp;rsquo;t properly sell them to the stakeholders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You see the true priorities of the business when you ask the funding question. This is why I never move past this question until it&amp;rsquo;s properly answered.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Whose Goals?</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/whose-goals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/whose-goals/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-whose-goals.jpg" alt="Whose Goals" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There have been times where my goals were &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/planned-thinking/">clear, written, specific&lt;/a>. When that happens a whole range of possibilities exist. The power of specific goals always amazes me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other times I&amp;rsquo;m coasting with no goals. I&amp;rsquo;m just making it to the next thing and not really thinking about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think that I just didn&amp;rsquo;t have anyone&amp;rsquo;s goals during those periods. A closer inspection reveals otherwise:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was meeting the goals of my more savvy colleagues that had clear goals themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was meeting the goals of Facebook or Twitter executives, for more page views, more advertising revenue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was meeting the goals of the Dallas Cowboys organization, for me to be a more engaged and thus more lucrative customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goals always exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My only choice is between having my goals or someone else&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surrounded</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/surrounded/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 08:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/surrounded/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-surrounded.jpg" alt="Surrounded" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Early in my career I was rewarded for knowing everything. People noticed when I interrupted, when I had the right answer. My boss took notice when I had the insight that he didn&amp;rsquo;t have at a critical moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The feeling of being the one that knows is so rewarding and addictive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a shame that it&amp;rsquo;s so limiting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you grow your ability to know and recognize the problems and solutions grows. Code turns into design. Design turns into process. Process turns into strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have to be the smartest person in the room at all times, you will simply not grow into the later stages. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So find a new addiction: surround yourself with people who have the answers that you used to have. Take notice at the critical moments when others stand up and reward those who fill those critical needs. And enjoy the journey into new territory that you&amp;rsquo;re there to conquer: the strategy, leadership, and process that it takes for your team and organization to be successful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Inferior "Right" Way</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-inferior-right-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-inferior-right-way/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-inferior-right-way.jpg" alt="Inferior Right Way" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent much of my career trying to find roadblocks to technical and organizational success. This passion leads me to great tools like &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">TeamCity&lt;/a> and of &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/">Chef&lt;/a>. My success in leveraging tools for organizational success leads me to be opinionated about what tools we should be using and how we should be doing things in our organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is so easily get locked into the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; solution that would &amp;ldquo;solve all of our problems.&amp;rdquo; Early on that worked just fine for me, but over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I&amp;rsquo;ve grown with our organization from a newly acquired startup to a mid-sized company to a large multinational, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that doing the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; thing &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/alignment/">without alignment&lt;/a> with the key stakeholders is the wrong thing. It&amp;rsquo;s not enough to read a book and evaluate a tool like chef to see that it will solve our problems. It&amp;rsquo;s not even enough to talk developers into using it and seeing its value. One must do serious work to analyze the state of the business, find the pain points that are either preventing revenue or creating unnecessary cost, and then set a strategy for addressing those things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that, one finds the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; way. After that, one finds the &amp;ldquo;tool&amp;rdquo; that they&amp;rsquo;ll use to solve the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyone claiming to be the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; tool or solution before that analysis happens is likely wasting your time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alignment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/alignment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 08:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/alignment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-alignment.jpg" alt="Alignment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You can meet with the CEO of your company and craft an awesome strategy for taking your business to the next level, but if you do not have the agreement of middle management you have nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can meet with countless people on the ground who know the real problems, but if you can&amp;rsquo;t quantify it in the way that their leadership can understand, you have nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read the greatest business book that lays out a superior path forward through industry best practices, but if you can&amp;rsquo;t join the solutions it promises to problems that are clear within your business, you have nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can craft a strategy with a respected leader in your organization to bring an initiative forward, but if her peers don&amp;rsquo;t see the value in the initiative, you have nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can even get an entire development organization rallied around a particular initiative, but if the sales organization doesn&amp;rsquo;t see that as adding value to its goals and the company&amp;rsquo;s profitability, you have nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Value isn&amp;rsquo;t found in leadership, books, best practices, departmental unity, or from those who do the work. &lt;strong>Value is found at the intersection of those things&lt;/strong>, where everyone sees the problem in the same way and will do their part in solving it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My life has been transformed by acknowledging the immense &lt;em>power of alignment&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Essential Components to Compliance at Velocity in the Enteprise</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/three-essential-components-to-compliance-at-velocity-in-the-enteprise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 08:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/three-essential-components-to-compliance-at-velocity-in-the-enteprise/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-three-essential-components-to-compliance-at-velocity-in-the-enteprise.jpg" alt="Compliance at Velocity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Security has been the most difficult part of &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/">implementing chef&lt;/a> in my large organization. I recently spoke with Chef about this and had a great conversation with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dromologue">Justin Arbuckle&lt;/a> related to it. Chef is focusing this year on helping organizations like mine to achieve compliance at velocity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through the conversation and Justin&amp;rsquo;s great advice, I realized that every Chef initiative must have these three elements to be sucessful:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="focus-on-the-workflow">Focus on the Workflow&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At first I was focused on the technology and what talked to what, which commands would be used, and how awesome the outcome would be for our business. From a security perspective, however, this was worthless. Security and compliance are focused on &lt;em>how we can safely make changes to this system&lt;/em>. This means that you don&amp;rsquo;t accidentally bring production down by a cookbook change. It also means that you get approvals within a defined process before making &lt;em>any&lt;/em> change. For us, this workflow didn&amp;rsquo;t really take shape until we decided to fully adopt &lt;a href="https://github.com/chef/chef-dk/blob/master/POLICYFILE_README.md">the Policy feature&lt;/a> and workflow for change management. We then wrote extensive documentation and visio diagrams to explain every element of every step in the journey from a checkin to a production change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until we had this documented and clear that we started making progress with our security team. The lesson we learned was: &lt;em>the technology is secondary to the workflow&lt;/em>. The workflow is most important. And, for you, if you&amp;rsquo;re security conscious and you haven&amp;rsquo;t looked at Policies yet, you really need to.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="make-it-real">Make it Real&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Looking back at the last few months of our implementation, we&amp;rsquo;ve spent way too much time in visio and not enough time creating a real environment in order to demonstrate the changes we&amp;rsquo;re talking about. I spent quite a lot of time trying to consolidate the chef ecosystem into something that someone could understand in an hour-long meeting, but that was ineffective. It turns out that: (1) chef is complicated and hard, that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s so powerful, and (2) people don&amp;rsquo;t generally have time to wrap their minds around it like I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Knowing what I know today, I would have started by creating an environment that demonstrated what I was talking about and then showed every stakeholder the workflow (defined above) applied to a real work situation that I could control. This is what we have done: we migrated YouTrack management to Chef and will demonstrate a secure, repeatable workflow to our security stakeholders with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This will shift the conversation away from the abstract and into the implemented. It also means there are no unknowns to implementing the solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="empower-security">Empower Security&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Security people are used to hearing from people, &amp;ldquo;We want to do this cool thing that will make &lt;em>our&lt;/em> lives easier but will make &lt;em>your&lt;/em> lives more difficult.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s natural for them to  approach chef in the same way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortunately, chef has made some amazing investments lately in features that enable a partnership with security rather than an impediment. The &lt;a href="https://www.chef.io/blog/2015/04/09/chef-audit-mode-cis-benchmarks/">audit mode features&lt;/a> recently released in Chef allow a security team to map the auditor&amp;rsquo;s implementation of the security compliance into actionable requirements that can then be applied to the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, all of the sudden, the crazy devops person who wants to make everything go faster is the person who will enable automated, reported compliance for PCI throughout our data center. The posture of the security group changes from being antagonistic into being a true partnership.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re planning on taking some PCI requirements and writing audit cookbooks for them. We&amp;rsquo;ll go into the auditing relationship with demonstratable proof that we are creating a more secure, auditable, and fast system for managing configuration in our hosted environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Empathy is probably the most important aspect of any change. Begin with how a change will improve the effectiveness of your colleagues and the ultimate profitability of your company. Security is no different. Thanks to my friends at Chef, I have a more solid strategy for meeting those goals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Discriminatory Wind</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/discriminatory-wind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/discriminatory-wind/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-discriminatory-wind.jpg" alt="Discrimantory Wind" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The other day I was &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/">riding my bike&lt;/a> to work, felt great, and got there in 26 minutes. I usually take about 35 minutes to get there. My wife even noticed with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/">my automated location texts&lt;/a> that my phone sent her (Michael is leaving home, Michael is arriving at work). She sent me a text congratulating me on the great accomplishment. I even congratulated myself a bit on how regularly I bike now and how I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten so much better at this over the last year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the end of the day, I started home. The wind was screaming in my face, and I could barely go over 10 MPH.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the way home, I saw two bikers going in the opposite direction, cruising along happily. They looked at me with pity, thinking I was out of shape. I wanted to yell out, through the wind, &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t realize how good you have it!!!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost an hour later I was home. I was tired and beaten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When the wind is at your back, you go faster. You don&amp;rsquo;t realize it&amp;rsquo;s the wind that is pushing you; you think it&amp;rsquo;s you doing it. &lt;strong>When the wind is in your face, you are constantly reminded of the challenge and you constantly have to push.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are women I meet at conferences and work who have had the wind in their face and pushed through anyway and built successful careers. They meet countless people along the way who think they are better suited for more people-oriented professions like sales.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At a recent conference, a lady in technology was checking out a technology at a sales booth. The person at the booth immediately raised his voice to a less threatening and gentle voice and then remarked about how surprised he was to hear that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t in sales herself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At other times women run into people who will mindlessly delegate the meeting notes, or the administrative tasks to them, because…there is no good reason.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Minorities within technology have the wind in their face and push through. I was horrified to overhear a white man at an event start talking with an inner city accent to an African American man about how he was going to go &amp;ldquo;all ghetto&amp;rdquo; on some technology and make it work, presumably, by not taking digital prisoners. The African American man politely acknowledged the awesomeness of this endeavor and quickly exited the conversation. I thought to myself, how many of these types of conversations does this person have to endure in places like this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a white heterosexual male in technology, the wind is at your back. You may not notice it, but it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What to do for the others? My rule is that I will always treat others as people, never as labels, and keep my interest and conversation toward what can make them successful. I never bring up their status; they have enough awkward examples of that without me adding to it. But I also make an effort, in whatever way I can, to support, encourage, and respect those who have exhibited much more tenacity and courage than I have.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Advice For Chef in Large Corporations</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/my-advice-for-chef-in-large-corporations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 11:21:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/my-advice-for-chef-in-large-corporations/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-my-advice-for-chef-in-large-corporations.jpg" alt="Advice for Chef" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s my simple advice about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/">Chef&lt;/a> I wish I would have heard a year ago:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of the stories about &lt;a href="http://www.itskeptic.org/content/devops-unicorns-horses-and-mules">the unicorns, rainbows, and fairies&lt;/a> that are doing absolutely amazing things with configuration automation are extremely inspirational. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/customizing-chef-book-review/">Read about them&lt;/a>. Learn about them. Enjoy their talks. Enjoy their hipster vibe. Tell yourself that you are going to be cool like that one day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then forget everything they are talking about. Because what they are doing is likely too advanced for what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to do, because you&amp;rsquo;re not five years or more into your infrastructure automation initiative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do this instead:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Create these four nodes in your Data Center, behind firewalls, with no outside connectivity whatsoever:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>A Chef Server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Chef Client with the &lt;a href="https://downloads.chef.io/chef-dk/">ChefDK&lt;/a> installed on it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A Chef Analytics Server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An Artifacts Server (like SFTP server)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Does your security team not allow connectivity between Production and UAT? Awesome! Build two environments! Does your security team segment audited environments from non-audited environments? Awesome! Build the above four servers in &lt;em>every segmented environment you have&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You heard that right. Now isn&amp;rsquo;t the time to get into pissing matches about your &amp;ldquo;new devops vision of greatness&amp;rdquo; that will totally transfor&amp;hellip;EVERYTHING! No, now is the time to automate the things. Set up your servers and make it happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If this becomes political, then you are doing it wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>But Michael, how am I going to maintain all those environments?&lt;/em> Well, thankfully you have the joy and pleasure of (1) probably having a bad system in place which is why you are looking at Chef, and (2) Policyfiles. So get over your perfectionism and implement this easy workflow for change management:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.chef.io/config_rb_policyfile.html">Use a policyfile&lt;/a> for every node in your infrastructure&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Save changes to policyfiles into Git where each team has their policyfiles in their own git repository separate from their cookbooks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use your CI &lt;a href="https://docs.chef.io/ctl_chef.html#chef-install">to automatically generate&lt;/a> your policyfile.lock.json files and check them into Git.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use your CI to &lt;a href="https://docs.chef.io/ctl_chef.html#chef-export">to package each policy into a file&lt;/a> with the &lt;a href="https://docs.chef.io/ctl_chef.html#chef-export">chef export&lt;/a> command. This has all cookbooks, policy, everything.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=how+to+transfer+a+file+from+one+place+to+another">Get your updated policy archives to your Data Center&lt;/a>. You should be good at this. You do this already.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.chef.io/ctl_chef.html#chef-push-archive">Activate your archives&lt;/a> on the Chef Server for the appropriate policy group with the &lt;a href="https://docs.chef.io/ctl_chef.html#chef-push-archive">chef push-archive&lt;/a> command&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s as easy as that. Have one or a hundred chef servers and you have those six steps above. You can save the absolutely mind blowing automation of step #5 and the simplification of everything later. That&amp;rsquo;s not the most important thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s most important: an application team deploys an upgrade with zero outages and zero problems. Then they brag to their leadership about it because it never went this smoothly when they did it the old way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notice nobody cared about a stupid security argument about what ports are open between environments (there are none in the above proposal) or trying to be &lt;a href="https://codeascraft.com/">like Etsy&lt;/a> or Netflix. People saw the zero outage and zero problems and people said to themselves, ‘Holy Shit This Is Real.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>!(Holy Shit This Is Real)[http://i.imgur.com/ON3nwXb.png]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Multiply the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/ON3nwXb">Holy Shit This Is Real&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; moments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to accomplish. Not a dream state. Not what a book said. You&amp;rsquo;re fundamentally transforming your organization&amp;rsquo;s ability to react to change, and that capability will be an absolute game changer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So get out of the politics, get out of the arguments, document and implement the simple strategy above, and watch perceptions of what is possible rapidly change.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intrinsic Motivators Leading to Chef</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 08:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-intrinsic-motivators-leading-to-chef.jpg" alt="Intrinsic Motivators" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m reading about culture in &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1LfPSL8">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>, and the author makes the point that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u6XAPnuFjJc">bonuses aren&amp;rsquo;t the most effective means of motivating employees&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>While extrinsic motivators such as bonuses are effective in&amp;hellip;mechanical work, they actually &lt;em>reduce&lt;/em> performance in the context of knowledge work. People involved in nonroutine work are motivated by intrinsic factors summarized by Dan Pink as:&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>1: &lt;em>Autonomy:&lt;/em> the desire to direct our own lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>2. &lt;em>Mastery:&lt;/em> the urge to get better and better at something that matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>3. &lt;em>Purpose:&lt;/em> the yearning to do what we do in the service of something larger than ourselves.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think this does a really great job of describing what my intrinsic motivators are for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/" title="Learning Chef Book Review">rolling out Chef&lt;/a> in our organization. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;d love to be compensated well for doing what we are doing and would never argue to the contrary. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen though in the past that money is just money and there are things that matter to me as much or more than money. Daniel Pink really hits the nail on the head about what those are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Autonomy:&lt;/strong> providing this capability to my company will create more of an ability to direct my own path in the future. The more value I help create, the more I can be in control on how I express that value, and the more freedom I&amp;rsquo;ll have, within the context of a team, to solve problems that interest me.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Mastery:&lt;/strong> here is something that I can master: how to automate infrastructure configuration management through code using chef. This is something that can scale quite large, and I have the ability to become one of a few people in the organization that has a full handle on it. That&amp;rsquo;s exciting to me! I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be mediocre or have a skill that everyone else views as a commodity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Purpose:&lt;/strong> this is the biggest intrinsic motivator for what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. People who do configuration management today have chaotic lives and regularly stay up all hours of the night to perform their duties manually. I get to change that! Our customers don&amp;rsquo;t yet have the uptime and consistency that they expect and deserve. I get to help change that, and create a game-changing strength for our organization compared to our competitors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m excited about this journey that I&amp;rsquo;m on. The motivators are far more intrinsic than extrinsic. I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that is why they are so powerful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning from Ebola Healthcare Workers with Enterprise Problem Solving</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 09:30:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving.jpg" alt="Learning from Ebola" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In a large enterprise it can be difficult to implement large meaningful change. On many days I have ended up frustrated while sitting down to a margarita during &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">one of my quarterly retrospectives&lt;/a>. How do I get through all the opinions and politics to create real, lasting change? After reading about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">the Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a>, I have a new way of thinking about it, which starts with healthcare workers in West Africa &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/news/international/21625813-ebola-epidemic-west-africa-poses-catastrophic-threat-region-and-could-yet">fighting Ebola&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When these brave individuals arrive to risk their lives and help others, they are met with a striking contrast to the first world. As you have probably learned, there are entire tribes of people in West Africa who celebrate the recently deceased within an elaborate ceremony where the entire tribe drinks after the deceased loved one in a shared cup. Science certainly had nothing to do with it, but science does tell us that when the deceased person has Ebola, this is a surefire way of getting the whole village infected. Couple this with the cultural norm that those who are sick should travel large distances to medicine men who will heal them, and you have an epidemic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, faced with such a terrible situation of men, women, and children dying every day due to a horrible disease, what do I imagine is the reaction of these healthcare workers? Do they pound their fists and whine, &amp;ldquo;We could change this situation if these people weren&amp;rsquo;t being so &lt;em>stupid?&amp;quot;&lt;/em> Do they clock in and out, thinking that the problem is just too large and that they will just collect a paycheck so that they can support their family? In other words, is their primary approach to the situation that of &lt;em>frustration&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think they certainly feel frustration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, these people are professional scientists, and they probably follow &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_method">a much different formula&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First, they start with a hypothesis.&lt;/strong> They ask themselves, maybe if we visit the tribal leaders we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to convince them that this practice is dangerous and that will stop the spread of this disease. If the leaders cannot be convince, then they may say that the tribes are a lost cause and that maybe they should lock down the entrances to the cities. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are hundreds of ideas that they come up, all without despair, but with a genuine hope that something can be done to improve the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Next, they test the most promising hypothesis.&lt;/strong> The team may decide to educate the tribal leaders. They then create a short-term way to test their hypothesis. They decide to go to one village and talk to the tribal leaders then pay an informant to record the activities of the next funeral, which is likely to happen in the coming days. They try this with ten villages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Finally, they measure the results of the test.&lt;/strong> Out of the ten villages, only two changed their practices. While many of us might view this as a failure, the scientists see this as success. We now know what &lt;em>wouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> be helpful. Now we can come up with a better hypothesis and start the process all over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method is what got us technology, medicine, and progress. &lt;strong>Why aren&amp;rsquo;t we using it in the enterprise?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Continuous Delivery Needed in Our Organization?</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/is-continuous-delivery-needed-in-our-organization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/is-continuous-delivery-needed-in-our-organization/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-is-continuous-delivery-needed-in-our-organization.jpg" alt="Continuous Delivery" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Continuous Delivery sounds wonderful when &lt;a href="http://www.infoq.com/interviews/jez-humble-lean-enterprise">you&amp;rsquo;re at a conference&lt;/a>. You hear about companies like &lt;a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/netflix-continuous-delivery">Netflix&lt;/a> that deploy to production many times per day. When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/">learning Chef&lt;/a>, people often ask me if we really need something that will enable us to deploy that often. Some of them are on projects that take many months to deliver, and the customer would have it no other way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I answer this problem by splitting it up into two questions:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How quickly does a customer want a Severity 1 defect fixed in production?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d say the answer to this is usually, regardless of the tooling used, within a few hours. If there is a critical defect affecting operations, no one is talking about how we&amp;rsquo;ll have that delivered in a few months. People are on phones, developers are doing what it takes to get done, and something happens. So I&amp;rsquo;d say in this situation it&amp;rsquo;s a great investment to automate your delivery so the emergency situation is as tested as the non emergency situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How quickly does a customer want a feature in production?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a trickier question. We can separate the answer into what the customer &lt;em>wants&lt;/em> and what the customer &lt;em>expects&lt;/em>. The customer &lt;em>wants&lt;/em> to have the feature in production right now. Otherwise they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have told you about it. I have never heard a user make a request for change in software and say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just letting you know, I&amp;rsquo;d rather have it six months from now.&amp;rdquo; Now is always better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, our customers have a business to run, so they&amp;rsquo;re not going to be foolish with updates. They want us to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/safety-net/">fully test and properly deliver the software&lt;/a>. So I believe their answer to this question would be: &lt;strong>as quickly as you can safely get it to me.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a flexible arrangement based on the trust we create from automating our delivery and testing process. The better job we do, the more they trust us and the quicker they get their software. It will probably never be _today_that they get updates, but also if we&amp;rsquo;re taking this seriously it also shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a long time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So even for us, with real customers that are paying us to get it right, there is room for continuous delivery and Chef.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The One Metric that Matters</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 08:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-one-metric-that-matters.jpg" alt="Metric that Matters" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The more I measure &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">the more successful I am&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve known this for a while, but I realize that the lack of measurement is still the thing that is holding my career back. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about how measurement is key to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">The Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a> of using the scientific method to find innovation in your organization. So I&amp;rsquo;m hooked with this idea, but I desperately want to implement it in a good way. I want to have a breakthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Lean Enterprise&lt;/em> book cites the &lt;em>Lean Analytics&lt;/em> book concept of &lt;strong>The One Metric That Matters (OMTM):&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>OMTM is a single metric that we prioritize as the most important to drive decisions depending on the stage of our product lifecycle and our business model…We focus on One Metric that Matters to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Answer the most pressing question we have by linking it to the assumptions in the hypothesis we want to test&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create focus, conversation, and thought to identify problems and simulate improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide transparency and a shared understanding across the team and wider organization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support a culture of experimentation by basing it on rates or ratios, not averages or totals, relevant to our historical data set&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When I started out my current project in 2008, my boss for a very short time was &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-hughes/3/720/3a3">Jeff Hughes&lt;/a>, who is a genius at innovating software. The project I was doing was related to software quality, so Jeff gave me a metric for the first year: make defect containment go up, as defined by the percentage of software defects found inside the company related to the software defects found by our customers. He gave me the one metric that matters, and with that direction I was able to take the project in the direction it needed to go. At first we thought that we were going to stick with testing just customer situations, but we ended up having a mixture of customer situations and vanilla, or regression, situations. Without that &amp;ldquo;one metric that matters&amp;rdquo;, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the freedom to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fast forward to last year, I started a project to improve the installation experience for all of our products that get installed in restaurants. Everyone seemed to want this to be better so I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop and create the one metric that matters. I rushed ahead and started on the solution. My one metric that mattered internally was lowered cycle time from a release to working software. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to define where we were before I started, and how my changes had improved the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This led to a lot of unnecessary drama. People would question &lt;em>why&lt;/em> we were taking a particular approach. People would question whether an improvement was warranted in the first place (even after agreeing that it was warranted before). It&amp;rsquo;s easy to point fingers and talk about how people don&amp;rsquo;t understand or care, but they do understand and they do care. I just didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to create a metric that would measure what outcome I&amp;rsquo;m trying to create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is not a lesson &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">I will soon forget&lt;/a>. I hope that I will be able to fundamentally transform my approach to include measurement as one of the key aspects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progression of Responsibility</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-progression-of-responsibility.jpg" alt="Progression of Responsibility" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>While reading &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zxdulv">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, I&amp;rsquo;m coming up with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/">a lot of great ideas&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">improvements for my organization&lt;/a>. Much of the book so far has been about how to properly execute portfolio management within an enterprise to make sure that (1) you maximize ROI, and (2) you don&amp;rsquo;t manage your existing proven products with an investment horizon of this year or this quarter the same way that you would manage innovation products that have a longer investment horizon. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something occurred to me though. In order to gain entry into the higher level strategic decisions, one must first master the lower level ones. Here&amp;rsquo;s a progression I can see, that I wish I knew about ten years ago:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Personal Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you take on work in an efficient, organized way? Do you have a system for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/" title="Getting Things Done Action Plan">getting things done&lt;/a>, a system for communicating with others, for follow-up, for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">what to do when things get difficult&lt;/a>? Do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/" title="Two Questions You Should Ask About Your Commitments">when you&amp;rsquo;re overcommitting&lt;/a>?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Planning Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you understand why we are doing what we are doing on this project? Do you measure things in terms of how they will profit your company or on some other, less meaningful way? Do you have a way to create value for your stakeholders quickly by strategically prioritizing certain things over others? Do you know what the short-term and long-term risks to the product and what can be done about them?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Management Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/" title="Measure for Reality">how to measure success&lt;/a>? Have you linked the measurement to profitability of the company? Are you able to iteratively create improvements to measurements in a fluid, changing situation? Are people motivated by your leadership and understand the parameters that you&amp;rsquo;ve set out that measures your team&amp;rsquo;s success?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Executive Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> are you able to create profitability for the various products in your portfolio in a way that respects their lifecycle? Are your established, older products increasing in quality and customer satisfaction? Have your newer innovative products succeeded in creating new markets, as measured by appropriate metrics? Has your team leadership received the appropriate amount of direction (not too detailed to constrain innovation and not too broad to create chaos)? Have you had innovation experiments that have failed in the past three months, that had minimal investment yet provided a valuable lesson for the leadership team?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Right now I&amp;rsquo;m at #3. It&amp;rsquo;s fun reading about #4 in the book, but I do realize the trap of trying to live in a place that is beyond your current capability:** If you live in a later stage than you&amp;rsquo;re at right now, you end up ignoring the key elements that are needed to progress to the next stage.** So I can start thinking a lot about portfolio management or how we would manage innovative products differently than our established products. But if I get too caught up in that, I avoid the reality for me right now: I need to find a measurement of success that leads to profitability of my company for every project that I&amp;rsquo;m doing, be able to communicate that to others, and manage its improvement with a team. That will be my focus over the next year or so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone comes to me about how we need to do a better job planning yet don&amp;rsquo;t have an established workflow for how they manage their own work, I quickly get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone wants to be a manager of a group but can&amp;rsquo;t see what that group is doing strategically and the trade-offs that exist in the group, I get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to master your current responsibilities before you can progress to others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Phoenix Project Book Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-phoenix-project-book-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 08:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-phoenix-project-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-phoenix-project-book-review.jpg" alt="Phoenix Project" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As I&amp;rsquo;ve looked into devops more and more over the past few months, the book &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1AinIdB">The Phoenix Project&lt;/a> has come up over and over. I finally bought it when Matt Stratton at chef basically insisted on it in &lt;a href="http://www.mattstratton.com/tech/devops">his very awesome reading list&lt;/a> to ramp yourself up on devops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been into fiction very much, but over the summer I read &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zx9aT7">A Man in Full&lt;/a> as a means of integrating stoicism into my own philosophy. That book lit up my imagination and helped me absorb the stoic themes in a way that would be difficult had I just read an outline of stoicism. I was awakened to the reality of how fiction can transform your mind deeply by awakening all aspects of the mind during learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I was very excited to read the book. And the book did not disappoint in changing my outlook on my own career and what is possible for those around me. It taught me a few basic lessons that I believe will transform my behavior in the future:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Have a respect for the system.&lt;/strong> Up until I read this book I treated a inefficient system like it was garbage. Let&amp;rsquo;s get rid of the inefficiency! This is dumb! What I realized by reading the book is that in order for you to effectively and profitably change a system, you must have a respect and understanding of why it is the way it is. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know why it is this way, you can realize that it is an inefficient system, but you will not effectively change it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">Measure, Measure, Measure&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong> The main character in the book has a great respect for measurement. People say you can&amp;rsquo;t manage what you don&amp;rsquo;t measure. I think that can be taken too far, but there is a reality in it: if I can&amp;rsquo;t measure the reality of the system, it will be very difficult for me to (1) convince people that a more efficient change is needed, and (2) know that the changes I am making are having their desired effect.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Take a Breath and Count to 2.&lt;/strong> One of the nice things about the book that taught me a lesson is when the main character interacts with various antagonists, who are obviously being reckless, dumb, and incendiary, the main character will take a breath and count to 2. Then respond. And when he responds, it&amp;rsquo;s with facts and an attitude of doing what&amp;rsquo;s best for everyone. I desperately want to exhibit this kind of tact and patience. I get so passionate about my ideas that I can forget to have patience, be calm, and move the ball forward.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Find the Bottleneck Constraint.&lt;/strong> In the book there is a legendary character named Brent. Brent can do everything. He can fix problems in seconds that everyone has spent days trying to understand. He knows why this server is the way it is, and the answer lies in activities from 2002. Brent has everyone asking him for everything and the business is at it&amp;rsquo;s knees due to Brent&amp;rsquo;s inability to clone himself into fifty other people. In the book, the main focus was on getting Brent isolated and his work properly documented, prioritized, and managed. Brent remained a hugely valuable member of the team, but they couldn&amp;rsquo;t grow until his workload was under control. And once Brent had his priorities under control, he was able to do some special things for the company.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed the Phoenix Project and recommend it to anyone wanting to lead change in their organization using lean principles. It reaches the reader in a way that a nonfiction book can&amp;rsquo;t: you can feel the tension. You drop the F-bombs right there with the reader. You feel the desperation as the core concepts come to life. And therefore when you face similar situations, you have a whole new world of awesome manufacturing theory available to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This book was one of the best software-related books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. If you want to be a leader, please get a copy and read it. Then invite me to lunch and let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it; maybe we can change the world together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Son's Choice Between Negativity and Taking Action</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 08:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-my-sons-choice-between-negativity-and-taking-action.jpg" alt="Negativity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My son has felt negative about everything lately which has created for him a vicious cycle of disdain and despair. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/embrace-difficulty/" title="Embrace Difficulty">He is a lot like me&lt;/a>, so whenever we learn a lesson about him, it usually has something to do with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">how I&amp;rsquo;m wired as well&lt;/a>. He and I sat in bed a few nights ago and I walked him through this very basic method of how leaders have a choice to make:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I talked about how he and I are gifted with the ability to think deeply about things and thus we see things that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.** We have the responsibility of being able to see problems that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.** Something that bothers him is how his cub scout pack meetings spend too much time talking to the parents and that leaves him feeling like the meeting isn&amp;rsquo;t his. When I asked one of his good friends about cub scouts, his friend said, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m cursed as well about seeing problems everywhere. I talked to a police officer one time that told me that every room he goes into, even if it&amp;rsquo;s a church sanctuary, he automatically tries to ascertain who in that room is a potential threat. That man has a similar curse: he sees problems that other people don&amp;rsquo;t see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I then asked Samuel why he thought President Obama wanted to be President. &amp;ldquo;Because he wanted to be famous.&amp;rdquo; I told him how there are better ways of being famous. The truth is Mr. Obama became President Obama because he saw problems that others didn&amp;rsquo;t see and cared enough about them to get in public life. &lt;strong>A leader always starts with a perception of something wrong in the world.&lt;/strong> If nothing was wrong, there would be no leaders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it&amp;rsquo;s a given that a potential leader sees problems. It is our curse. The question now, is: what are we going to do about it? There are two choices:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A potential leader &lt;em>could&lt;/em> choose the path of negativity, disdain, and ultimately despair.&lt;/strong> This is the path of the critic, the internet troll, or the quitter. This is the path my son was on and one I&amp;rsquo;ve been on many times. I can see what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the situation, and my response is to continue to criticize or believe that nothing will ever change and quit. It&amp;rsquo;s even easier to do this when &lt;em>I&amp;rsquo;m the only one who sees the problems!&lt;/em> Well of course you&amp;rsquo;re the only one who sees the problems; perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re the one who is supposed to do something about it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Or a potential leader &lt;em>could&lt;/em> choose the path of taking action, improvement, patience, and love.&lt;/strong> In other words &lt;strong>a potential leader could choose the path of leadership.&lt;/strong> This is the path I encouraged Samuel to take. The question isn&amp;rsquo;t what problems do you see with cub scout pack meetings; the question is what are you going to do about those problems? When you see a problem with a group of people, the loving thing you can do is, within your power, help solve that problem with them! It&amp;rsquo;s not to despair and quit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes problems are so deep and impenetrable that there is nothing you can do about them. At that point the best thing to do &lt;em>is&lt;/em> quit. However, most times the problems are there and as a leader we can work to make them better. That&amp;rsquo;s the path of leadership, the path of people who are cursed with the ability to recognize problems that others don&amp;rsquo;t see and choose to take action to solve those problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Lean Startup Cycle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 08:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-lean-startup-cycle.jpg" alt="Lean Startup Cycle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermann_Hauser">Herman Hauser&lt;/a> created a team to create the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARM_architecture">ARM processor&lt;/a>, now the processor that runs most of the mobile devices you know and love, &lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/features/358750/whatever-happened-to-hermann-hauser">he remarked&lt;/a>*:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When we decided to do a microprocessor, in hindsight, I think I made two great decisions. I trusted the team and gave them two things that Intel and Motorola had never given their people: the first was no money and the second was no people. They had to keep it simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When you start a project the normal course of action is to try to get as many people as possible so you will be able to have enough resources to accomplish the goal. In &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1HdjuUt">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>, the authors advocate another way, what they call &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_startup">the Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Working out what we need to &lt;em>learn&lt;/em> by creating a value hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Decide what to &lt;em>measure&lt;/em> in order to test that hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design an experiment, called the &lt;em>minimum viable product&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Build&lt;/em> the minimum viable product to gather the necessary data from real customers to determine if we have a good product/market fit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The authors continue:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trick is to invest a minimum of work to go through this cycle. Since we are operating in conditions of extreme uncertainty, we expect that our value hypothesis will be incorrect. At this point we &lt;em>pivot&lt;/em>, coming up with a new value hypothesis based on what we have learned, and go through this process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I love this idea. Instead of wasting years of time and money on an idea, let&amp;rsquo;s realize that we don&amp;rsquo;t know everything and use the scientific method to get us to the right idea. Let&amp;rsquo;s not be afraid of failure; you can&amp;rsquo;t have innovation without failure. &lt;strong>The key to innovation isn&amp;rsquo;t avoiding failure; the key is reacting to failure earlier than the competition.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method also calls into question the annual budget cycle. If all you have is once chance a year to respond to reality, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up clamoring for more people and avoid the simple, early, scientific method laid out above. A better way is to start small, provide some runway to solve a problem, and scale only when the solution shows its value in the real world.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I got this quote from Lean Enterprise as well, but cite the original source as they did.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mission Command</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 08:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-mission-command.jpg" alt="Mission Command" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In the past whenever I found myself micromanaged, I complained that I&amp;rsquo;m not in the military, and I should have freedom to operate in my best judgement to solve the problem. I viewed the military as a command and control environment where orders were specifically given and followed to the T. I then reasoned that this is not how successful organizations operate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The excellent book &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zGXBeP">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>&lt;/em> has debunked this myth with a concept of Mission Command that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you. From the book*:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In reality, command and control has not been fashionable in military circles since 1806 when the Prussian Army, a classic plan-driven organization, was decisively defeated by Napoleon&amp;rsquo;s decentralized, highly motivated forces.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Sounds a lot like a startup vs. a large company. Except this is two hundred years ago. The authors continue:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Napoleon used a style of war known as &lt;em>maneuver warfare&lt;/em> to defeat, larger, better-trained armies. In maneuver warfare, the goal is to minimize the need for actual fighting by disrupting your enemy&amp;rsquo;s ability to act cohesively through the use of shock and surprise. A key element in maneuver warfare is beinig able to learn, make decisions, and act faster than your enemy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Once the Prussians were defeated, they studied what went wrong and how they needed to innovate their military strategy in order to regain dominance. Their thought leadership came up with the concept of &lt;em>Auftragstaktick&lt;/em>, or Mission Command:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In 1869, Helmuth von Moltke issued a directive titled &amp;ldquo;Guidance for Large Unit Commanders&amp;rdquo; which sets out how to lead a large organization under conditions of uncertainty. In this ducment, von Moltke notes that &amp;ldquo;in war, circumstances change very rapidly, and this is rare indeed for directions which cover a long period of time in a lot of detail to be fully carried out.&amp;rdquo; He thus recommends &lt;strong>&amp;lsquo;not commanding more than is strictly necessary, nor planning beyond the circumstances you can foresee.'&lt;/strong> Instead he has this advice: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>the higher the level of command, the shorter and more general the orders should be. The next level down should add whatever further specification it feels &lt;em>to be necessary&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> and the details of the execution are left to verbal instructions or perhaps a word of command.** This ensures that everyone retains the freedom of movement and decision within the bounds of their authority &amp;ldquo;**the rule to follow is that an order should contain all, but also only, what subordinates cannot determine for themselves to achieve a particular purpose.**&amp;rdquo; [emphasis mine]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So with lives on the line leaders implemented a sophisticated framework for implementing strategy while preserving freedom. This happened 150 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s still difficult to implement today, though. We either overdo it with too much control because &amp;ldquo;the leaders know best, that&amp;rsquo;s why they&amp;rsquo;re leaders.&amp;rdquo; Or we give everyone autonomy and everyone ends up going in different directions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These kinds of ideas are what I love about the &lt;em>Lean Enterprise&lt;/em> book in particular and the lean movement in general. Software seems so new to everyone, that you can get caught up in solving problems in new ways and giving crazy names to them, like scrum, agile, TDD, etc. But the lean movement says, &amp;ldquo;Hey, we&amp;rsquo;ve had a few hundred years of solving problems with technology and enlightened thinking. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably find a lot of answers from those who have gone before you.&amp;rdquo; This concept of Mission Control is a great example of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the book also credits The &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1Hdelfn">Art of Action&lt;/a> for developing these ideas. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read this book but it&amp;rsquo;s on my short list.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Test of Tolerance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance.jpg" alt="Tolerance" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I am fortunate to be married &lt;a href="http://reclaimed.house">to someone&lt;/a> who shares many of &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">my values and passions&lt;/a>. For the things we disagree with, though, I have to find a way &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">to not control her&lt;/a> and to let her be her own person. This is the ultimate expression of tolerance: she is welcome in my personal space, influences my future, and is free to &amp;ldquo;ruin&amp;rdquo; it with her own dreams and values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key to making it work is giving her freedom and working hard to connect so values and goals can be shared as much as possible. It won&amp;rsquo;t always work, but if it does, then it is the start of a lifestyle of this, which opens up so many wonderful relationships in all areas of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We like to think of tolerance as something that happens with people who are drastically different than us. With people from other political parties, religions, or backgrounds. I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years that tolerance really begins with those who are closest to me: &lt;strong>do I try to control them or do I let them freely be themselves?&lt;/strong> That&amp;rsquo;s ultimately the question that is asked of all of our relationships. The less we control, the better the relationships are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Right Fit</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/right-fit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/right-fit/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-right-fit.jpg" alt="Right Fit" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">My wife&lt;/a> and I spent the early part of this week looking into a business opportunity that would help us meet some specific goals over the next few years. We were excited, talking late into the night about the various details of this business opportunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then halfway into our trip we realized &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/">it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to work&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, we could have made it work. We could have brought more into the deal and thus introduced more risk. We could have compromised our values or our goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was reminded me of &lt;a href="http://blogmaverick.com/2010/08/25/the-best-investment-advice-you-will-ever-get/">Mark Cuban&amp;rsquo;s advice&lt;/a>: get out of debt and save up 100K in cash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why does he give this advice? Because if you have cash that you can invest, a right fit will come along and present itself. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go try to make things work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have to force anything. I can stay true to my values. And I should continue to live a simple and frugal lifestyle. If I do this, the right fit will come along.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assumption of Agreement</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/assumption-of-agreement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/assumption-of-agreement/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-assumption-of-agreement.jpg" alt="Assumption of Agreement" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We were having a great time with our new friends from California on a gogi-berry farm in New Mexico. The family loves nature like us, and we had great conversations about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/">biking&lt;/a>, hiking, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">living simply&lt;/a>, and cooking naturally. At one point the lady told us that they would love to have us back next summer and that they were pleasantly surprised to find out that there were liberals from Dallas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was eating dinner at my church on a Wednesday night with other members, and one member starts talking about how evil Wendy Davis is and how Obama has ruined everything. I sat there quietly as the whole table seemed to being railing on how dumb the Democrats were and how the world was going to end because of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s the common thread? It&amp;rsquo;s what I call the&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.chrisdikes.com/2013/05/30/the-ever-changing-idea-of-god/">Chris Dikes Assumption of Agreement Hypothesis&lt;/a>. From his post:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One common thread I&amp;rsquo;ve found is this:  people want, sometimes even insist, for you to agree with them and what they think about God/religion.  Divergence of opinion and differing ideas are seen as a threat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t get that.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well said, Chris. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it, either. I think this extends to politics and lifestyle, as well. We all assume that everyone in our group will think of us as being intelligent and on the right path. Anyone who thinks we&amp;rsquo;re not on the right path is obviously a threat to that and must be silenced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want to grow, influence others, and sharpen our thinking we need to grow past this. &lt;strong>Disagreement isn&amp;rsquo;t a threat&lt;/strong>. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">Everyone doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to agree with us&lt;/a>. In fact, if we&amp;rsquo;re truly honest with ourselves, &lt;strong>&lt;em>people who disagree with us are much more effective at changing our perspective when we let them.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> We can never get there if we&amp;rsquo;re not open to the assumption that there are pleasant people with whom we have a lot in common that fundamentally disagree with some of our religious, political, or cultural views.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Litmus Test for Tolerance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-litmus-test-for-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-litmus-test-for-tolerance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-litmus-test-for-tolerance.jpg" alt="Litmus Test" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>About ten years ago, &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">my wife&lt;/a> and I were deeply involved in a church that claimed to be evangelistic and desperately wanted to lead people to God. We devoted ourselves to The Cause and poured hours and hours of our labor into its programs. At one point (I kid you not), I was doing the music on Sunday mornings, keeping track of our procedure for keeping and maintaining new members, leading youth group on Sunday mornings and Wednesday nights, attending another small group Bible study, and taking a graduate level Seminary class. All of this while having a full time job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the problem, looking back on it: I wasn&amp;rsquo;t growing. Why not? I believe a simple litmus test could have exposed it for me very quickly. It&amp;rsquo;s a test I have run through my life quite extensively since this experience:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In the past three months, how many people have been in my home that can and will openly but respectfully disagree with my political, religious, or cultural views?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my overcommitted church days, that was no one outside of my extended family. I was a part of a giant echo chamber. I suppose this is true of a lot of people at church. You hear over and over again in those environments that the key is to be outwardly focused, but then when you actually survey those within the organization itself, &lt;strong>&lt;em>many have absolutely no personal contact with those outside of their political, cultural, and religious beliefs.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So do you think of yourself as someone who is growing and tolerant of others? Test out that thought by inviting someone over who doesn&amp;rsquo;t share your political beliefs, or was born outside of the United States. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, doing so will open up a whole new realm of fulfillment and growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A European Education</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-european-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 22:14:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-european-education/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-european-education.jpg" alt="European Education" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Yesterday I was at lunch with a Czech friend of mine talking about education. His daughter just started the first grade and this week they had their initial teacher conferences. The teacher informed him and his wife that the daughter had a hard time focusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Of course she can&amp;rsquo;t focus; they have her there from 8AM to 3PM. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t focus at that age either!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It never occurred to me that there was anything out of place about the duration of the American elementary public school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I asked him how long school was in the Czech Republic. He said that first graders would be out by 11:30 AM. Wow, what a way to solve the problem of so many kids who are diagnosed with ADHD but may just need to run around and climb a few trees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our exchange student last year brought some perspective as well. She explained that when kids in Czech are in the fourth grade, they separate the &amp;ldquo;academic&amp;rdquo; ones from the non-academic ones. The academic ones are prepared for the university. The non-academic ones are prepared for a vocation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So instead of forcing a bunch of people into a mountain of student loan debt that puts them in a career or job that they don&amp;rsquo;t perform in, we could train them to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> go to college, save a ton of money, get back years of earning instead of going to school, and live much more confident and productive lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of labelling kids as being bad because they can&amp;rsquo;t (unnaturally) sit in a room for seven hours with a few breaks in between, we could limit the amount of time young students spend in school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I absolutely love having friends with different perspectives and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/" title="Life is Art">life experiences&lt;/a>. The American system is not the only good system; it&amp;rsquo;s not even the best in most things. Without my European friends, I would never see that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empathy</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/empathy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 08:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/empathy/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-empathy.jpg" alt="Empathy" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A few months ago we were at my mom&amp;rsquo;s house eating dinner. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know my mom, she&amp;rsquo;s an awesome cook. She had made one of my favorite meals of all time: meatloaf with green beans and mashed potatoes. I was in heaven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh gross,&amp;rdquo; the middle child exclaimed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parental embarrassment ensued, and then we got to talking about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mom talked about how her dad&amp;rsquo;s rule as he was growing up was that no one complains about food. If you do, you&amp;rsquo;re just going to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">have to figure out&lt;/a> a way to make it to the next meal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was my mom&amp;rsquo;s rule growing up. Complain and wait until the next meal to eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And from that day onward that has been our rule. You don&amp;rsquo;t complain about food. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to like it. But be polite and don&amp;rsquo;t whine about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of days ago we sat down to tamales, rice, and corn, and the middle child was being a pickle about the tamales. He stepped over the line and Mom said, &amp;ldquo;You may be excused&amp;rdquo;, which is code for, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not eating until breakfast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He sat there and cried and the look on his face of ‘I will not be eating for another 12 hours and I was already starting to feel hungry&amp;rsquo; was in full force.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I felt truly bad for him. He made a mistake.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that you can&amp;rsquo;t really relate to your children with love until you learn how to truly empathize with their mistakes. A few days ago I had a breakthrough in that. &lt;strong>My middle son needed to learn how to treat others. But he also had to deal with a bad situation.&lt;/strong> Taking away the consequence wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been empathetic: if there&amp;rsquo;s no pain in which to share, then there is no empathy. But also acting coldly towards him with a &amp;ldquo;this is how it is&amp;rdquo; attitude isn&amp;rsquo;t empathetic either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My wife saw that I had felt bad for my son, and she interpreted it as questioning her judgement on the consequence. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t it at all. &lt;strong>Empathy holds this strange place in between allowing consequences and loving others.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Empathy is when you share in someone&amp;rsquo;s suffering. It&amp;rsquo;s something I discovered a few days ago with my son and something that will transform my relationship with all three of them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life is Art</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-life-is-art.jpg" alt="Life is Art" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Earlier this year, I was pretty excited about some &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">drastic changes&lt;/a> we had made in our lifestyle. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m excited about something, I must tell someone and my friend at a dinner party at my house was no exception. I excitedly pointed out all the ways that simplicity has led us to a life of greater contentment and tranquility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could sense my friend becoming increasingly uncomfortable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Well, not everyone can live that way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend assumed that I view life as a science; that there are certain rules that &lt;em>must&lt;/em> be followed and a right and wrong way to do things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I completely disagree with that notion. To me &lt;strong>life is more like a work of art.&lt;/strong> You have a canvas on which to paint decisions, consequences, and ultimately meaning. Every life is as different as every work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a painter presents her painting, she is expressing herself in a unique way that is unlike anyone else. The painter has &lt;em>her&lt;/em> way of painting. To her it &lt;em>feels&lt;/em> like the right way, because, of course, she did it that way. Another painter may do it totally differently. A wonderful and mysterious thing happens in the gallery: &lt;strong>each painter admires the brilliance and beauty in the other&amp;rsquo;s work of art.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I am creating a work of art that I hope to be beautiful and meaningful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the entrepreneur who spends her nights and weekends creating a groundbreaking service that improves the lives of millions of people. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the philanthropist who travels the world to find a way to cure malaria worldwide. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the video game developer who works for two solid years to create a game that captures the imagination of a teenager who stays out of trouble because he has something to do when he&amp;rsquo;s out of school. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of a hospice nurse who works the night shift helping dying patients find dignity and meaning in their final days. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m creating a life of tranquility, meaning, and purpose. I do this through simplifying life in every facet, achieving in the marketplace through a fearless pursuit of adding value, and creating margin in my life to build a legacy with those around me, especially my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my work of art. This is the journey I will share with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It isn&amp;rsquo;t the only way.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I want it to be beautiful, and I want to share it with you because I hope we can inspire each other to make our lives a beautiful work of art.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ten Takeaways from the Last 10 Years at Radiant/NCR</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2014 08:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr.jpg" alt="Ten Takeaways" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Five thousand, four hundred and thirty two dollars and twenty three cents&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yes…&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Five thousand, four hun…&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yes, we will take your home next Tuesday if you don&amp;rsquo;t pay us five thousand, four hundred and thirty-two dollars and twenty three cents.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m…&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry there&amp;rsquo;s nothing else we can do for you&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yes, you will lose your house next Tuesday if you don&amp;rsquo;t pay us fi….&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yes, thank you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was where I had found myself in the spring of 2004. For some reason, I thought it was a great idea to accept a developer position at a Law Firm that specialized in foreclosures. In some cosmic twist, they sat me in the cubicle next to the lady who was delivering the bad news to people. All day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to get out of there. But to where? A recruiter had told me about this place that was a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radiant_Systems">&lt;em>real&lt;/em> software company&lt;/a> that created a POS for restaurants called Aloha. I was done being the IT department. I wanted to be a part of a &lt;em>real&lt;/em> software company. So on July 12, 2004, ten years from tomorrow, I started working at Radiant Systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I arrived ten years ago a mid-level software engineer whose confidence was shaken by all the foreclosures I had to hear about, and a rough few years of post-Y2K job market crappiness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking back, I&amp;rsquo;ve grown so much. Here are ten takeaways from the last ten years at Radiant/NCR:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Speak Up.&lt;/strong> Early on I developed an opinion on what needed to change about my team&amp;rsquo;s situation, and I spoke up and did something about it. This fueled even more change, and gave me a reputation for leadership, which opened up so many opportunities.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Make a List.&lt;/strong> When I started, I worked with a friend that always made lists, and I thought that was strange at first. But then I realized my colleague always got stuff done quicker than me. So I made a list, and got stuff done as well. People aren&amp;rsquo;t organized because they are dorks that like inane details; they&amp;rsquo;re organized because it works.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Do it Right, But Do it Fast.&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve been passionate about doing things well for a long time. But I realized early on that the only way to do this is to get fast at developing software. I needed to take advantage of tools that I had available to me and get smart about getting things done, so I could have time to get it right.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tools Matter.&lt;/strong> I don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a super-genius to be effective. Really I just need to use the right tools, and let my teams and company for that matter use those tools to be more effective. That way I win, everyone wins, and we can be more focused on the problem at hand. That&amp;rsquo;s why I love tools. It&amp;rsquo;s a win for everyone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Don&amp;rsquo;t be Religious about Process.&lt;/strong> Early on I was very religious about being agile, doing test-driven development, whatever. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized over the years that it&amp;rsquo;s much more valuable to use those frameworks as starting points to solve the problem in front of you. If you solve problems, you get things done, and create a profit for your company. It seems so elementary that one should make more money for one&amp;rsquo;s company than they cost, but the honest truth is the degree to which you do that is the degree to which you will have flexibility on everything else: money, what you work on, flexibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Be Patient.&lt;/strong> I can think over the past ten years of so many times where things weren&amp;rsquo;t going well, or where I wanted something to change so badly. Eventually it did. Like I say above, if you create value, that value is rewarded. So focus on the value, not on the drama or the desire to change everything overnight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>You Live with the Past Forever, so get the Present Right.&lt;/strong> I am at a conference in Huntington Beach this week and was at breakfast overhearing two of our users argue about the proper approach to a weakness in a product…that I created seven years ago. It was a strange feeling that I had so much impact on these people so many years later. What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years, is that you have to live with the past for a long time, especially when you move projects and can&amp;rsquo;t influence the product directly, so get it right today because you never know what tomorrow will bring.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Value is Immune to Change.&lt;/strong> In the last ten years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been through the worst recession ever, an acquisition from Radiant to NCR, and numerous other business cycle downturns and upswings. In every one of those, I&amp;rsquo;ve thrived. Why? Because I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on bringing value to my employer beyond what they pay me. If one is valuable, change doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. Even if the company folds, that value can be transferred elsewhere. So I don&amp;rsquo;t worry about change; I worry about value.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Without Sales, Software is Dead.&lt;/strong> There is a sales guy at this conference who is the center of attention. He&amp;rsquo;s laughing, drinking, yucking it up with the customers. And they love it. For years, the software engineer in me despised it. &amp;ldquo;He doesn&amp;rsquo;t know the first thing about software&amp;rdquo; I would tell myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned recently though that without sales and marketing, software is only an idea that dies quickly. Software &lt;em>needs&lt;/em> to be sold, and that usually happens by people who actually had friends in High School. Sales is a valuable aspect of software and must be rewarded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Show Grattitude.&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve had  my share of ups and downs in the past ten years. But when I look back, these ten years have completely changed my life. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have gotten there without John Pearson, Vince Severns, Jeff Hughes, Jimmy Fortuna, and Honza Fedak helping me through, and the numerous team members and other leaders who have believed in me. I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way since I was grimacing next to the lady explaining the foreclosure to the poor soul on the other line. I&amp;rsquo;ve been very open with people about how great this journey has been for me.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Embrace Difficulty</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/embrace-difficulty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 08:12:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/embrace-difficulty/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-embrace-difficulty.jpg" alt="Embrace Difficulty" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It was an impossible project and I was scared. The fact that &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">the world was ending&lt;/a> was the least of my concerns. We have software that is so flexible and configurable that it was impossible to fully test all the combinations of options our customers could run. My leadership at the time asked us to mitigate this by recording everything that happened at a restaurant and playing it back it back internally on prereleased software to make sure everything behaved the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t overstate how I felt: this problem scared the crap out of me. So much could go wrong, and so many issues to figure out. How would I get the software started? How would I know when/if the simulation was running correctly? What about all the other automation projects I had heard about over the years that had been cancelled due to lack of results? Would this project (and my career with it) be the next one thrown on the scrap heap when management realizes how impossible it is?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to step back, step away from my fear, and think of a good strategy. We were facing a difficult problem. The process we would come up with was likely to fail. A lot. Instead of running &lt;em>away&lt;/em> from that failure, we needed to embrace it. We needed to welcome it with open arms. Because &lt;strong>if we didn&amp;rsquo;t face the failure head on, we would never get past it, and we would fail.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we created a system where we ran any automation we had &lt;em>every day&lt;/em>. In fact, this is how we do it today, with over 150 restaurants running in a virtual environment and over 4,000 small scenarios. We do it every night. Do we have to do it every night? Technically no. But we embrace the difficulty of it by doing it every night so we get quick feedback of the problems and keep it on track.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People still argue with me over whether we &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to run this every night. I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that; I know it seems silly at times. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s key to our success: &lt;strong>we embrace the difficulty by doing difficult things all the time, so we can learn how to deal with them and make them not difficult anymore.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are a few other examples of embracing the difficulty in a system:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>When&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Embrace Difficulty By&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Doing Laundry&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Doing it every day&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Budgeting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Starting every month and facing reality&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Blogging&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Keeping a month ahead and posting at a regular pace&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Learning to Cook&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Cooking a regular meal on a day of a week&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Keeping the Family Close&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Eating dinner together every night&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>What have you avoided that you need to embrace in order to overcome it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Failure the Catalyst</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 08:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-failure-the-catalyst.jpg" alt="Failure the Catalyst" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t take credit cards, only cash.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was November 2009, and I was locked into &amp;ldquo;Project: Have a Third Child&amp;rdquo;. Part of the deal I made with my wife is that we could offset some of the hardships of having another child by doing some things for ourselves. This translated partly into changing our half bath into a full bath and completely redoing the furniture and decorating of our master bedroom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As with most home projects, reality quickly surpassed our budget. That was OK. I was going to use my credit card. Nevermind that I promised myself I would never use it in this manner…this totally frivolous remodeling project was an emergency! I would pay it off, I promised. I just needed to get through this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.viperplumbing.com/">My plumber&lt;/a> dug a hole in our foundation, extended the toilet drain to what would be the shower, and charged me a hefty sum to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And he only took cash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As did &lt;a href="http://mastertilesetter.com/">the tile guys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://paulhedgpethpainting.blogspot.com/">the painter&lt;/a>. Crap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The inevitable occurred. I overdrafted our checking account and our finances went into a tailspin that took us a few weeks to get out of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My wife and I awoke to how totally out of control and useless our current financial system had been. Some major changes were on the horizon. But these changes had a beginning in failure. At the time failure seems so terrible, so awful, that nothing good can come out of it. But in reality failure is often a catalyst for change.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>When you fail by&lt;/th>
&lt;th>it is the catalyst for&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>losing your job&lt;/td>
&lt;td>putting yourself on the right path to meet your goals, with the options wide open&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a marital separation or affair&lt;/td>
&lt;td>finding or abandoning your true commitment to that person, which means there will no longer be a lukewarm relationship&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a project failure at work&lt;/td>
&lt;td>understanding what &lt;i>will not &lt;/i>work, so you can pursue what will work either for you or your organization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>gaining weight&lt;/td>
&lt;td>reanalyzing your relationship with food and an active lifestyle and making changes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Failure feels terrible at the moment, but it really is a wonderful blessing because it is the only catalyst I know of for real success. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been able to believe this enough to make failure suck any less, but it sure is nice to know while I&amp;rsquo;m going through it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surprise</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-surprise.jpg" alt="Surprise" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/">the last post&lt;/a> I wrote about a mistake I made where I focused too much on The Grand Vision and not enough on solving small problems. At the time, I felt that accomplishing The Grand Vision was going to be awesome and would save the world, and would mean that there would be a parade for my entire team, and cheering, and wonderful speeches given for us all. It will be glorious, except, now I realize I totally screwed it up:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I left no room for surprise.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Surprise is when someone&amp;rsquo;s expectation is suddenly shifted into a totally new place in an instant. &lt;strong>Surprise has a way of changing the game immediately and causing your competitors to scramble.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When your competition expects an outcome, they have time to spin it as no big deal. Your flaws (and there will be flaws if you ship it) will be the surprises, not the big game-changing outcome that you created. People adjust to the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; reality over a period of months, when in fact the reality hasn&amp;rsquo;t even changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This lesson will be central to everything I do for the rest of my life. If I am trying to create an important outcome that makes a difference, I should focus &lt;em>first&lt;/em> on creating the outcome. &lt;strong>If it is as important as I think it is, surprise will be my ally.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Grand Vision</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 08:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-grand-vision.jpg" alt="The Grand Vision" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Late last year I started a new project that was dedicated to improving our delivery process and tools. I spent a few weeks talking to people throughout our organization about what the problems were and how we can best address them. And then I came up with &lt;strong>The Grand Vision.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grand Vision was an awesome elevator speech where I drew quadrants and arrows, talked about the main problems I was seeing and how to bring them together into one, totally awesome, unified structure that Would Save The World.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the meetings, a key leader I respect said to me, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s ambitious.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thanks,&amp;rdquo; I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a complement&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lesson I learned is that it&amp;rsquo;s important to map out the process and see how what you&amp;rsquo;re doing fits into the entire goal. &lt;em>But it&amp;rsquo;s also important to solve problems immediately that have a quick return on investment.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This kind of thinking happens all the time:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ambitious&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Should be&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get rid of all sugar in my house and go GLUTEN FREE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>On Fridays I eat donuts that people bring in the office. In June I&amp;rsquo;m not going to eat any.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a gym membership with personal training and wake up every day at 5:30AM and get RIPPED!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to bike anywhere within 5 miles of my house and do 20 pushups a night&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>We are going to a full week marriage conference in Aspen, Colorado so we can get our marriage back on track&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Let&amp;rsquo;s go on a date and not look at our phones&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to avoid the really tough problems in front of you by dreaming a big dream.&lt;/strong> I think many of us like to think if we can&amp;rsquo;t do it all, then why do it at all? The real battle is won when we drop that all or nothing thinking and get something done&amp;hellip;&lt;strong>today&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When have you let the grand vision distract you from what really needed to be done right then and there?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christmas with Russians</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-christmas-with-russians" alt="Christmas" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It was Christmas 2008, and the world was going to end. We didn&amp;rsquo;t know if there would be an economy or even civilization. And I had two weeks of vacation to end the year. I had an 18 month old who was mostly occupying himself with Christmas toys, and my wife was two months away from having my second child. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to take the vacation, but the policy at the time was &amp;ldquo;use it or lose it&amp;rdquo;, so I took it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could have done anything with those two weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I chose to set up &lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/articles/continuousIntegration.html">Continous Integration&lt;/a> for one of our largest products through &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/">TeamCity&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was something I was passionate about. I had &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0026772IS/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0026772IS&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=RJ6US3SXFLCWDTR5">read the literature&lt;/a> on how transformative Continuous Integration had been to organizations. This product was built twice a day by a homeade tool called bmcon.exe and some batch files. If the build broke, dozens of people stopped everything to try to get it working, with no clear feedback mechanism for knowing what went wrong, who did it, and whether it was being worked on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was my moral duty to fix this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it so happened that those working on TeamCity were going to take their Christmas holiday&amp;hellip;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas_in_Russia">on January 7&lt;/a>. They were Russian. So I took it upon myself to monitor the email and get the build working over the Christmas holidays. I remember on Christmas day &lt;a href="http://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/TW-6471">I was conversing with&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://de.linkedin.com/in/jonnyzzz">Eugene Pentrenko&lt;/a> across the world about how to deal with the complexities of TFS pulling thousands of files and then building them*.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Years later, almost all of our products build with TeamCity, and we have thousands of integration tests and tens of thousands unit tests that run on our 100+ build agents to make it happen. It is central to everything we do. And it all started one Christmas years ago when I had a &amp;ldquo;moral duty&amp;rdquo; to do something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008KPM424/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B008KPM424&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=52YQPMBZ7Z4IMUKU">Selling with Noble Purpose&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href="http://www.mcleodandmore.com/what-is-selling-with-noble-purpose/">Lisa McLeod&lt;/a> leads the reader through an exercise where the reader thinks about situations where one makes a difference with customers, in a different way than other people, while loving what they are doing. When I went through this exercise I was reminded of this story. Through the exercise I found my noble purpose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I share tools and insight for success&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what truly excites me, and why this blog exists. I want to share the tools and insights I&amp;rsquo;ve found to succeed. I want to help those who have given me tools and insights that have made me more effective by spreading them to others. And I want to properly define success so I can make sure to follow the path that will lead me there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next few posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about key elements of &lt;em>true&lt;/em> success. Success is one of those things that seems easy to see in others, but never seems recognizable in ourselves. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve found a few reasons why this is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>_* You can&amp;rsquo;t see it in the issue I link to above but Eugene was emailing me and went above and beyond, after his normal hours, to resolve the issue._&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>