<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>growth on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/growth/</link><description>Recent content in growth on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Was Told to write this blog post</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/i-was-told/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/i-was-told/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-i-was-told.jpg" alt="I Was Told" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A lot of times in IT I&amp;rsquo;ll hear the phrase, &amp;ldquo;I was told&amp;rdquo;. For example, &amp;ldquo;I was told we are going to use Chef.&amp;rdquo; This is the worst possible phrase you can use. It suffers from two major defects:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First it uses the &lt;em>passive voice&lt;/em>. I think the passive voice is the enemy of productive and clear communication. In this context the passive voice shadows the listener from the person that did the telling and subtly tells you to not question the statement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I was told to use Chef.&amp;rdquo; Who did the telling? Your mom? Your five year old son? Your boss? &lt;em>Their&lt;/em> boss? The teller implies that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter; you should just accept the statement because, &amp;ldquo;I was told&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this isn&amp;rsquo;t the worst part of the statement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I was told&lt;/em> takes the teller completely out of the chain of responsibility for actions and results in their business. If &lt;em>I was told to do Chef&lt;/em> and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t go well, then that&amp;rsquo;s not my fault at all. I can go about my career life with great pride in the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m only doing what I&amp;rsquo;m told and can chalk up failures to &lt;em>management&lt;/em> or &lt;em>the crazy Chef evangelist&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>I was told&lt;/em> needs to die. It&amp;rsquo;s the death knell of a career. It lulls its teller into a rejection of responsibility, and their skills fade away into oblivion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a secret: even though I wrote that on the Internet for the &lt;em>whole world to hear&lt;/em>, you&amp;rsquo;re going to go to work tomorrow and hear &lt;em>I was told&lt;/em>. It will be like the car that you buy and then see it everywhere. Everyone using the passive voice! Obfuscating the actions of others into an unquestionable force that we should all follow!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And as that happens, I have some advice for you. Take charge. See what needs to change and change it. Call out a problem, suggest a solution, and solve it. Don&amp;rsquo;t complain about funding. Don&amp;rsquo;t complain about the other team that is stupid. Don&amp;rsquo;t complain about management and &lt;em>I was told&lt;/em> yourself into oblivion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stand up, take action, make the world a better place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of Context</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/power-of-context/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/power-of-context/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-power-of-context.jpg" alt="Power of Context" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve coached a couple of people lately who have made a career change into technology from other disciplines and have noticed a pattern emerge that I want to share more broadly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People from other disciplines bring diversity to their roles. In this context, we&amp;rsquo;re not talking about their gender or ethnicity. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about their &lt;em>background&lt;/em>. From a purely business perspective, we want higher diversity and inclusion to remove the efficiency barriers that exist from the echo chamber that is generated from only having one group present. If a disproportionate amount of women were in technology, that same echo chamber would exist and we would want to hire more men. Same with all other groups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that in mind, people we hire onto our teams that are in underrerpresented groups or lack the traditional indoctrination of the culture of IT through universities (i.e., are making a career change) have special powers. They can see things the rest of us can&amp;rsquo;t. They work around the echo chamber and can truly be powerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because these people generally lack deep technical skills, they experience immense temptation to get outside of a technical role and into a &amp;ldquo;better fit&amp;rdquo;. After all, if a new DevOps Engineer is growing and only OK at coding Ansible scripts, but is removing barriers left and right on getting a critical project delivered, why not let her focus on the latter?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This would be a huge mistake. Don&amp;rsquo;t do it. Stay technical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the secret: when people have the technical &lt;em>context&lt;/em> within which they can solve human and technical problems together, their value shoots through the roof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you walk away from opportunities to deepen your technical skills in an effort to maximize your value, you&amp;rsquo;re making a huge short-sighted mistake. Without those technical skills, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to as effectively lead in the future. You&amp;rsquo;ll be a &lt;em>passenger&lt;/em> in the software value creation process. Passengers in this process don&amp;rsquo;t get compensation, respect, and rewards equal to the &lt;em>drivers&lt;/em>, or producers (unless they are in sales, which is another kind of producer).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me leave you with an example, used by permission from my wife. I and many people who know her think that Annie will be a high performing IT executive in five years. She&amp;rsquo;s got all the intangibles you need to be a VP Engineering. In order to get there, though, she needs to dive into her Chef projects for her customer, continue to build her technical skills by learning Ruby deeply, and continue to build her technical prowess. Without that, she would probably stall out and lack the direct engagement that is needed for effective executive-level management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a career change or are supporting people who are, don&amp;rsquo;t take the bait of getting a non-technical role early on. Build off of technical proficiency paired with the soft skills. Let them grow together. With that context, you&amp;rsquo;re truly on the path to long-term success.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2017 Year in Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/2017-year-end/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/2017-year-end/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-2017-year-end.jpg" alt="Year End" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>At the start of 2018, &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">Annie&lt;/a> and I feel like we&amp;rsquo;re at the start of a brand new journey. We&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move to Boulder, Colorado in the coming months. Our jobs are going great, so we plan on working remotely with our companies after making the move. We&amp;rsquo;re both very excited about what&amp;rsquo;s in store; every time I go to the mountains I come alive in a way that no other place can match.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before moving onto this next chapter, I wanted to write about some of the great things that have happened in 2017.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the automation front, we&amp;rsquo;ve settled on an automation stack that works for us using Chef, RunDeck, ARM Templates, Hashicorp Vault, Artifactory, and Salt. I abandoned my &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/introducing-cafe/">experimental Cafe project&lt;/a> when I realized Chef was going in another direction. While that was painful to give up, I got to scratch a coding itch and realize that it was really up to me (and not a single vendor) to build the stack that solved our problems. After finalizing this approach to automation, I was able to build alignment with our central IT partners within NCR and make this our reference architecture going forward as we migrate some workloads to the cloud. It&amp;rsquo;s all very exciting and really a culmination of years of work and lots of great partnership with Chef, Inc. especially.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At work in July I took on a new challenge to migrate our critical applications to a new hardware platform that would help us grow our business. It was a unique challenge for me because we wanted to move our critical applications to this platform before our peak season which started mid-November. So much of the second half of the year I became obsessed with delivering this project. It had no &amp;ldquo;devops&amp;rdquo; associated with it, or code, or any of that. However, I loved it. I enjoyed rising to the challenge, bringing a lot of different departments together and delivering the project. Our peak season has been one of the most stable and successful yet for the critical applications we migrated, and that&amp;rsquo;s thanks to our efforts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In August we had a successful DevOps Days in Dallas. I was really proud of two things: first, we put together a leadership summit that attracted forty of Dallas&amp;rsquo; devops-minded IT leaders. I really enjoyed being in that group and thinking about DevOps from a strategic/leadership perspective. I was also proud of how well my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/MeganBohl">Megan Bohl&lt;/a> did as a sponsor liason and that we were able to get her a scholarship to &lt;a href="https://www.techtalentsouth.com/">Tech Talent South&lt;/a>. Stay tuned with Megan; she&amp;rsquo;s going to be a star.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This past year I was also impressed with Annie&amp;rsquo;s growth. She started the year only a few months into the job and very much struggling to put it all together and get herself on billable jobs. It felt at the beginning of the year like she was battling uphill for success in the industry. And along the way there were lots of people (don&amp;rsquo;t worry, we&amp;rsquo;re not mad at you) who suggested that Annie should be in a non-technical role.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of giving up, Annie dug in and studied hard. When the opportunities came, she worked extra and I watched the kids. She got help wherever she could get it. In May she got a particularly challenging make-it-or-break-it project, and her colleague Scott Nowicki spent time after hours walking her through the challenges she was having so she could deliver. That was a huge turning point for her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another huge turning point was when her CEO helped her realize that if she wanted to be technical, she needed to &lt;em>focus&lt;/em> on that and stop speaking, blogging, marketing so much. That was the absolute right advice she needed right then. A lot of people would see her talents and say &amp;ldquo;you should be blogging!&amp;rdquo; but then ignore the technical skills that were growing so rapidly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which reminds me of a third turning point for me personally. At DevOps Days, after our speaker dinner, Adam Jacob and John Willis heard our story and they both remarked at how unusually talented Annie is as a technologist. I must admit I had become blind to that reality because I had spent the last year working with her at the edge of her abilities. But the truth was evident: it&amp;rsquo;s not normal going from nothing to knowing InSpec in two weeks enough to write tutorials on it. It&amp;rsquo;s not normal to accomplish what she has accomplished, because, frankly, she&amp;rsquo;s good at it. She&amp;rsquo;s abnormally good. She has the potential to be a technical game changer for a valuable business. That makes me so glad she&amp;rsquo;s stayed on the path she&amp;rsquo;s on as a technologist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Late in the year Annie started working on a long-term contract with a company to help them with their Chef and Azure workloads. She&amp;rsquo;s integrated InSpec into their workflow and has done so much more than that. She loves finding the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; way that aligns with the business objectives and challenges. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see how much she&amp;rsquo;s able to accomplish there in the coming months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been an amazing journey to see Annie transform like this. Years ago I&amp;rsquo;d come home from work and she would be taking wood from the side of the road and turn it into something beautiful and useful. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see her be able to transform those skills and that work ethic into a fantastic technical engineering position. And this is only the beginning!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next year I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on two things:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First I&amp;rsquo;m going to move to Boulder and find my place in that community. There are a lot of differences between Dallas and Boulder and I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that I can fit in. I&amp;rsquo;m there for more personal reasons: I want to bike everywhere, I want to live in a smaller place, and I want to hike up mountains. I would also love to snow ski for the first time. Moving to Boulder really is a dream come true!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, next year I&amp;rsquo;ll be focusing more on the broader elements of our DevOps transformation journey at NCR. I am looking forward to influencing our growth and transformation beyond just code and automation improvements. I want to dramatically improve what we do and what we can do. I&amp;rsquo;m more excited than ever about the new challenges before me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think there will ever be another 2017 for Annie and me. It was a year of dramatic growth for both of us. We started the year both not quite sure about our futures, but finish off as valuable contributors of our companies and so happy about how we are both growing. My mantra has always been to go for growth first and everything else will follow. That&amp;rsquo;s where I feel we both are at, and I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to see where this takes us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally, thanks to everyone who have supported us along the way. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t have done what we did without you. You know who you are, and believe us, we are so incredibly grateful for your support, friendship, and love.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DevOps Leadership Summit in Dallas</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/devops-leadership-summit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/devops-leadership-summit/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-devops-leadership-summit.jpg" alt="Devops Leadership" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Last year when we organized the first DevOps Days DFW, many attendees told us that they thought the content was fantastic, but that they wished they could have something that they could invite their leadership team to. Since &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/finding-alignment/">alignment&lt;/a> is so critical to changing anything in a large organization, the DevOps Days DFW Organizers agree and are pleased to announce a &lt;strong>DevOps Leadership Summit&lt;/strong> on Monday, August 28, 2017 from 8:00 to 1:30 at the &lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/GSqXneQtXAL2">Capital One Plano Conference Center&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to have &lt;a href="http://nicolefv.com/">Nicole Forsgren&lt;/a> of DORA, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/adamjacob/">Adam Jacob&lt;/a> from Chef Software, and &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/johnwillisatlanta/">John Willis&lt;/a> from Docker join us for the event. We will have a couple of talks, a workshop, and an interactive networking lunch where attendees can interact directly with our speakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attendance to the event is limited to 50 people and is by invitation only through nominations. The ideal attendee is a Director, VP, or C-level executive who is or is interested in facilitating a DevOps transformation in his or her company. To nominate yourself or someone else, let us know how this person fits that criteria via email: &lt;a href="mailto:organizers-dallas-2017@devopsdays.org">organizers-dallas-2017@devopsdays.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cost of the event is covered by a ticket to DevOps Days DFW 2017, which can be purchased &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/devopsdays-dfw-2017-tickets-33482024637">here&lt;/a>. We don&amp;rsquo;t expect everyone attending the Leadership event to attend the entire DevOps Days. In fact, it would be just fine if they came to the keynotes in the morning and that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you know anyone who would benefit from coming to our Leadership Summit, please let us know!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Which Line?</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/which-line/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/which-line/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-which-line.jpg" alt="Which Line" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I started my career as a developer at a worker&amp;rsquo;s compensation case management company. We wrote software that nurses, who were employees, used to manage worker&amp;rsquo;s compensation cases in hopes that we would get people back to work quicker and thus lower costs. I had a talented and opinionated boss who gave me a lot of room to learn and grow. It was a great first job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a couple of years, however, it became clear that the software I was working on wasn&amp;rsquo;t seen as increasing the revenue of the company but decreasing its costs. Within this business model, the key &lt;em>operational&lt;/em> revenue was coming from the nurses who were managing the cases. I was making the nurses more efficient, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>directly&lt;/em> contributing to revenue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In business terms, I was not contributing to the &lt;em>top line&lt;/em>, I was contributing to the &lt;em>bottom line&lt;/em>. For those of us who don&amp;rsquo;t handle P&amp;amp;L every day, here&amp;rsquo;s what that means:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>Insurance Companies pay for Case Management (Revenue) - TOP LINE
SUBTRACT Cost of Nurses to Manage Cases (Cost)
MY SOFTWARE Lowers the Amount of Nurses We need (Lower Cost)
Company Investors get money left over (Profit) - BOTTOM LINE
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>So in this job, I was contributing to the bottom line by lowering the cost of operating the business. This is wonderful, but I quickly realized the downsides to this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>There is a ceiling to the financial impact I can have to the company&lt;/strong>. Within this model, I can only add value to the level that the operations cost. And the further down the road I get, the less efficiency I can extract out of this system. For example, if in the first year it costs $5M to run this group and I make software changes that mean we only need to spend $4M on nurses, I made a great impact. But in the next year, I&amp;rsquo;ll need to&amp;hellip;reduce costs by another $1M? At some point the efficiency runs against the core business model.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>The rewards are going to the top line&lt;/strong>. Who are the people getting the large bonuses and promotions? The people who are closest to the top line revenue. That is an unfair fact of business but a very real one. So I saw myself with fewer options than my peers within other business models. I&amp;rsquo;ve often wondered why this is, and the closest I can get to is the previous reason: if you have a rockstar sales person, they could &lt;strong>create&lt;/strong> millions of dollars of revenue for the company by creating a new deal. For those dealing with the bottom line, the upside is limited to costs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I quickly came the conclusion that I wanted to work at a software company and got a job at Radiant Systems (which later was aquired by NCR). At NCR there is a different equation:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>Restaurants pay for MY SOFTWARE (Revenue) - TOP LINE
SUBTRACT cost of support, services, operations
Company investors get money left over (Profit) - BOTTOM LINE
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Within this model, my software is what the company is selling. This changes everything. The upside to my work is unlimited. If I work with sales to get a feature in the software, that could move the needle tremendously for the company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For years I enjoyed the career benefits to being aligned with revenue at a business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then I moved to a DevOps role.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A strange thing happened at that point. In people&amp;rsquo;s minds, I was &lt;em>moved&lt;/em> into the cost side of the business. Therefore, I was making the cost of the business more efficient but also was missing out on the upside. In the revenue-aligned positions that I enjoyed in the past, I was rewarded for innovation because that meant there would be upside. But in the operations world, I fought a perception that innovation would disrupt the efficiencies already gained and take us (and our careers) backwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my mind, DevOps is the biggest revenue driver opportunity that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. If we can find a way to ship ideas and features more quickly, then by definition our revenue will increase. It&amp;rsquo;s a force multiplier for development. However, I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that most businesses out there will not see it this way. Most businesses see DevOps through an efficiency lens, because efficiency is all IT Operations has been about since it began.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last night a friend of mine was talking about this with me, and he said that he worked a DevOps job for six months writing Chef scripts, getting paid well, for an application with few to no users. He ended up having very little financial impact on that company. Then he pivoted to a development role where he increased his company&amp;rsquo;s revenue by 1/3 in a year. In the latter role, he used DevOps principles to create a CD pipeline, etc., but he also developed the capability to fundamentally change his business. What an exciting story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s interesting to consider though: let&amp;rsquo;s say I split my friend up into the rockstar Developer and rockstar DevOps person. They work together to create this same outcome. At the end of the day, who will the company reward and nurture more? I&amp;rsquo;m thinking the Developer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, then those of us headed down the pure DevOps path might want to consider the limitations we are imposing on ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would love to hear your thoughts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Funnel</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/funnel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/funnel/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-funnel.jpg" alt="Funnel" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Years back when &lt;a href="https://www.ncr.com/news/newsroom/news-releases/hospitality/ncr-completes-acquisition-of-radiant-systems">NCR bought Radiant Systems&lt;/a>, there was a lot of talk about a new term I hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard until then: &lt;strong>the funnel&lt;/strong>. It took me a few years to understand this concept and how it relates technology change initiatives but NCR&amp;rsquo;s rich history as an effective sales organization was instrumental in gaining that understanding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over a century ago, NCR established itself as a pioneer in defining a sales process for how its products are bought. It had a revolutionary new technology, the cash register, that would massively change businesses who adopted it. At the same time, there were a lot of prospective customers who didn&amp;rsquo;t know how the new technology related to &lt;em>their&lt;/em> needs. NCR created a sales process that brought people into a set of stages that led them to the sale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fast forward to today and it is clear that the commitment to excellence in defining the sales process is alive and well at NCR. I was having lunch with the VP of Hosted Solutions on the sales side a few months back (thanks to Adam Jacob &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/_DEToXsgrPc?t=2041">imploring me to having lunch with my sales people&lt;/a>). My sales friend brought me through the sales process and how it rolls up all the way to the highest levels of leadership at NCR. On that day I got a new appreciation for how results-oriented and well designed our a sales organization is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the next few months, I began thinking about how all of what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about sales at NCR has related to what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do. The truth is, if I&amp;rsquo;m really trying to be a change agent in my organization, I&amp;rsquo;m not that far off from those sales people in the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s who were trying to bring the cash register to small retailers. There are a few people who are excited and adopting, a few people who are outright hostile, and a lot in the middle who can and will be persuaded when the time is right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where the funnel concept in sales is important and helpful. In a sales funnel, you have stages of the funnel that demand more and more buy-in and resources from potential customers until they are to the point where they are a paying customer. Whenever I map out a change initiative, I think about the funnel, what the stages are, and which people are in which stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the very center of the funnel is the people who are committed to the change initiative and getting solid and visible benefits from the change. At first there is no one in this place, but you want to see who &lt;em>might&lt;/em> be in there in a few months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A little bit out, you have people who are excited, see the benefits of the change, but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet gotten to the place where those benefits can be shown to outweigh the costs. This is a difficult place to be because you&amp;rsquo;re asking these people to spend resources toward an end that is not at all guaranteed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people in this phase will be different depending on the lifecycle of the initiative. At first, you&amp;rsquo;ll have forward-thinking people who have a highly critical business problem to solve. Toward the end of the change&amp;rsquo;s lifecycle you&amp;rsquo;ll have people who would not have been involved unless there was a long track record of success that they could draw from. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to not judge the people in the latter camp, but to empathize with their needs that stem out of their own unique market forces and commitments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A bit further out, there is the part of the funnel where people are curious and happy about the change, but they aren&amp;rsquo;t ready to make the commitment needed for it to be successful. These people are kind of dangerous, because if you spend all your time trying to &amp;ldquo;make&amp;rdquo; people who are interested but can&amp;rsquo;t commit to something, then you&amp;rsquo;ll end up killing your change initiative because you don&amp;rsquo;t have any results. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>absolutely imperative&lt;/em> that before you really engage people with what you&amp;rsquo;re doing you first ensure that they are willing and able to make the investment needed to get to the finish line. Lots of people &lt;em>want&lt;/em> the change but aren&amp;rsquo;t able (for whatever reason) to make it happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then there is the group that is difficult to even put in the funnel: those people who are in some way hostile to what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to accomplish. These people are sometimes difficult to spot. A lot of times they&amp;rsquo;ll show up and say something like &amp;ldquo;My boss thinks that your initiative is really cool and she wants me to check it out.&amp;rdquo; That could translate into a number of things. For one, the boss could have wanted a promotion but then was blindsided by this &amp;ldquo;other team&amp;rdquo; that is doing great things and stealing the attention from the results she feels like merits a promotion. So she is sending a detractor into the mix to build a case that maybe the change initiative isn&amp;rsquo;t as great as we think it is. That happens. That&amp;rsquo;s politics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key thing to remember with the final group in the funnel is to not focus your resources on them. That&amp;rsquo;s difficult to do, especially because you don&amp;rsquo;t want to alienate anyone and you want to try to help people make the changes that they need to make. In reality, maybe &amp;ldquo;my boss said&amp;rdquo; person is your next champion of your change initiative. Who knows? Usually with these people I create a small experiment to me see what they&amp;rsquo;re really seeing. It could be as simple as &amp;ldquo;why don&amp;rsquo;t you install ChefDK&amp;rdquo; or as complicated as &amp;ldquo;let&amp;rsquo;s do a POC on your product&amp;rdquo;. Whatever it is, it should be small enough to not distract me from other more important groups of people further into the funnel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to see how the funnel concept can help you map out how you do a change initiative in an organization. I use it on every change initiative I take on as a guide to (1) knowing how to allocate my limited resources and (2) how to strategically move people through a process to where they adopt and embrace change.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Margin for Leadership</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/margin-for-leadership/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/margin-for-leadership/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-margin-for-leadership.jpg" alt="Margin for Leadership" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>There was a phase in early 2014 where I had a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of new initiatives going. In retrospect, I was smack dab in the middle of a horrible career calculation. I had gotten excited about DevOps, told my management about it, and found myself on a project to get all of our development teams &lt;em>operating&lt;/em> on the same development tools. Needless to say I was in a lot of meetings with people who were looking at me angrily as a complete waste of their time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was during this time that I really dropped the ball on mentoring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would be in meetings all day, and the poor members of my team would need my help in growing and learning and I would be absent. They would try to catch me as I walked very briefly to my desk before going to the next meeting. It was really bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized a valuable lesson during that season. If you&amp;rsquo;re in meetings all day and don&amp;rsquo;t have time for people around you, then you and others around you are going to stagnate. That may be fine for people at a certain level, but for most of us that is &lt;strong>a very bad thing&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to create margin in my day so I can check in with people. I keep my calendar blocked during a portion of the day and I &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/planning-vs-execution">focus on planning&lt;/a> and also on &lt;em>talking to people&lt;/em>. I reach out to them, make sure that we have an &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/exposing-the-unknown/">open line of communication&lt;/a> and that they have a &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/internalizing-the-plan/">solid plan themselves&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re wanting to mentor people, put room in your day for it. You &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to create margin in your position for leadership. Your work isn&amp;rsquo;t all about what you &lt;em>do&lt;/em> yourself today, it&amp;rsquo;s more about doing the smart things and enabling those around you to do the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Goal</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-goal/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-goal/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-goal.jpg" alt="The Goal" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A while back I was working with someone who wasn&amp;rsquo;t new to technology, but was new to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/category/process/">the style of software development&lt;/a> that my team was operating within. We worked on &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/exposing-the-unknown/">getting honest about where he was at&lt;/a> over the first few weeks of working together. I could tell this was uncomfortable for him, and, frankly since then I&amp;rsquo;ve also grown in my empathy for the fear and difficulty experienced by being new with a new technology or process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I remember clearly talking to my colleague in a 1:1 that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t where he needed to be to be successful. He knew it. I knew it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s usually a bad place. That&amp;rsquo;s usually the place where people give up on each other. That&amp;rsquo;s the place where both parties start making plans to get themselves out of the uncomfortable situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of doing that, though, we talked about his goals. What did he want to get out of this job? Out of his life? What is he missing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we aligned his goals with mine by creating a growth plan that identified some training opportunities, coding challenges, and regular communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years later and my colleague is doing well. He made the transition. I see so many managers take the easy way out by their inability to see what&amp;rsquo;s possible in people. If you had a chance to change someone&amp;rsquo;s life by helping them gain valuable skills and insights that will serve them the rest of their lives, why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you take it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watching lives change through clear goals has been one of the most rewarding aspects of my career.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Planning vs. Execution</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/planning-vs-execution/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/planning-vs-execution/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-planning-vs-execution.jpg" alt="Planning vs Execution" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When you&amp;rsquo;re new at something, you&amp;rsquo;re excited and want to prove yourself, and you want to get to that &amp;ldquo;proving&amp;rdquo; of yourself as quickly as possible. There is a lot of tension in your life through feeling &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; at that thing, and that tension is uncomfortable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other day &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">Annie&lt;/a> and I were talking about something she was working on. We were breaking the problem down into &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/exposing-the-unknown/">steps that she understood&lt;/a> and she was beginning to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/internalizing-the-plan/">internalize the plan&lt;/a>. She was eager to put the plan into action and getting excited about the newfound insights she had gained from our discussion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then she made a tactical mistake: she got so excited about the plan, that she started working on that plan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds great, and it is great in principle, but the problem with her approach to &lt;em>just get started with it&lt;/em> was that we really weren&amp;rsquo;t done planning out the whole of what she was working on to accomplish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This mistake is similar to what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen over and over with newer people in technology. Early on in my career I worked with a friend of mine that always wrote everything down. I would kind of make fun of him&amp;hellip;but then realized that his organization and plan meant that he executed at a level that I didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I started writing things down. I started making a plan. And I started really focusing on the &lt;em>planning phase&lt;/em> of my work. I was also able to separate the &lt;em>planning phase&lt;/em> from the &lt;em>execution phase&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you&amp;rsquo;re executing on a great plan, it&amp;rsquo;s like the wind is at your back and everything is easy. When you&amp;rsquo;re working without a good plan, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re new to something, you get onto an emotional rollercoaster of unclear expectations. The key to growth is making &lt;em>finding the plan&lt;/em> just as important as &lt;em>executing on the plan&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internalizing the Plan</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/internalizing-the-plan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/internalizing-the-plan/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-internalizing-the-plan.jpg" alt="Internalizing the Plan" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As I wrote about in &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/exposing-the-unknown/">my last post&lt;/a> it&amp;rsquo;s extremely important when working with someone new to technology to create an honest and open relationship with them where they feel free and even supported to tell you that they don&amp;rsquo;t know something. I really love it when I try my best to explain something and the person I&amp;rsquo;m working with is free enough to tell me that they don&amp;rsquo;t have a clue what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. A part of me comes alive whenever that happens because I know that honesty is the basis for growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s easy in a technical context to focus on the technical journey that someone needs to make in order to be effective. Do they know proper source control, how to interact with a good coding editor in an efficient way, a great coding editor, and how to write tests? These are all important topics and ones that &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">Annie&lt;/a> and I covered extensively in the early days of her journey into technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the easy part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the hard part: are they able to create a plan and internalize it? I think that&amp;rsquo;s the true test to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re on the right path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s always horrible when I go over a plan with someone and they look at me enthusiastically, nodding, then at the end they can&amp;rsquo;t articulate the plan to get there. If that happens, then &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/exposing-the-unknown/">we have to work a bit more on honestly&lt;/a>. What I work on early on in any mentoring relationship is that we have an honest conversation back and forth about where we are and where we are going, and break things down &lt;em>at the level that the person understands&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes this means we create a list of things to do &lt;em>in the next few hours&lt;/em> that covers exact files to change and relate them to a diagram on the whiteboard we just drew. That&amp;rsquo;s fine with me as long as (1) they know what they need to do, for real, and aren&amp;rsquo;t faking it, and (2) they can internalize it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can&amp;rsquo;t internalize a plan enough to tell someone about it, you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. No amount of googling is going to change that. You &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to plan ahead, and at a level that &lt;em>you&lt;/em> understand. Never let a mentor plan &lt;em>above&lt;/em> your understanding, and, if you&amp;rsquo;re mentoring someone, seek to find out where they are and ensure there is a solid plan &lt;em>at that level&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exposing the Unknown</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/exposing-the-unknown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/exposing-the-unknown/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-exposing-the-unknown.jpg" alt="Exposing the Unknown" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When someone starts on my team, regardless of their experience level but &lt;em>especially&lt;/em> if they&amp;rsquo;re new to technology, my first goal is to ensure that we are honest in our communication with each other. This is easier said than done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From their perspective, you just gave them this job and they now have to prove things to you. If they don&amp;rsquo;t understand what you&amp;rsquo;re saying but think they might be able to google it later, what&amp;rsquo;s the benefit in getting you to explain it to them? It&amp;rsquo;s much safer to just try to figure it out and to bend the truth a little bit on whether they are understanding what you&amp;rsquo;re saying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, if you&amp;rsquo;re the senior person who has a handle on this project, to the new person you &lt;em>feel&lt;/em> like a magical wizard who is casting spells. Especially if they&amp;rsquo;re new, they haven&amp;rsquo;t wrapped their minds around what you work on every day, and so the effortlessness by which you solve problems to them is &lt;em>extremely intimidating&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We humans are hardwired to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> be vulnerable when in extremely frightening and scary situations. We&amp;rsquo;re hardwired to hide and let the danger pass. So it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that lack of honesty is a major initial issue to deal with when working with people who are just getting started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how I solve it: whenever I start working with someone who is very junior, the first thing I do is find something that I &lt;em>know&lt;/em> they don&amp;rsquo;t know. Then we talk through it and I do the best job I know how of explaining that thing, all the while knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s probably not sufficient for them to get it because I can&amp;rsquo;t read their mind. Then I ask them if they get it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They will almost always say, &amp;ldquo;Yeah that makes sense.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is when I know we have a great opportunity to establish a solid working relationship, because I know that they don&amp;rsquo;t get it but they are telling me they do. So then I say, &amp;ldquo;Great, then please explain it to me.&amp;rdquo; And usually they can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, I communicate to them that &lt;strong>I don&amp;rsquo;t expect them to know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, even after I explain it to them. Instead, I expect two things from them: (1) that they honestly tell me when they don&amp;rsquo;t know and (2) that they ask questions that will help them understand.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So our relationship of learning is based on trust now: I trust that they&amp;rsquo;ll be honest and engage with me, and they trust me that I will accept them for not knowing, or even forgetting something I&amp;rsquo;ve told them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had so much success with helping people grow when I&amp;rsquo;ve established this level of trust early on. Instead of months of frustration while they go through the wildnerness of confusion and dealing with impostor syndrome, we can get to the bottom of what we need to do and make a plan for getting better. It&amp;rsquo;s so rewarding to see people light up when you say to them, &amp;ldquo;I know that you&amp;rsquo;re not where you want to be; here&amp;rsquo;s a timeline of how to get you there.&amp;rdquo; We&amp;rsquo;re working on real problems now and not using fear to hide!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I encourage you, if you&amp;rsquo;re working with someone junior to you on your team, have some compassion, understand the fear that is involved, and work hard to create an honest and supportive relationship with them. It will pay dividends for months and years to come.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summer of Discovery</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/summer-of-discovery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/summer-of-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-summer-of-discovery.jpg" alt="Summer of Discovery" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been hiding out a bit this summer, but hopefully you trust me enough to know that I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to a lot. Earlier this year, &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">my wife&lt;/a> decided it was time to go back to work after a decade out of the full time workforce. She considered a lot of different options, but after a few initial experiments we quickly realized that she would be a great fit in technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling her almost since I met her how great technology is and how much we need people like her in it. She would always tell me the reasons why she didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do it, like that she wanted to be more creative or that it sounded boring. It always frustrated me because I knew from my own experience that working in technology is one of the most creative and interesting jobs I know of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So Annie &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com/introduction">decided to give it a shot&lt;/a> after a great dinner with some colleagues of mine at &lt;a href="http://www.ncr.com">NCR&lt;/a> and some good friends at &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/category/chef">Chef&lt;/a>. From there, I devoted almost all of my free time to helping her map out the path to take from her art/film background to a full-time technology job. That path included taking advantage of her strengths: &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">blogging&lt;/a>, networking, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U7i4JE4Zk7w">connecting with people&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com/elasticsearch-network-hosts">getting obsessed about solving problems&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also included a lot of growing pains. Some of our experiments failed. In June we were convinced that it would be great to learn Ruby enough to write custom InSpec resources, but that proved to be too difficult to accomplish at the time. We had to keep thinking about what was working, what wasn&amp;rsquo;t, and adjusting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have found the process to be incredibly fascinating and rewarding. For a long time, I have been frustrated by the lack of diversity in technology. How are we going to get past this? Are we going to wait twenty to thirty years for higher education to figure it out?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I believe there is a huge transfer of wealth and power to those who can harness technology. Are we going to allow that transfer to unequally go to white men who for their whole lives were &lt;em>always&lt;/em> told that they naturally fit into technology? Or are we going to break through the misconceptions and outright falsehoods that permeate our industry and help people take advantage of this fantastically liberating industry?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annie is on her way to a great career; I can already see it. Stay tuned &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">on her blog&lt;/a> with what her next gig will be&amp;hellip;you&amp;rsquo;ll hear about it soon. Going forward, I want to write a few posts about some things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years and with Annie on how to work with people who are new to technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve realized through this experience that it isn&amp;rsquo;t intuitive for people. If we&amp;rsquo;re really going to have positive change in including everyone in this fantastic shift in our economy, we are going to have to get &lt;em>way better&lt;/em> at helping new people quickly become productive and valuable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coding for Kids</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/coding-for-kids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 08:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/coding-for-kids/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-coding-for-kids.jpg" alt="Coding for Kids" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As a part of the &lt;a href="http://hourofcode.com/us">hour of code&lt;/a> initiative, I was pleased to present my perspective on computer programming to first and third graders at &lt;a href="http://www.gcisd-k12.org/Domain/1675">Grapevine Elementary School&lt;/a> in December. Through the presentation I was able to inspire the students to see programming in their future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been frustrated over the years with how little people know about programming. When I ask an eight year old what they want to do when they grow up, you get a lot of firemen, police officers, teachers, and professional athletes. When children of today grow up they will more likely work closely with computers, regardless of their profession. No one will be exempt. So it&amp;rsquo;s important for them to view programming as a tool, like math, reading, or writing, that is to be used to create value for others.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en">
&lt;p>
Mr. Hedgpeth sharing with our 1st graders about coding for Computer Science Week. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/GESshineon?src=hash">#GESshineon&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/hourofcode?src=hash">#hourofcode&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://t.co/pfb3JGKjPg">pic.twitter.com/pfb3JGKjPg&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
— Grapevine Elementary (@GESStars) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GESStars/status/544871858835697664">December 16, 2014&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I talked about the people who made this toy, the producers, and the people who bought it, the consumers. When they grow up and produce, they&amp;rsquo;ll produce solutions that use computers in awesome ways. We call that programming. They&amp;rsquo;ll call it normal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ended the presentation with some myths related to programming:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Myth&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Reality&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>It&amp;rsquo;s only for video games&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Programming is for solving problems. Problems are everywhere, not just in video games&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>It&amp;rsquo;s only for adults&lt;/td>
&lt;td>My son learning &lt;a href="https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby&lt;/a> through &lt;a href="http://www.codecademy.com/">Codecademy&lt;/a> and using &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/ruby/">RubyMine&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>It&amp;rsquo;s too complicated&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Actually trying to solve a complicated problem &lt;em>without&lt;/em> the help of a computer is complicated. Illiterate people think that reading is complicated. This is just another form of literacy.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Computers will take over the world and we won&amp;rsquo;t need humans anymore&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Computers do one thing well: do what they&amp;rsquo;re told. You can&amp;rsquo;t reduce love, empathy, and character to a set of instructions. Being able to work with other people is essential to one&amp;rsquo;s development and ultimate economic value to the world.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>My son and I are working through his math homework using Ruby right now. If that goes well I might post a few YouTube videos explaining it. I think there is a large, untapped group of people who would really be interested in finding programming literacy from a young age.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to think Mrs. Cox&amp;rsquo;s fourth grade class for the encouraging thank-you notes on the presentation. You guys don&amp;rsquo;t know how much those meant to me. I also want to thank &lt;a href="http://www.gcisd-k12.org/Domain/2938">Nancy Hale&lt;/a> for setting it up and encouraging kids to learn coding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Look Around</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-look-around/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 11:39:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-look-around/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-look-around.jpg" alt="Look Around" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been about six months since &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">I started this blog&lt;/a> and I thought it&amp;rsquo;s time for a retrospective. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoye talking about issues and ideas that have really helped me find new insight and motivation for where I&amp;rsquo;d like to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed, I have had a bit of a content categorization problem that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally found the answer to. Let me explain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The motivation of starting my blog was pretty clear to me from the beginning:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://michaelhyatt.com/">Michael Hyatt&lt;/a> convinced me in &lt;a href="http://michaelhyatt.com/093-10-reasons-every-leader-needs-a-blog-podcast.html">a podcast&lt;/a> that by not having a platform for my ideas I was not going to be an effective influencer. The path to scaling influence is through creating a platform. The easiest way to begin building a platform is through a blog&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I wanted to find a way to find like-minded people who could influence me, and who I could influence&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I wanted to solidify a lot of what I was learning by writing about it and explaining it&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I started out early by writing about a lot of professional topics, then some financial management topics. I saw very quickly that it would not be easy to build a professional oriented platform; the interest wasn&amp;rsquo;t there. The interest appeared to be there for the more personal oriented topics, so I went in that direction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve written more and more about the ideas and experiences that I have found useful to accomplish my goals, and my readership has gone down and down. For example in July the readership numbers spiked at 50 or so sessions per day. At the moment the spike is more like 20 per day when I publish something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/post-assets/2014-12-08-a-look-around/site-metrics.png" alt="Site Metrics">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not bad that 20 or so people are reading the blog, but the problem is that a good portion of that are my extended family that I could easily (and more persuasively) share a personal conversation. So it&amp;rsquo;s clear right now that I need a change in strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I continue to work on deployment both for our hosted and our store products at my company. I&amp;rsquo;m learning a lot of lessons, both through management and through learning new products. In fact I&amp;rsquo;ve spent more time learning in the past eight weeks than I had in the past three years combined. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about where these ideas will take us, and want to share it with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re one of my readers who won&amp;rsquo;t care about that topic, I want to tell you two things. First, thanks for reading and for sticking with me. Second, I&amp;rsquo;d love to have lunch with you and talk about these topics further. I have a passion for living life well and think that in order to do that one must get off of the normal path set by us by our culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For everyone else, welcome to the new hedge-ops, which asks the question: &lt;strong>how can we operate most efficiently with management in technology&lt;/strong>. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to writing about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mornings</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/mornings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/mornings/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-mornings.jpg" alt="Mornings" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>On the bad mornings, I begin by rolling over and checking my phone. I cycle through &lt;a href="http://www.espndallas.com">ESPN Dallas&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.wfaa.com">WFAA&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com">CNN&lt;/a>, and look at my &lt;a href="http://feedly.com/">feedly feed&lt;/a>, personal and work email. The work email in particular, since I work with Czechs who are well into their day, causes me to start thinking about work. My mind races to the world&amp;rsquo;s problems, the world&amp;rsquo;s drama, and problems I&amp;rsquo;ll need to solve in a couple of hours that began a half a world away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thirty minutes later I get out of bed, make a breakfast, talk to my kids, and then I am late for work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the good mornings, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/">my phone is in another room&lt;/a>. I wake up, do a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shovelglove">14 minute workout&lt;/a>, read a little on the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/">Kindle&lt;/a> or the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/">Economist&lt;/a>, have some time for meditation/introspection. I think about my life as a whole and how I&amp;rsquo;m contributing to my goals today in realistic ways. I think about how I want to love and serve others in very real and tangible ways. I eat breakfast, and get to work on time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have as much time on the good mornings as the bad mornings. The key is being intentional and staying off the phone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Test of Tolerance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance.jpg" alt="Tolerance" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I am fortunate to be married &lt;a href="http://reclaimed.house">to someone&lt;/a> who shares many of &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">my values and passions&lt;/a>. For the things we disagree with, though, I have to find a way &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">to not control her&lt;/a> and to let her be her own person. This is the ultimate expression of tolerance: she is welcome in my personal space, influences my future, and is free to &amp;ldquo;ruin&amp;rdquo; it with her own dreams and values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key to making it work is giving her freedom and working hard to connect so values and goals can be shared as much as possible. It won&amp;rsquo;t always work, but if it does, then it is the start of a lifestyle of this, which opens up so many wonderful relationships in all areas of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We like to think of tolerance as something that happens with people who are drastically different than us. With people from other political parties, religions, or backgrounds. I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years that tolerance really begins with those who are closest to me: &lt;strong>do I try to control them or do I let them freely be themselves?&lt;/strong> That&amp;rsquo;s ultimately the question that is asked of all of our relationships. The less we control, the better the relationships are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Right Fit</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/right-fit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/right-fit/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-right-fit.jpg" alt="Right Fit" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">My wife&lt;/a> and I spent the early part of this week looking into a business opportunity that would help us meet some specific goals over the next few years. We were excited, talking late into the night about the various details of this business opportunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then halfway into our trip we realized &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/">it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to work&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, we could have made it work. We could have brought more into the deal and thus introduced more risk. We could have compromised our values or our goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was reminded me of &lt;a href="http://blogmaverick.com/2010/08/25/the-best-investment-advice-you-will-ever-get/">Mark Cuban&amp;rsquo;s advice&lt;/a>: get out of debt and save up 100K in cash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why does he give this advice? Because if you have cash that you can invest, a right fit will come along and present itself. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go try to make things work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have to force anything. I can stay true to my values. And I should continue to live a simple and frugal lifestyle. If I do this, the right fit will come along.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assumption of Agreement</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/assumption-of-agreement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/assumption-of-agreement/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-assumption-of-agreement.jpg" alt="Assumption of Agreement" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We were having a great time with our new friends from California on a gogi-berry farm in New Mexico. The family loves nature like us, and we had great conversations about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/">biking&lt;/a>, hiking, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">living simply&lt;/a>, and cooking naturally. At one point the lady told us that they would love to have us back next summer and that they were pleasantly surprised to find out that there were liberals from Dallas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was eating dinner at my church on a Wednesday night with other members, and one member starts talking about how evil Wendy Davis is and how Obama has ruined everything. I sat there quietly as the whole table seemed to being railing on how dumb the Democrats were and how the world was going to end because of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s the common thread? It&amp;rsquo;s what I call the&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.chrisdikes.com/2013/05/30/the-ever-changing-idea-of-god/">Chris Dikes Assumption of Agreement Hypothesis&lt;/a>. From his post:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One common thread I&amp;rsquo;ve found is this:  people want, sometimes even insist, for you to agree with them and what they think about God/religion.  Divergence of opinion and differing ideas are seen as a threat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t get that.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well said, Chris. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it, either. I think this extends to politics and lifestyle, as well. We all assume that everyone in our group will think of us as being intelligent and on the right path. Anyone who thinks we&amp;rsquo;re not on the right path is obviously a threat to that and must be silenced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want to grow, influence others, and sharpen our thinking we need to grow past this. &lt;strong>Disagreement isn&amp;rsquo;t a threat&lt;/strong>. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">Everyone doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to agree with us&lt;/a>. In fact, if we&amp;rsquo;re truly honest with ourselves, &lt;strong>&lt;em>people who disagree with us are much more effective at changing our perspective when we let them.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> We can never get there if we&amp;rsquo;re not open to the assumption that there are pleasant people with whom we have a lot in common that fundamentally disagree with some of our religious, political, or cultural views.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Proper Understanding of the Opposition</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-proper-understanding-of-the-opposition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-proper-understanding-of-the-opposition/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-proper-understanding-of-the-opposition.jpg" alt="Opposition" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun exercise: first read the first five headlines on &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/">DailyKOS&lt;/a>. Next read the first five headlines on &lt;a href="http://www.lucianne.com/">Lucianne&lt;/a>. See any patterns?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On DailyKOS&lt;/strong> you get the feeling that Republicans are heartless idiots with half a brain, and that our world&amp;rsquo;s problems would be solved if they would just get out of the way of progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On Lucianne,&lt;/strong> you get the feeling that Democrats are heartless idiots with half a brain and that our world&amp;rsquo;s problems would be solved if they would just get out of the way of progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re the typical American, you probably relate to one site and not to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve only recently recognized how destructive this is to my life, my thinking, and my relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to pursue &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">a life of meaning and purpose&lt;/a>, I need to be constantly open to the reality that &lt;strong>&lt;em>I don&amp;rsquo;t have all the answers&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> and pursue growth in all areas. If I&amp;rsquo;m doing this right this means that I will learn from people with drastically different perspectives than me. If I was only a part of the American Political echo chamber on either side, I would in effect cut myself off of half of the country&amp;rsquo;s ideas and thoughts. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a recipe for growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to deepen my ability to think about tough, difficult issues the world faces, I need to be constantly open to the reality that &lt;em>&lt;strong>tough issues cannot be reduced to simple soundbite answers those from the media on both sides provide.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> If I go through life just listening to one side and thinking that if the other side would just grow half a brain we&amp;rsquo;d all move past these elementary problems, I end up being mentally lazy. And I don&amp;rsquo;t grow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to have people in my life that I can influence, I need to constantly be open to the reality that &lt;em>&lt;strong>I can never influence people who totally agree with me.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> That&amp;rsquo;s an impossibility built on a perfectionistic lie that the only think keeping people from succeeding is their idiotic ideas that you have obviously moved passed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you&amp;rsquo;re a Republican and meet a Democrat and think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;What a tool of the liberal media elite&amp;rdquo;, you&amp;rsquo;re killing the relationship right then and there. You may still spend time with this person and some of it may be enjoyable. But if you think that someone in terms of a tool and not a thinking breathing person, they will notice this and they will not listen to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growth in meaning, thinking, and relationships begin with accepting that you don&amp;rsquo;t know everything and thus could be wrong. It then follows that you accept all types of people in your life to sharpen and grow your perspective. Following this path is much more rewarding than stewing for years and years about Obama, or Bush, or the Iraq war, or whatever else you might get upset about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A European Education</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-european-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 22:14:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-european-education/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-european-education.jpg" alt="European Education" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Yesterday I was at lunch with a Czech friend of mine talking about education. His daughter just started the first grade and this week they had their initial teacher conferences. The teacher informed him and his wife that the daughter had a hard time focusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Of course she can&amp;rsquo;t focus; they have her there from 8AM to 3PM. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t focus at that age either!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It never occurred to me that there was anything out of place about the duration of the American elementary public school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I asked him how long school was in the Czech Republic. He said that first graders would be out by 11:30 AM. Wow, what a way to solve the problem of so many kids who are diagnosed with ADHD but may just need to run around and climb a few trees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our exchange student last year brought some perspective as well. She explained that when kids in Czech are in the fourth grade, they separate the &amp;ldquo;academic&amp;rdquo; ones from the non-academic ones. The academic ones are prepared for the university. The non-academic ones are prepared for a vocation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So instead of forcing a bunch of people into a mountain of student loan debt that puts them in a career or job that they don&amp;rsquo;t perform in, we could train them to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> go to college, save a ton of money, get back years of earning instead of going to school, and live much more confident and productive lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of labelling kids as being bad because they can&amp;rsquo;t (unnaturally) sit in a room for seven hours with a few breaks in between, we could limit the amount of time young students spend in school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I absolutely love having friends with different perspectives and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/" title="Life is Art">life experiences&lt;/a>. The American system is not the only good system; it&amp;rsquo;s not even the best in most things. Without my European friends, I would never see that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two Questions You Should Ask About Your Commitments</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 08:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-two-questions-about-commitments.jpg" alt="Commitments" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Lately we have been too busy, and we have had to figure out &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/" title="Achievable Contentment">what is working for us&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">what isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/a>. Usually when we get this way, our entire lives are filtered through two questions. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share them with you to think about what the answers are in your life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, make a list of the things in your life that you&amp;rsquo;re committed to. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OK, now for each of those things ask, &lt;strong>&lt;em>How would I feel if this wasn&amp;rsquo;t in my life? Relieved&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>? Then perhaps it should be a candidate for either changing or removing it from your life. How you feel when imagining something is gone is the best way to know if you really want to do something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now for the second question: &lt;strong>What would be the reaction of others if you &lt;em>did&lt;/em> say no?&lt;/strong> This is a tricky one, because it shows the long-term health of your relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can tell my wife, &amp;ldquo;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that. Let&amp;rsquo;s think of an alternative.&amp;rdquo; She would respond with love, acceptance, and we would work something out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell my church from college that. If you had asked me at the time to imagine it being gone, I would have sworn up and down to you that I loved it, etc. But then if you would have asked me if I was &lt;em>free&lt;/em> to reject it, if I was being honest I would have to say no.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So &lt;strong>rid yourself of everything you are relieved to get rid of. Only keep that which you can freely and openly reject.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Focus with the Amazon Kindle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-focus-with-the-amazon-kindle.jpg" alt="Focus with the Kindle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/" title="Life is Art">focusing on what matters&lt;/a> lately by &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">making good choices&lt;/a> with how and what you consume. Some things are just a complete waste of time like the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">local news&lt;/a>. Other things have a good alternative, like &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/">reading the Economist&lt;/a> instead of going to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">news sites&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I wrote last time, though, in this mobile world that isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. You have to make sure your smartphone is serving you and not enslaving you. And beyond that I&amp;rsquo;m convinced &lt;strong>to lead a life of growth and meaning you need to read.&lt;/strong> Probably more than you are right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do we do that? The solutions that come to mind immediately are: on our smartphone, a paper book, or a tablet. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about a better way to read books: through the Amazon Kindle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years back &lt;a href="http://www.chrisdikes.com/">my friend Chris&lt;/a> asked me what I thought about the Kindle, and my opinion to him as of July 16, 2010 was: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>It seems like having a book would be better.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Well, thankfully Chris didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to my awful advice and bought one, told me about it, changed my mind, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s so great about the Kindle:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distractionless:&lt;/strong> yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a feature and not a bug. I like it that there aren&amp;rsquo;t pop ups telling me all about the emails I&amp;rsquo;m not reading or the cool Facebook posts that I need to be looking into. I&amp;rsquo;m here to read. The Kindle helps me read.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Battery Life:&lt;/strong> I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be preoccupied with powering the stupid thing while I&amp;rsquo;m using it. I can read. I have to charge it every once and a while. It&amp;rsquo;s not like the power sucking smartphone or tablet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Position Independent:&lt;/strong> this may seem small to some, but I like reading while I&amp;rsquo;m laying down. And I get comfortable holding a book in one hand. Then I read fast and get to the other side of the book. So I have to move to read the other section. It seems like a small thing, and admittedly a first-world problem, but I love how I can read the Kindle with one hand laying on the same side for as long as it is comfortable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sleep Friendly Lighting:&lt;/strong> I have the Kindle paperwhite that doesn&amp;rsquo;t blast light into my eyes and keep me up. I can do a little nighttime reading with a very small amount of light. It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t distract my wife.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Borrower Capable:&lt;/strong> I have learned to take advantage of my library&amp;rsquo;s borrower privileges on the Kindle. This is easy once you figure it out. I do admit to buying more books than I would have before, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing as long as I read them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Keeps Your Place:&lt;/strong> I pick up the book and read exactly where I left off. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it. I just go.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Read More:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve read much more than before. If I&amp;rsquo;m interested in a topic, I can get a book on that topic and read through it quickly while I have a passion and interest in the book.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Portable:&lt;/strong> I admit to not doing it very often, but if I want to, I can read on my smartphone or even my computer to continue my reading.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I highly recommend going for a Kindle. You need to read to meet your goals, and in my mind there is no better way to do so than with the Kindle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sanitize Your Smartphone with Republic Wireless</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 08:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless.jpg" alt="Sanitize Smartphone" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The invention of the iPhone will probably be one of the key technological events of my lifetime. It changed the game from quirky Blackberry kind-of-phones, to a new experience that delivered a whole set of new capabilities in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. It has changed &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">the businesses I serve&lt;/a> and will continue to change our lives for years to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I finally got an iPhone it took over my life. This coincided with the birth of my children, so I spent a lot of time on the iPhone while they were at the park, or sleeping, or messing around at our house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Then I realized that I will never get those moments back.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized that the promise of convenience and greater efficiency does not line up with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">my personal goals&lt;/a> because my personal goals are to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">live a life of meaning, love, and connection&lt;/a>, especially with my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To put it more simply, &lt;strong>I was on my phone and ignoring my family.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What to do about this? I considered going away from a smartphone. That didn&amp;rsquo;t seem possible because there were times where it really did serve me. I tried to make a few rules like, &amp;ldquo;Stop ignoring my children&amp;rdquo;, but those didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work when the siren song of Facebook and email came singing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, I was spending over a thousand dollars a year on this habit that wasn&amp;rsquo;t serving me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Then I learned about a better way: Republic Wireless.&lt;/strong> With Republic Wireless, I bought a phone for $300* and now spend $10 a month on my mobile phone. I get data through Wi-Fi, which, by the way, exists at home and at work. I don&amp;rsquo;t get data on the way home from work. If I&amp;rsquo;m traveling, I get the option to change to the $25 a month plan that has data. I can even change it back to the $10 plan when I get home and only pay for the $25 plan prorated for the amount of days I used it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that I don&amp;rsquo;t instinctively go for the phone when I&amp;rsquo;m out and about. It&amp;rsquo;s a tool; it&amp;rsquo;s not my master. It also means if I need it to direct me somewhere I can type in directions before I leave when I&amp;rsquo;m on Wi-Fi, and the smartphone will get me there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like I have the best of both worlds. Combine that with my $10/month landline, I now have no excuse to be on my phone…ever. &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s an accessory. It&amp;rsquo;s not my whole life.&lt;/strong> Now I can live with the best elements of it and leave the rest alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in freeing your life from the insane addiction from the smartphone, you can get $10 off of Republic Wireless (as well as give me $10 off on my bill) by going &lt;a href="http://rwshar.es/6lhy">here&lt;/a>. Enjoy!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can get them even cheaper for $99 for an off-contract phone. Do the math and you&amp;rsquo;ll save a bundle while being able to spend less time on your phone. It&amp;rsquo;s a win-win!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Facing the Ultimate Distraction and Often Losing</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/facing-the-ultimate-distraction-and-often-losing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 08:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/facing-the-ultimate-distraction-and-often-losing/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-facing-the-ultimate-distraction-and-often-losing.jpg" alt="Distraction" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It was around 2008, and I heard about this new way to interact with people in your world. We were at a family gathering, and I started talking about this great application I had found called Facebook. My sister-in-law was delighted that we had finally caught up with her and that we were all going to join in this wonderful new thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those were the days when we were all so clueless about social media that Facebook had to cue us to post stuff, with &amp;ldquo;Michael is . . . &amp;quot; and then you wrote your thought into the text area. So the posts were things like &amp;ldquo;is enjoying my &lt;a href="http://www.nosdiet.com/">s-day&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; on August 23, 2008 and &amp;ldquo;is getting ready to go to India&amp;rdquo; on September 25, 2008 (almost exactly six years ago).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been great. I&amp;rsquo;ve stayed connected to people and shared in the lives of others in a way that I would not have before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a confession to make though:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a very conflicted relationship with Facebook. To understand, let&amp;rsquo;s filter the last few posts I&amp;rsquo;ve written on through the lens of what it promises and what it delivers:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Category&lt;/th>
&lt;th>What it Promises&lt;/th>
&lt;th>What it Delivers&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">Traditional News&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Your world doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter as much as all of these important people doing important things. Know about them so you can influence them&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A visceral and frustrated passion for things over which you have no control&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/">Sports News&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>The game will be much more fun if you know EVERYTHING there is to know about it. So know the gossip and facts behind everything you are watching so your hobby can become your life!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Paying way too much attention to sports is a substitute for real growth and changes in your life.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">Local News&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This is YOUR WORLD, these are YOUR NEIGHBORS, this stuff can happen to you. So you better pay attention before your lack of attention can cost you dearly.&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None of this affects your life, it&amp;rsquo;s just used as a distraction.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Facebook&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This really is your world. We&amp;rsquo;re serious this time. This really does affect you. Why would it not? These are your friends! So pay attention so you can live a more informed life pertaining to your world around you&lt;/td>
&lt;td>This replaces smalltalk which in reality will hurt your relationships with others, not help&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Hopefully that illustrates it for you. The promise of Facebook is so alluring: this is a situation in which being informed can really pay off. After all, this is your life! The problem is there is not a very easy way to filter out the noise within Facebook to get to the reality. And the second problem is that even when people are informed about your life through Facebook, when you finally meet face to face &lt;em>there is nothing to talk about!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You read that correctly. &lt;strong>Facebook, rather than making you &lt;em>more social&lt;/em> actually makes you less social.&lt;/strong> You already know the things about people that you used to talk to them about to gain interest. So over time you talk to people in smalltalk less and less. Over time you are less and less social.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is my conflicted relationship with Facebook. On the one hand I like being in tune with friends and family. On the other hand, that comes at the price of a lot of checking and time. I&amp;rsquo;ve considered over and over giving it up all together. But as my brother says, &lt;a href="http://weknowmemes.com/2011/11/quitting-facebook-is-the-adult-version-of-running-away-from-home/">leaving Facebook is the adult&amp;rsquo;s equivalent of running away from home&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wish I had some answers for you on this one. On paper this is something I should give up, but somehow I keep coming back to it over and over again. Maybe in a year I&amp;rsquo;ll have a good balance. But right now I don&amp;rsquo;t and I just wish the whole thing would go away. Maybe that means I&amp;rsquo;m ready for a break.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Have Time</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/you-have-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 08:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/you-have-time/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-you-have-time.jpg" alt="You Have Time" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m taking a break from &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">my hatred of all things&lt;/a> news to take a step back and write about &lt;em>why&lt;/em> I&amp;rsquo;ve been so negative in these recent posts about the news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not against entertainment. I think it serves a valuable role in our lives. I like watching a football game or hearing about things that are none of my business. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I just no longer fool myself into thinking that it matters.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s just entertainment. This isn&amp;rsquo;t life or death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I read books so I can grow into a better person, that takes time. When I &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/">ride my bike&lt;/a> to work every day instead of driving a car, that takes time. When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/">I read&lt;/a>, spend time with my family, volunteer, that all takes time. And our first reaction to changing things up in order &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">to live out our values is&lt;/a>: I don&amp;rsquo;t have time. I disagree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You have time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I said that right. &lt;strong>You have tons of time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you don&amp;rsquo;t have time to consume the news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you never watch TV for anything ever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you don&amp;rsquo;t get a full night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you never do anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve feeding or sheltering your family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You have time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My time waster is the news. I used to spend literally hours a day reading and thinking about it. Yours might be different. Whatever it is, see it for what it is, put things in perspective, and focus on what really matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is not: When will I have enough time to do what matters?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is: &lt;strong>When will I stop doing what doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter so I&amp;rsquo;ll have enough time to do what matters?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That mindset change will change your life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rubbernecking with the Locals</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-rubbernecking-with-the-locals.jpg" alt="Local News" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bumper to bumper traffic. Lights ahead. An ambulance speeds by in the shoulder lane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We inch by for a few minutes, and finally make it to the accident. Then something inevitable happens:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>OMG what happened!?!?! I need to brake and see what happened! Are they going to be OK? Do I know them? Is there&amp;hellip;BLOOD?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rubbernecking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is exactly what is happening in the local news. I&amp;rsquo;d like to give you a test to take right now:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Go to your &lt;a href="http://www.wfaa.com">local news site&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Count how many articles that fulfill this criteria:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>You will remember them a month from now&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You didn&amp;rsquo;t hear about them from another source&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They will affect your life in some way&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I just did this as of this writing, on September 5. I counted zero articles. I think that you might come up with a similar amount.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s going on here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We like knowing that no matter how bad things are for us, or how crappy our day is, there are at least a few people on the news that have it worse.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What value does this serve us? Logically speaking, absolutely none. This is a worthless activity. It isn&amp;rsquo;t even &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/">entertaining like sports&lt;/a>. It has no significance in the lifes and livelihood of all but a very small number of people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I&amp;rsquo;m trying to wean myself off of my local news addiction. I&amp;rsquo;m not replacing it with anything. I&amp;rsquo;m just stopping. I&amp;rsquo;ve had varying degrees of success over the past few months, because I love reading the local news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s worthless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to fully believe that one day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sports News: Soap Operas for People Who Make Fun of Soap Operas</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 08:00:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-sports-news-soap-operas-for-people-who-make-fun-of-soap-operas.jpg" alt="Sports News" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In the past I used to listen to &lt;em>The Ticket&lt;/em> every day on the way to and from work. I would follow the local teams through ups and downs. When the Dallas Cowboys won their only playoff game in the last almost twenty years, I was turning on The Ticket to hear their analysis. When the Mavericks won their World Championship a few years ago, I celebrated with my friends on the Ticket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I realized something:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sports News is even more worthless than &amp;ldquo;Real&amp;rdquo; News.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, you are hearing me correctly. I &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">just finished&lt;/a> outlining everything wasteful and dumb about CNN and Fox News, but I&amp;rsquo;m saying sports news is even worse than that. The difference: at least in &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; news we are talking about people&amp;rsquo;s lives and well being. In sports we are talking about a game using the same medium and tone that we talk about people&amp;rsquo;s lives and well being.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of observations really hit this home for me:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sports news &lt;em>loves&lt;/em> the soap opera story.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s funny to think that way, too, since so many sports fans are uber-masculine and would never admit to enjoying soap operas as entertainment. A few examples (as you read these in the tone of an airhead woman in her early twenties talking about a soap opera):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>_OMG did you hear about** &lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/dallas/mlb/story/_/id/11471420/ron-washington-quits-manager-texas-rangers">Ron Washington&lt;/a>?** He RESIGNED today as manager of the Rangers for personal reasons. Jon Daniels says it ISN&amp;rsquo;T about drugs. But who knows? I wonder how the players are feeling?_&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>OMG did you hear about the &lt;a href="http://insider.espn.go.com/blog/nfl/rumors/post/_/id/24032/will-refs-pocket-flags-in-regular-season">number of penalties being called in NFL preseason&lt;/a>? I wonder if, like, the NFL will call those during the REGULAR SEASON!?!?! This might like change the whole game.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>OMG, did you &lt;a href="http://espn.go.com/blog/denver-broncos/post/_/id/8501/wes-welker-roundup-everything-you-need-to-know-about-his-suspension">hear that Wes Welker&lt;/a> is SUSPENDED for FOUR GAMES for taking drugs? I wonder what drugs they are????&amp;hellip;!?!?!?!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is all of this about?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just like the news, this is about sucking people into intrigue over things that don&amp;rsquo;t matter so they&amp;rsquo;ll be sitting there when the advertising comes on. &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s about selling you stuff you normally wouldn&amp;rsquo;t buy.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does the nature of Ron Washington&amp;rsquo;s resignation matter? No.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there any effect that you can have on the number of NFL penalties by reading the article? No. No effect. You. Are. Wasting. Your. Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Does it matter what Wes Welker did or did not do? To him and his family, it means he makes a few hundred thousand less from multiple millions. To us, it means nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It means nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let that sink in, sports fans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is entertainment. It&amp;rsquo;s not your life. It&amp;rsquo;s not your family. It&amp;rsquo;s not your livelihood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s a business run by people who make a lot of money tricking you into thinking it matters.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that in perspective, by all means go to a game or watch it on TV and enjoy. But leave it at that, and find better things to do with your time. Over time, even that will begin to fade away.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Economist Keeps it Real</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-economist-keeps-it-real.jpg" alt="Economist" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Over the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to see &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">the absolute insanity&lt;/a> of following the news on normal news sites like CNN or Fox News. You might be thinking that I have no clue what is going on in the world. I do value being an educated person who knows about world events.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a secret weapon that helps me get this insight into the world without driving myself crazy day to day. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://www.subscriptionaddiction.com/magazines/subscription/the-economist-magazine-magazine.jsp">a paper subscription&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/">The Economist magazine&lt;/a>. Here are seven things I love about having a paper subscription to The Economist:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>International.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not focused on Americans only. I get more of an insight into the world than the typical American news outlets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Soap Opera Free.&lt;/strong> It doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to get me sucked into idiotic stories about how people are going to react to this or that, or worse what a celebrity was doing last Friday night. I want to be an educated man who knows world events…not a celebrity gossip connoisseur. The subscription keeps everything serious and leaves the rest out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distraction Free.&lt;/strong> When I read the magazine, I don&amp;rsquo;t see emails popping up. My kids don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m playing video games. They know I&amp;rsquo;m reading a serious news magazine. And when I put it down, I do something else. I don&amp;rsquo;t get sucked into ten hours of mindless video watching. &lt;strong>This is a feature and not a bug.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Not Republican or Democrat.&lt;/strong> I love it that I get out of the false American dichotomy of Republican and Democrat with the magazine. It has no interest in getting me to be &lt;em>more&lt;/em> one way or another. It just calls it like it sees it. Which is probably more of a Libertarian bent but honestly it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tell sometimes. And that&amp;rsquo;s how I would like to take my news. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be told what to think. I want some facts and fair analysis and I want to think about it myself.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Weekly.&lt;/strong> I don&amp;rsquo;t think that the appropriate news cadence should be any more frequent than once a week. If something is important I&amp;rsquo;m going to find out about it. I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend every day reading the news. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much. So the fact that the Economist is weekly is perfect for me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Guilt Free to Skip.&lt;/strong> This isn&amp;rsquo;t a &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; of the magazine as much as it is for me. If I had a weekly subscription and didn&amp;rsquo;t read &lt;em>any&lt;/em> of it, I still think it would be worth it. Why? Because it kept me from the hours per day of distraction I had been getting by going to news sites. So the Economist can be skipped just fine.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Diversified.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not just a political magazine. It also has stuff on business, technology, science. It has special features that bring you up to speed on a topic in depth.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I have subscribed to the Economist for months now and absolutely love it. I highly recommend you ditch your current news habit and buy an Economist subscription. I did some searching and found a deeply discounted deal &lt;a href="http://www.subscriptionaddiction.com/magazines/subscription/the-economist-magazine-magazine.jsp">here&lt;/a>. Try it and you&amp;rsquo;ll be hooked. If you run into me personally, I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to give you a copy so you can see what I&amp;rsquo;m saying; just ask.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Escaping with the News</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-escaping-with-the-news.jpg" alt="Escaping with the News" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I was having a great time at a party at my house recently, when a friend of mine who is quite conservative started talking to me about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012_Benghazi_attack">the Benghazi incident of September 2012&lt;/a>. He went on and on about how outrageous it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I respond, &amp;ldquo;I just don&amp;rsquo;t see how any of this is important or relevant to my life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With an outraged tone, he responds with eyes wide open in outrage, &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t think &lt;em>Benghazi&lt;/em> is important???&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To my life? No, I don&amp;rsquo;t. In fact I can take that a step further: &lt;strong>the news, especially political news is designed to get people to get outraged over things that are not in their power to change or influence.&lt;/strong> This state of frustration and anger puts them in a place where they are willing to buy more things in the advertisements, which is good for the provider of the outrageous news. But for the person who is consuming it, it is the very definition of a waste of time: spending time on something one doesn&amp;rsquo;t find enjoying, can&amp;rsquo;t do anything about, and causes them to act in ways that are outside of their values. This is insanity!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d like to propose we ask a question about every news article that we consume from now on: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>How will my life change as a result of me knowing this information?&lt;/strong>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I propose the answer is, for the most part, &amp;ldquo;none at all&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To illustrate, let&amp;rsquo;s comment on some CNN and Fox News headlines as of the date of first writing this, July 26, 2014:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Story&lt;/th>
&lt;th>How will my life change as a result of me knowing this information&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/26/world/meast/mideast-crisis/index.html?hpt=hp_t1">Rockets fired; Israel-Hamas truce appears over&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. The rockets likely won&amp;rsquo;t make it to North Texas. There is no election today to influence our political establishment, and political leadership in the U.S. seem to be aligned (for the most part).&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/26/world/africa/libya-us-embassy-evacuation/index.html?hpt=hp_t2">U.S. evacuates embassy in Tripoli&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am in North Texas, not Tripoli. I have nothing to be afraid of by whatever is happening there.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/joe-paterno-feared-wrongly-accusing-sandusky-son-says/?intcmp=latestnews">Joe Paterno Feared Wrongly Accusing Sandusky, Son Says&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am not nor do I have any friends who are a part of this case. While it is a tragedy, me knowing about the state of mind of one of the participants of the case, who is now dead, will have no bearing on the outcome of the case whatsoever.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/officials-cite-marijuana-as-reason-for-rise-in-denver-homeless/?intcmp=latestnews">Officials cite marijuana as reason for rise in Denver homeless&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I live in North Texas, not Denver. I do not use marijuana. I suppose if I did this news article wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change my mind about it. There is no marijuana vote on the Texas ballot today for me to vote on.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2014/07/26/some-in-cia-torture-report-denied-chance-to-read-it/?intcmp=latestnews">Some in CIA &amp;lsquo;torture&amp;rsquo; report denied chance to read it&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I am not subject to torture or defining what torture is in the coming months as far as I know. In fact if I were to be tortured, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that this report would have anything to do with how I would be treated.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/colorado-business-owner-fights-back-after-falling-victim-to-caller-id-spoofing/?intcmp=latestnews">Colorado business owner fights back after falling victim to &amp;lsquo;caller ID spoofing'&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I have managed to live my life for 35 years without knowing what the term &amp;ldquo;caller id spoofing&amp;rdquo; means. Even if there were a risk, I suppose I would hear about it from the phone company. The fact that it&amp;rsquo;s on a news site tells me that it is a rare occurrence. Besides, I don&amp;rsquo;t even own a business so there is absolutely no chance of anything in this article affecting my life.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2014/07/26/fast-food-workers-vow-civil-disobedience-in-wage-fight/?intcmp=latestnews">Fast food workers vow civil disobedience in wage fight&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;td>None. I don&amp;rsquo;t work at McDonald&amp;rsquo;s. I also don&amp;rsquo;t eat there very often. I suppose if their wages do go up, the price of a Happy Meal will eventually go up, thus creating an unexpected surprise on the rare occasion that I go to McDonalds. But we&amp;rsquo;re quite a ways from this: they are &lt;em>vowing &lt;/em>civil disobedience. Nothing has actually happened. This affects my life in no way whatsoever.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Let me give you a little guarantee: If you play this game for a few days on the news sites you are visiting, you will very quickly be awakened to the reality that this all is a complete and total waste of your time. &lt;strong>You are a pawn in someone else&amp;rsquo;s game to get you to buy stuff.&lt;/strong> There actually isn&amp;rsquo;t news on almost every day. And when there is it can be summed up in a ten second brief description.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let&amp;rsquo;s stop investing so much time in &amp;ldquo;news&amp;rdquo; and make some &lt;em>real&lt;/em> news in our own lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Escaping</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 08:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-escaping.jpg" alt="Escaping" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I get home &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">from work&lt;/a> and am daydreaming about a feature I need to add to my software as my son tells me about &lt;a href="https://minecraft.net/">Minecraft&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finally have a few moments of free time and spend them reading about movie stars and wars on the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At work I have something really important to work on but I read the latest tech news instead, and I get involved in a long conversation with a colleague about office politics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is going on here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think it&amp;rsquo;s simple: &lt;strong>real life is lived right here and right now with the choices you make.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not at work when you&amp;rsquo;re at home. It&amp;rsquo;s not with movie stars. It&amp;rsquo;s not in office politics. It&amp;rsquo;s not even on Facebook. It&amp;rsquo;s in your own choices &lt;em>right now.&lt;/em>****&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our problem is that many of us don&amp;rsquo;t like or are scared of the choices we have in front of us. If we were really honest with ourselves we&amp;rsquo;d have to admit that we just don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with our &lt;em>true&lt;/em> lives. We really want an escape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I run away from my present choices and go somewhere else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At home I go to work or to the lives of famous people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At work I move away from important decisions to politics or the unimportant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When relating to others I am preoccupied with my Facebook or Twitter status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or I keep thinking about how everything will be better in the future once my plans come to fruition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you want a &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">beautiful life&lt;/a> of meaning and purpose?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stop running away from it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do this you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set up a lifestyle that blocks out those distractions that keep you &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">from what truly matters&lt;/a>. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to figure out how to ignore the news. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to figure out how to stop checking your phone like a crack addict every five minutes. &lt;strong>You&amp;rsquo;ll have to learn how to live a life that is present in what is happening &lt;em>right now&lt;/em> in &lt;em>your life&lt;/em>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the journey I&amp;rsquo;m on, and I&amp;rsquo;m by no means perfect at it. We&amp;rsquo;re in this together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you running from? And what are you using to distract yourself from what really matters?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Finding a Philosophy of Life</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/finding-a-philosophy-of-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 08:00:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/finding-a-philosophy-of-life/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-finding-a-philosophy-of-life.jpg" alt="Finding Philosophy of Life" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We realize that the &lt;em>default&lt;/em> cultural script &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/our-cultures-script/">does not deliver on its promises&lt;/a>. We need a new one. We need a &lt;em>philosophy of life.&lt;/em> We need a framework of values and prescriptions that we can use as a starting point for living out our lives in such a way that they will be &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">a beautiful work of art&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before we get into the specifics of evaluating a &lt;em>particular&lt;/em> philosophy of life, I&amp;rsquo;ll define my requirements for it:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Christian but Universal.&lt;/strong> The philosophy I find must conform to my Christian faith. I need to be able to combine meaning I get from my life&amp;rsquo;s pursuits with ultimate meaning I get by faith within my religion. At the same time, we all live in the same world and deal with the same human condition, so the philosophy of life must be as universally applicable as possible. If I had a choice between an approach that &lt;em>only&lt;/em> worked for my denomination or religion and an approach that worked for everyone, I&amp;rsquo;ll pick the latter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Achievable Right Now.&lt;/strong> This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be something I need to spend twenty years on in order to see results. I should be able to see results from following the philosophy of life right now. I don&amp;rsquo;t have two thousand years to experiment, so results must happen quickly, and I must be able to adjust the plan. I can&amp;rsquo;t afford to just &amp;ldquo;trust&amp;rdquo; that in decades the &lt;em>real&lt;/em> results will come through.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Relational.&lt;/strong> If a philosophy of life tells me to live life by living alone on a mountain for decades, it&amp;rsquo;s the wrong one for me. I must relate to others. I must love my wife and family more. I must grow in serving and helping others. I must be motivated to help my community and those who are less fortunate than I am.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Historical.&lt;/strong> If a philosophy of life is something someone just dreamed up, it&amp;rsquo;s probably not going to work. Human condition in the civilized world has not changed &lt;em>so much&lt;/em> in the last two to three thousand years that we can&amp;rsquo;t rely on the wisdom of those who have gone before us. So a philosophy of life isn&amp;rsquo;t something I should &lt;em>create&lt;/em>; it should be something I &lt;em>discover&lt;/em>, and then tweak to fit my specifics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Moral.&lt;/strong> It must be something that enables me to be a better person and do good for others. It should be centered around love, which selflessly looks at the interests of others above one&amp;rsquo;s own.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Those are my requirements for finding a philosophy of life that will lead to happiness and meaning in my life. I&amp;rsquo;m sure yours are different. My question for you, before we dig deeper into this journey, is &lt;strong>what are your requirements for a philosophy of life?&lt;/strong> Are they different than mine? If so, how?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Our Culture's Script</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/our-cultures-script/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/our-cultures-script/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-our-cultures-script.jpg" alt="Our Culture Script" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We want our lives to be &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">a work of art&lt;/a> and reflect the beauty and meaning of our values. Most of us in search of meaning in our lives will naturally absorb our culture&amp;rsquo;s script for us:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>To create a beautiful work of art, you must feel good. To feel good, first you must make good money. You need to go to school and then get a good, stable job.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Once you get the job, start maximizing convenience. Pay for things you no longer want to do, including mowing the lawn, making meals, washing your car, fixing your house, going to the store. You work hard so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do these things.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Also, make sure you are as comfortable as possible. Get a nice big house you can be comfortable in, a nice, new car with leather seats that feel great, and stop at the ice cream store and give yourself a treat that makes you feel like a kid again. You deserve it because you work hard.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>You won&amp;rsquo;t be happy unless other people respect and want to be like you. So when you get a car, get something that will show everyone how hard you have worked. When you go on vacation, make sure it&amp;rsquo;s something totally awesome that will show how you have great taste and can afford the finer things in life. You want to be the best you can be. You&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard for this.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>You need to be happy. That&amp;rsquo;s what life is about. So make as much money as possible and spend that mainly on three things: convenience so you can focus on the things that really matter, comfort so you won&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by annoyances and pain and can focus on enjoying life, and respect so you can be validated that you have done something meaningful with your life.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with this? Well, nothing if it works. The problem is, when we think through this approach we don&amp;rsquo;t actually see anyone reaping its benefits. Instead we see millionaires that need more. Actors who are on drugs. Affairs. It&amp;rsquo;s an absolute mess out there. There&amp;rsquo;s never an end. There&amp;rsquo;s never enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t a good way to create a life of meaning and value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to sell stuff though.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This script does nothing about the biggest human problem: &lt;strong>no matter how much you have today, you always need more.&lt;/strong> Once you realize that, the above description becomes silly. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uEY58fiSK8E">You&amp;rsquo;ll never have too much convenience&lt;/a>. No matter how much comfort you have, you know people who have more and that makes you feel…uncomfortable. There will always be someone who gets more respect than you do. Your needs are &lt;em>insatiable.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is unavoidable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution? &lt;strong>Accept insatiability as a fact of life,&lt;/strong> dealing with it on a regular basis, and you will have a shot at sanity. How do you do this? Keep reading to find out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empathy</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/empathy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 08:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/empathy/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-empathy.jpg" alt="Empathy" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A few months ago we were at my mom&amp;rsquo;s house eating dinner. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know my mom, she&amp;rsquo;s an awesome cook. She had made one of my favorite meals of all time: meatloaf with green beans and mashed potatoes. I was in heaven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh gross,&amp;rdquo; the middle child exclaimed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parental embarrassment ensued, and then we got to talking about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mom talked about how her dad&amp;rsquo;s rule as he was growing up was that no one complains about food. If you do, you&amp;rsquo;re just going to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">have to figure out&lt;/a> a way to make it to the next meal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was my mom&amp;rsquo;s rule growing up. Complain and wait until the next meal to eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And from that day onward that has been our rule. You don&amp;rsquo;t complain about food. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to like it. But be polite and don&amp;rsquo;t whine about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of days ago we sat down to tamales, rice, and corn, and the middle child was being a pickle about the tamales. He stepped over the line and Mom said, &amp;ldquo;You may be excused&amp;rdquo;, which is code for, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not eating until breakfast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He sat there and cried and the look on his face of ‘I will not be eating for another 12 hours and I was already starting to feel hungry&amp;rsquo; was in full force.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I felt truly bad for him. He made a mistake.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that you can&amp;rsquo;t really relate to your children with love until you learn how to truly empathize with their mistakes. A few days ago I had a breakthrough in that. &lt;strong>My middle son needed to learn how to treat others. But he also had to deal with a bad situation.&lt;/strong> Taking away the consequence wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been empathetic: if there&amp;rsquo;s no pain in which to share, then there is no empathy. But also acting coldly towards him with a &amp;ldquo;this is how it is&amp;rdquo; attitude isn&amp;rsquo;t empathetic either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My wife saw that I had felt bad for my son, and she interpreted it as questioning her judgement on the consequence. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t it at all. &lt;strong>Empathy holds this strange place in between allowing consequences and loving others.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Empathy is when you share in someone&amp;rsquo;s suffering. It&amp;rsquo;s something I discovered a few days ago with my son and something that will transform my relationship with all three of them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life is Art</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-life-is-art.jpg" alt="Life is Art" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Earlier this year, I was pretty excited about some &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">drastic changes&lt;/a> we had made in our lifestyle. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m excited about something, I must tell someone and my friend at a dinner party at my house was no exception. I excitedly pointed out all the ways that simplicity has led us to a life of greater contentment and tranquility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could sense my friend becoming increasingly uncomfortable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Well, not everyone can live that way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend assumed that I view life as a science; that there are certain rules that &lt;em>must&lt;/em> be followed and a right and wrong way to do things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I completely disagree with that notion. To me &lt;strong>life is more like a work of art.&lt;/strong> You have a canvas on which to paint decisions, consequences, and ultimately meaning. Every life is as different as every work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a painter presents her painting, she is expressing herself in a unique way that is unlike anyone else. The painter has &lt;em>her&lt;/em> way of painting. To her it &lt;em>feels&lt;/em> like the right way, because, of course, she did it that way. Another painter may do it totally differently. A wonderful and mysterious thing happens in the gallery: &lt;strong>each painter admires the brilliance and beauty in the other&amp;rsquo;s work of art.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I am creating a work of art that I hope to be beautiful and meaningful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the entrepreneur who spends her nights and weekends creating a groundbreaking service that improves the lives of millions of people. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the philanthropist who travels the world to find a way to cure malaria worldwide. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the video game developer who works for two solid years to create a game that captures the imagination of a teenager who stays out of trouble because he has something to do when he&amp;rsquo;s out of school. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of a hospice nurse who works the night shift helping dying patients find dignity and meaning in their final days. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m creating a life of tranquility, meaning, and purpose. I do this through simplifying life in every facet, achieving in the marketplace through a fearless pursuit of adding value, and creating margin in my life to build a legacy with those around me, especially my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my work of art. This is the journey I will share with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It isn&amp;rsquo;t the only way.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I want it to be beautiful, and I want to share it with you because I hope we can inspire each other to make our lives a beautiful work of art.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting There with Metro Arlington Express (MAX)</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/getting-there-with-metro-arlington-express-max/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 08:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/getting-there-with-metro-arlington-express-max/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-getting-there-with-metro-arlington-express-max.jpg" alt="Failure Masquerading as Success" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Last week my family spent the week at my childhood home in Arlington with my mom. We had a great week of organization, projects, and best of all: &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/empathy/">my favorite food&lt;/a> from my childhood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mom lives in Central Arlington, southwest of UTA. I work near the &lt;a href="http://www.trinityrailwayexpress.org/stationsdetail.html?item_id=5">TRE Centreport station&lt;/a>, so I decided to try something a bit different:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t take my car for the entire week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How did I do this, you ask? By taking advantage of an awesome new service in Arlington: &lt;a href="http://www.ridethemax.com/">the Metro Arlington Express (MAX)&lt;/a>. The line goes from the east side of the UTA campus, stops at Collins, and drops off at the TRE station, 300 yards from my work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought I would review the experience for those who are interested in what it is like and may want to take advantage of it themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What I liked about it:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bike rack on the bus.&lt;/strong> I was able to ride up to the bus, pull the bike rack down, and put my bike on the bus. It was a great experience for a cyclist.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Riding through UTA and historic Arlington.&lt;/strong> I love the university feel of UTA. Every day I chose a new route to ride. The houses around UTA are also great to see. I enjoyed the scenery a ton.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Simple payment.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s $5 for a day pass. I had $5 bills ready to go and bought one a day. It was easier than a normal situation where the amount differs from factors you don&amp;rsquo;t understand. (A monthly pass is $70 to have access to all of DART.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Free internet.&lt;/strong> When I entered the bus, I opened my laptop and was able to get some work done or work on writing my blog posts. I felt like I was able to get back some time that I normally just spend in traffic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Flexible schedule for coming and going.&lt;/strong> The bus is running all day, so I can flexibly go back whenever I need to. I&amp;rsquo;m not locked in.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Flexibility with minor tardiness.&lt;/strong> The bus driver will stop if you&amp;rsquo;re running up to it and have just missed the bus. This happened to others, and it happened to me as well. I was grateful for the grace that they showed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Someone was DRIVING ME TO WORK.&lt;/strong> This is a service that only the ultra-wealthy were able to enjoy just 100 years ago. But now for $5, someone else will drive me to work. It&amp;rsquo;s really amazing. I got to sit there, not worry about traffic, directions, safety, or even timing. All that was handled for me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Popularity.&lt;/strong> The buses were about half full, which is what you want. People really use this in their every day lives. I was scared that I would be the only person on a bus because Arlington hasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly been a mass transit friendly place. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case. There were plenty of people who use this for their everyday commute, but not too many to make it crowded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Better options.&lt;/strong> For me this is a choice I have made, but it was so good seeing people without cars freed up to go where they needed to go. One day I spoke with a lady and her two children. The lady was trying to find a school to attend so she could get a better job. I met so many UTA students when I was a student there who were just stuck in Central Arlington. They now have the option to go to Dallas and Fort Worth. I think this is a wonderful addition to Arlington.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What can improve:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall it was a great experience. There were only three things that bothered me even a bit about it:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>** Bus Driver Friendliness.** Why are mass transit drivers so unfriendly? This is Texas. Smile, say hi, welcome. And when I ask you a question, provide a polite answer. I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is anything really bad about the MAX experience that is out of the ordinary. Just for some reason bus drivers usually seem like they are mad at someone. The exception to this was Chavez who was very nice to everyone.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Internet Connectivity.&lt;/strong> The internet goes out during parts of the trip. So generally I had to do disconnected work like blogging in Word or email.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cost.&lt;/strong> The gas to drive me there is cheaper than the $5 round trip. So financially speaking it is not competitive for the MAX ride itself. It becomes worth it when you transfer into Dallas or Fort Worth. Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t do this, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to save any money. I did this to ride my bike to work and go without a car. I would have liked to have an option to make my situation financially competitive with driving.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>If I lived in Arlington, I would definitely use the MAX every day instead of a car. It is a wonderful service that brings a component of transportation that has been lacking for many years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Things Done Action Plan</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-getting-things-done-action-plan.jpg" alt="GTD Action Plan" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>So you&amp;rsquo;ve been reading along and you want &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/mind-like-water/">to implement GTD&lt;/a> for yourself, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there before. More than once. I&amp;rsquo;ve started, then stopped, then started again. What do I tell people to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First, Collect Everything.&lt;/strong> Go through your entire life: your email, mail, closet, garage…everything. Put it all in an inbox. Make a list of everything on your mind and put &lt;em>that&lt;/em> in your inbox. You want to get everything out of your mind and into your system. Now that you have it all in once place, you&amp;rsquo;ll:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Get All Inboxes Empty.&lt;/strong> Take everything off the top and process it as we went over in the process post. No exceptions. You may not pay that bill right now (but if it takes 2 minutes you should), but you&amp;rsquo;ll have it in your system to do it later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Decide Your Yes.&lt;/strong> you now have a big list. You were saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to quite a bit of that list, so it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be any different than it was before. Only now you&amp;rsquo;re going to be conscious about it. So what do you want to do someday? What do you want to do now? What are your focuses? Put the things you want to focus on in a list with your name. I have a michael list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Share and Delegate.&lt;/strong> Do you need to do everything? If not, create another list and share it with that person. Talk with them about your joint goals and get agreement on what to do next and when. Set due dates and follow up. I have a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; list for home projects with my wife, and a &amp;ldquo;money&amp;rdquo; list for financial stuff that needs to be done with my wife. At work I have a list for every project I&amp;rsquo;m working on and share with the people who are on that project. Not everyone updates or is involved, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been pleasantly surprised at how receptive people are to having a project plan right there for them to think about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Review Regularly.&lt;/strong> Set recurring tasks in &lt;a href="https://checkvist.com/">Checkvist&lt;/a> to review your lists or a calendar if you don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re going to check it. Reviewing is key to the GTD methodology so do something that will get you looking at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Keep Saying No.&lt;/strong> Every day you&amp;rsquo;re going to say no to stuff. You should get comfortable with that. The minute you think &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that today&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s due today, change or remove the due date! &lt;strong>You have the power to make Checkvist show reality&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>by all means let it show you reality!&lt;/strong> Don&amp;rsquo;t settle with wishes when reality is just a few edits away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope you get as much out of GTD and Checkvist as I have. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear how your implementation goes if you&amp;rsquo;re convinced that you need to try this. I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that GTD isn&amp;rsquo;t about the tool and so you can implement it any number of ways. However, Checkvist is the best one out there, hands down!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mind Like Water</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/mind-like-water/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 08:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/mind-like-water/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-mind-like-water.jpg" alt="Mind Like Water" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The result of &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/productivity/">Getting Things Done&lt;/a>, when implemented properly, is &amp;ldquo;Mind Like Water&amp;rdquo;. When I first heard the term, I thought it meant, &amp;ldquo;peaceful, still, quiet.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s pretty silly though because water is in many &lt;em>other&lt;/em> states as well, just as often!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What &lt;em>Mind Like Water&lt;/em> really means is that you &lt;em>appropriately&lt;/em> react to your world. If a small pebble is thrown into a pond, it makes a small splash. If a large boulder is hurled into that same pond, it&amp;rsquo;s going to make a huge splash. This is how our minds should work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The problem is we get tricked into reacting to pebbles as if they are boulders.&lt;/strong> How to get out of it? Let&amp;rsquo;s review the system:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Collect&lt;/strong> helps you know that you can get to it later, and focus on the things that are happening now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Process/Organize&lt;/strong> helps you get the small things off your plate so you can focus, and organize the large things into actionable steps you know you will come back to later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Review&lt;/strong> is the essential piece where you start trusting that you will indeed remind yourself of things that you thought of before and take appropriate action. So for now, relax and focus!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Do you see a pattern? Everything in this system is oriented around you forgetting about everything around you and focusing on the next important thing. When a big thing comes along, you collect it, process it into your system, and do it. You appropriately react to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of the pieces of the system must be in place for you to reach this state of tranquility and productivity. And I only reached it when I used &lt;a href="https://checkvist.com/">Checkvist&lt;/a>, because that was the only system where I could get a good review workflow going and it is so adaptable because of its free form structure and keyboard centricity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The strange thing about GTD is the lack of focus on organizing what you do. Other systems will focus on prioritization, or assigning an &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; to the most important things. With Checkvist and GTD, once you organize your outcomes into actionable steps, and trust that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep juggling a million things, &lt;em>what you need to do becomes obvious.&lt;/em> What do I need to do today? Let me review my lists and the most important thing will pop out at me. I&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to all the rest by delegating them or saving them for later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is no need for priority codes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is no need to make it bold, or red, or flashing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system will work, and will tell you what to do. So get to work and get something done!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review the Glue</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/review-the-glue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/review-the-glue/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-review-the-glue.jpg" alt="Review the Glue" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It happened to me over and over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got sick and tired of being disorganized, of missing things, of not meeting my goals. &amp;ldquo;I am going to make a system.&amp;rdquo; I wrote everything I need to do down in a to-do list. I made sure my emails get processed correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And a few weeks later it was as if none of that ever happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why did this happen to me over and over again? Unlocking this secret was the key to actually implementing Getting Things Done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the key: &lt;strong>your system won&amp;rsquo;t work unless there is a place in it for you to review what you have processed.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about what we talked about earlier regarding your cluttered mind. You can&amp;rsquo;t tell your mind, &amp;ldquo;Stop thinking about that, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to it later&amp;rdquo; unless it can trust that you &lt;em>will&lt;/em> get to it later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about the empty inbox. Are you &lt;em>really&lt;/em> going to put that important email in the @Actions folder if you don&amp;rsquo;t trust that you&amp;rsquo;ll keep it there? No. What you&amp;rsquo;ll do instead is keep the &lt;em>important&lt;/em> emails in your inbox because, really, you don&amp;rsquo;t have a review system in place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where &lt;a href="https://checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a> really shines for me. I review items in Checkvist two ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Due Dates.&lt;/strong> If I need to get something done within a certain amount of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll set its due date. Every day I&amp;rsquo;ll check the &amp;ldquo;Due&amp;rdquo; screen (shortcut dd) and make sure I&amp;rsquo;m not missing anything. I&amp;rsquo;ll even set due dates on items that I &lt;em>commit&lt;/em> to doing by that time. For example no one is forcing me to read a book by August 1, but I put that as a due date to tell myself that is my goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Review Repeating Task.&lt;/strong> I set up a task called &amp;ldquo;Review [list]&amp;quot;* for every list I have that recurs as often as I need to review it. For example, I have a &amp;ldquo;Review money&amp;rdquo; task that recurs every Sunday and Wednesday with financial tasks on it. This is &amp;ldquo;Due&amp;rdquo; those days, so it will shows up in my due list that I&amp;rsquo;m checking from the above point. This way I only have to remember: every day look at my due list, which will tell me that I need to review my list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s my system. Other people can schedule meetings with themselves but that never worked for me. I need to review the areas of my life more regularly than that. And, as one who has tons of projects going on both personally and professionally, I have an even more complicated workflow that I&amp;rsquo;ll share in a future post regarding my reviews. But the above system I think works as well as anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bottom line is &lt;strong>make sure you have a system to review things, or else you don&amp;rsquo;t have a system.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hint: When you set up the review task, type &amp;ldquo;Review [lst:&amp;rdquo; and the list will pop up. Select the list and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to navigate to the list with the gg shortcut.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Process and Organize</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/process-and-organize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 08:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/process-and-organize/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-process-and-organize.jpg" alt="Process and Organize" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When I get home from work, I always go to my mailbox, take a few letters off of the top of my pile, open them, and put them back in the mailbox for later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Said no one ever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me though that is exactly what people do with email. This is insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order for you to have sanity in your life, you need a system that tells you, &amp;ldquo;What of my life have I put in my system to act on later, and what do I need to do so I can take action on them at the appropriate time?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the process and organize phase of Getting Things Done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how I do it: I go to each of the collection places I set up in the Collect Phase (physical inboxes, evernote, and email accounts), and follow this workflow:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is this actionable? Is there anything I need to do with this at any conceivable point ever?&lt;/strong> If not I should delete it or store it for reference, but my experience with this item is GONE FOREVER. I will never see this again and it will not invade my life ever again.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Can I do it in two minutes or less?&lt;/strong> If I can then I do it. There&amp;rsquo;s no sense of creating a to-do list item for &amp;ldquo;Reply &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; to email, &amp;ldquo;Are you coming tonight?&amp;rdquo; That would be silly. So keep it simple and get stuff out of the way that will just overload your system.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>What actions need to be taken for this to be done?&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not enough to say &amp;ldquo;Pool care&amp;rdquo; in your list. You have to have your list contain &lt;em>actions&lt;/em>, not just stuff. The action might be &amp;ldquo;Call the pool care company to schedule a filter cleaning.&amp;rdquo; Or it might even be &amp;ldquo;Search for a pool care company to help me with filter cleaning.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em>stuff&lt;/em>, it&amp;rsquo;s actions.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Add the actions into &lt;a href="http://www.checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong> I add whatever comes to my mind to finish what the item in my inbox represents into Checkvist. At first I recommend just having a &amp;ldquo;To Do&amp;rdquo; list in Checkvist and make it complicated later. You are dumping everything into that program because that is going to be your one-stop-shop for getting things done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Archive the item.&lt;/strong> It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stay in the inbox. Archive it. Move it to a folder. Whatever. But you will never see this again unless you need to. In this system there is a clear distinction between &lt;em>what is processed&lt;/em> and &lt;em>what needs to be processed.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Some more notes about this system:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I process my items from the top down, with few exceptions.&lt;/strong> This is important because in this workflow, you aren&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>doing&lt;/em> anything; you&amp;rsquo;re just processing your items. If you think, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get to this because it will take too long to do.&amp;rdquo; Well in that case, add the item to your list! I have an @Actions folder for these situations, so I know I can go to the email and write in a long response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My email inbox has zero items in it at some point every day.&lt;/strong> You think I&amp;rsquo;m crazy, I know. Believe me, once you do this workflow, you won&amp;rsquo;t ever go back. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told by people higher up than me that the email gets unbearable and that my workflow is impossible. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that it isn&amp;rsquo;t. I&amp;rsquo;ve already started forwarding emails to people on my team with short responses: &amp;ldquo;Yours&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Let me know if I need to do anything&amp;rdquo;. Most threads I&amp;rsquo;m copied on aren&amp;rsquo;t important. So I think that this should apply to everyone, and you &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to know what it is you need to get done in your life to have sanity in any way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The key to processing is translating &amp;ldquo;Stuff&amp;rdquo; into Actions.&lt;/strong> I can tell when someone really knows GTD by the items on their to-do list. &amp;ldquo;Set up blog&amp;rdquo; becomes &amp;ldquo;Buy domain on BlueHost&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Set up Genesis Theme on blog&amp;rdquo; and about fifty other things. How much faster do I burn through the fifty specific, actionable things, than my &amp;ldquo;Set up blog&amp;rdquo;? Honestly, for me &amp;ldquo;Set up Blog&amp;rdquo; goes nowhere, because &amp;ldquo;watch episode of Biggest Loser&amp;rdquo; is much more actionable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you think inbox zero will work in your situation? If not, why not?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Collect for Sanity</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/collect-for-sanity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 08:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/collect-for-sanity/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-collect-for-sanity.jpg" alt="Collect for Sanity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We are inundated with stuff. Stuff we need to act on. Stuff we need to remember. Stuff we need to worry about later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of us are stressed out with the amount of stuff in our lives. What to do about it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system outlined in Getting Things Done starts with collection: &lt;strong>there needs to be a system in your life for putting things that need to be processed later.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when you&amp;rsquo;re driving down the road and think of something, what is your system for collecting that for later? When you get a bill in the mail, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay it, what is your system for that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without this system &lt;strong>your mind will always be reminding you about everything.&lt;/strong> And you will never find peace. You will constantly be running from thing to thing and never able to say to yourself, &amp;ldquo;Relax, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to it later.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>Because your mind knows you won&amp;rsquo;t, because you don&amp;rsquo;t have a system for it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is where I collect things to be processed later:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Inbox at home.&lt;/strong> All my mail, bills, go here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Inbox at work.&lt;/strong> All my physical meeting notes, receipts go here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evernote.&lt;/strong> all my digital meeting notes go here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Gmail Inbox.&lt;/strong> All my personal email goes here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Outlook Inbox.&lt;/strong> All my work email goes here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If I want something to be processed in my life, they &lt;em>must&lt;/em> go here. If I put them here, I can forget about them, because I have a system to deal with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out a system for yet, but want to: daydreaming away from my computer. For this system to &lt;em>really&lt;/em> work, you have to empty your mind of all your stuff into a system. Anything that you ignore will come back over and over again. In the process phase you can say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to those things, but the key is that you tell your mind, &amp;ldquo;Forget about it. It&amp;rsquo;s in the system. Trust me.&amp;rdquo; This frees you up to &lt;em>truly focus.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right now I have no system for when I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in the car and realize, &amp;ldquo;I need to organize my closet.&amp;rdquo; Normally I forget about it by the time I arrive at my destination, and my mind gets stuck in a loop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The obvious solution to this would be my phone, but a lot of times it&amp;rsquo;s locked and difficult to get to. Another solution might be a portable recording device. I think I might experiment with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Has anyone come up with a good system for dealing with these times when you&amp;rsquo;re away from your inboxes or computers?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Planned Thinking</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/planned-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/planned-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-planned-thinking.jpg" alt="Planned Thinking" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In 2012 our efforts to add automated integrated testing to our central Point-of-Sale product were showing great results. We &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">were finding 20-40%&lt;/a> of all defects found in the software, many of which were found within hours of those defects being introduced by the developer. It took years of hard work to get to this place, and I was feeling good about our accomplishments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there was a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was running everything on adrenaline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was working extra hours, reacting to everything, and doing the next best thing to be done. But I was neglecting other really big things. It was review time and my boss wanted me to take my capabilities to another level. His advice was among the more valuable I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a review:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You need to stop at least once a week and think about things. You just need to stop and think&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My goodness he was right. And I knew better than this. Years ago I read the book Getting Things Done (GTD for short), which revolutionized how I did things. My problem was that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t developed a system for GTD principles. In the last year and a half I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on growing this area. I&amp;rsquo;m so excited to share with you my system, because I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great one that illustrates the concepts in GTD that I have only recently taken to the next level. If you read the book you get a good overview of the system. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe you really understand it until you see a system in practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The center of my GTD system is &lt;a href="http://www.checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a>. I met the creator a Checkvist a little over two years ago at Jetbrains when I was discussing TeamCity with them. Kirill was taking notes in Checkvist and copied me on it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the tool seriously until after the review at the start of 2013. This tool is the single biggest reason for my success in the last 18 months. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine life without Checkvist. In fact, this blog is managed through Checkvist and helped me create a workable plan that I could execute on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are five phases of Getting Things Done that I will cover in detail in four posts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Collect:&lt;/strong> how do you take the things in your life and put them in places that you know you&amp;rsquo;ll get to when you have time?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Process/Organize:&lt;/strong> Now that you have time, how do you take the things you have collected and put them in a system that you trust you will come back to later?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Review:&lt;/strong> what is your system for coming back to the things you&amp;rsquo;ve put in your system?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Do:&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;re going to do something, what is your system for knowing what is best?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet checked out Checkvist. I encourage you to do so and follow along in the next couple of weeks to get yourself organized. I&amp;rsquo;m here to help!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Growth Got Me Organized and Productive</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/productivity/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-productivity.jpg" alt="Productivity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If you keep learning and growing every day over the course of many years, you will be astounded by how far it will take you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As I read this in the introduction of John Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1599953668/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1599953668&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20">12 Indisputable Laws of Growth&lt;/a>, I realized how &lt;strong>low my expectations were&lt;/strong>. At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t believe Maxwell. My focus at the time was more on keeping it together and making the &amp;ldquo;next logical step&amp;rdquo; than on reaching a destination I didn&amp;rsquo;t previously think was possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I took Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s advice and have focused on growth ever since. I&amp;rsquo;ve read books. I got a mentor. I pressed into my work and made things happen. I built my team so it isn&amp;rsquo;t just me anymore having to do the major things; it is&amp;quot;we&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>After two years of intentional growth, I can see Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s wisdom firsthand.&lt;/strong> I have grown so much in these two years and feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve only begun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest area of growth is with my &lt;strong>productivity and organization&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other day I reviewed everything that was going on and took an action on one of my many projects. I went to talk with person, who was on the phone, so I stopped to say hi to a friend of mine. He was questioning out loud how much my team had taken on and how it seemed impossible. Two years ago it would have been impossible. But now it is working, because I have focused on growing as a leader and because I have focused on creating a system within which I can manage what needs to happen in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week I have six different projects at work going at the same time (and one project itself has three different subprojects). At home we are going through an amazing amount of change that is planned based on our newfound desire for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/" title="Achievable Contentment">contentment&lt;/a>. On the surface it feels like I have five different jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortunately, I have a secret weapon I use to keep my sanity: &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a> and the Getting Things Done methodology.&lt;/strong> This will be the focus of the next couple of weeks. But for now, open your mind to the possibility that if you intentionally grow over time, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to do things you previously thought weren&amp;rsquo;t even possible. All that&amp;rsquo;s needed is that you start.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>July Blog Update</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/july-2014-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 08:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/july-2014-update/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-july-2014-update.jpg" alt="Update" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This week I&amp;rsquo;m in Taos, New Mexico with my family and have been thinking a lot about things. I thought it would be a good time to share with you more about where I&amp;rsquo;ve been, where I&amp;rsquo;m going, and what you can do to help me.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="a-retrospective">A Retrospective&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When I planned out how I would start my blog, I planned five different series of posts, four of which have been published:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction:&lt;/strong> This shares some of my core values and lets you get to know me a bit. I naturally gravitated toward &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">contentment&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/">appropriate definition of success&lt;/a>. These topics have still remained very interesting to me and were fun to write. I think these posts are probably the closest to where I think this blog is headed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lessons Learned on my Install/Diagnostic Utility project:&lt;/strong> This coincided with speaking about it. These posts weren&amp;rsquo;t very popular; the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/safety-net/">safety net&lt;/a> post barely hit the top twenty. I had thought that there might be some more interest in the work-related sphere for lessons learned/etc., but there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Finances:&lt;/strong> Next I wrote about our financial story, which has played a big part in my character development in the last five years. This series was the most popular one, largely because I shared it on the &lt;a href="http://forum.youneedabudget.com/discussion/31368/success-story-posted-on-my-blog">You Need a Budget forum&lt;/a>. It was fun to write, especially when I write about the philosophy and mindset &lt;em>behind&lt;/em> making good financial decisions. I don&amp;rsquo;t read very many people writing about that, and think I may have insights in that area that can help people. The most popular posts in this series are also the most popular posts in the first two months: &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">the introduction to the story&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/month-ahead/">how I got a month ahead with YNAB&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lessons learned on my long-term Autopilot project:&lt;/strong> This coincided with speaking about it to our User Summit in Huntington Beach. The lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned have been valuable to me and I enjoyed sharing them, but my audience shrank during this series. This highlights a key surprise from the first couple of months: I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to get any traction or response from what I do professionally. If I talk broadly about what I do professionally, people enjoy it, but the more detailed I get the less response I get from it. That&amp;rsquo;s a strange reality that I want to understand more deeply, but I won&amp;rsquo;t do an entire series related just to a work environment before I know that it will be well received.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Getting Things Done:&lt;/strong> The next series I will write about how &lt;a href="http://checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a> has helped me implement the Getting Things Done system and has increased my productivity to previously unimaginable levels. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about this series because using this tool has created a breakthrough for me that has truly been revolutionary.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="my-purpose">My Purpose&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I write this blog for four reasons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>I want to create a network of people who want to grow and intentionally live a better life.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to grow as a writer and a speaker because I enjoy helping others win.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to help the vendors who have made me successful, giving back to those who have given so much to me.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to explore which of my ideas and passions resonates with an audience so I can know which paths my career can take me.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>So far I have learned a ton and have enjoyed the work that has gone into this.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-future">The Future&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I can already tell by how this first two months have gone that I want to write more about intentional, contented living. I&amp;rsquo;ve read a few books on this and will unpack it in August and beyond. I&amp;rsquo;m seeing by the response that these types of posts are the most helpful to people, and they are the most fulfilling for me to write.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-do-i-want-from-you">&lt;strong>What do I want from you?&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Subscribe to my email updates.&lt;/strong> This is on the right side of the posts and is the easiest way to be a regular reader.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Tell people about posts you like.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s really encouraging to see responses in social media/etc., so the more you do this the more you support what I&amp;rsquo;m doing and encourage me. Use the icons on the bottom of each post to easily do this.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Comment/Respond.&lt;/strong> If you&amp;rsquo;re an early reader of my blog and you like what I&amp;rsquo;m writing, you&amp;rsquo;re an important part of what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. If you like something, please tell me through a comment or &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/contact/">contact me&lt;/a>. If you don&amp;rsquo;t like a particular post or idea, tell me that too! It&amp;rsquo;s helpful to be able to hear from you.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you one way or another: &lt;strong>What about the first couple of months have you enjoyed the most? What would you like to read more about?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solve Problems by Isolating Them</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/solve-problems-by-isolating-them/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 08:02:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/solve-problems-by-isolating-them/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-solve-problems-by-isolating-them.jpg" alt="Isolate Problems" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out there is a [My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out there is a &lt;a href="http://www.legolanddiscoverycenter.com/dallasfw/">Legoland Discovery center&lt;/a> nearby. The other day they went to a birthday party there. The kids had an absolute blast. Legos, legos everywhere. It was totally awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also turns out that we have a &lt;a href="https://www.sixflags.com/overtexas">Six Flags&lt;/a> nearby. Fast roller coasters. Every amusement park craziness imaginable. We spent last summer doing that, and let me tell you, mom and I really got sick of it. But the kids absolutely loved it. They even wanted to do it again this summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So DFW area: lego land: check. amusement park: check. &lt;a href="http://california.legoland.com/">lego amusement park&lt;/a>? That will be a trip to California and $4000 please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how &lt;strong>the solution to a problem gets a lot more complicated and a lot more expensive when you combine it with another problem.&lt;/strong> I come across this a lot at work. I ruthlessly go through a project and eliminate anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t needed, because I want to ship it as quickly as possible and I know every little thing just adds to the time and complexity and makes the project that much more unrealistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So are we going to the LegoLand California Resort? If we do it, it will be with [My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Immunity</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/immunity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 08:05:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/immunity/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-immunity.jpg" alt="Immunity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We finally figured out a bedtime routine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the kids were late to school every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We figured out how to sit down every night for dinner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But we were spending too much on groceries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a reality we all face: no matter what you do, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">some other problem comes up to wreck everything&lt;/a>. And the same was true for my project that was dedicated to improving the quality of our software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we started, we focused mainly on making sure there was no problem with how an order was created, the receipt was printed, and the financials were calculated. We had prioritized this correctly; getting these three things right is critical to our success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once we had ramped up our solution, we saw a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of problems that we were able to catch before shipping our latest releases to anyone. We saved ourselves and our customers a lot of headaches that our competitors and their customers were likely suffering through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But over time, those problems decreased and the system seems to now have an immunity to these types of issues. It&amp;rsquo;s not a phenomenon I totally understand, but is one I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of from others in the industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our newfound immunity also hadn&amp;rsquo;t made us immune to &lt;em>every&lt;/em> problem. The problems we &lt;em>weren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> focused on were still there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We hadn&amp;rsquo;t focused on how software is installed at the site and that the correct environment was set up. So the software could be rock solid, but if the environment is off, we&amp;rsquo;re in trouble. It will likely never end, but it&amp;rsquo;s a fun journey to iteratively create immunity through automation in the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My advice with problem solving is &lt;strong>create a system that makes you immune to having the problem again.&lt;/strong> So get a month ahead of income so you never overdraft. Or put all your bills on autopay so you never miss one. Or every Friday take your spouse out for dinner. &lt;strong>But don&amp;rsquo;t expect all problems to go away entirely.&lt;/strong> Keep working at it, and you&amp;rsquo;ll grow beyond where you imagined, solving problems you didn&amp;rsquo;t even think you were capable of taking on. It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Embrace Difficulty</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/embrace-difficulty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 08:12:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/embrace-difficulty/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-embrace-difficulty.jpg" alt="Embrace Difficulty" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It was an impossible project and I was scared. The fact that &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">the world was ending&lt;/a> was the least of my concerns. We have software that is so flexible and configurable that it was impossible to fully test all the combinations of options our customers could run. My leadership at the time asked us to mitigate this by recording everything that happened at a restaurant and playing it back it back internally on prereleased software to make sure everything behaved the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t overstate how I felt: this problem scared the crap out of me. So much could go wrong, and so many issues to figure out. How would I get the software started? How would I know when/if the simulation was running correctly? What about all the other automation projects I had heard about over the years that had been cancelled due to lack of results? Would this project (and my career with it) be the next one thrown on the scrap heap when management realizes how impossible it is?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to step back, step away from my fear, and think of a good strategy. We were facing a difficult problem. The process we would come up with was likely to fail. A lot. Instead of running &lt;em>away&lt;/em> from that failure, we needed to embrace it. We needed to welcome it with open arms. Because &lt;strong>if we didn&amp;rsquo;t face the failure head on, we would never get past it, and we would fail.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we created a system where we ran any automation we had &lt;em>every day&lt;/em>. In fact, this is how we do it today, with over 150 restaurants running in a virtual environment and over 4,000 small scenarios. We do it every night. Do we have to do it every night? Technically no. But we embrace the difficulty of it by doing it every night so we get quick feedback of the problems and keep it on track.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People still argue with me over whether we &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to run this every night. I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that; I know it seems silly at times. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s key to our success: &lt;strong>we embrace the difficulty by doing difficult things all the time, so we can learn how to deal with them and make them not difficult anymore.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are a few other examples of embracing the difficulty in a system:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>When&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Embrace Difficulty By&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Doing Laundry&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Doing it every day&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Budgeting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Starting every month and facing reality&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Blogging&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Keeping a month ahead and posting at a regular pace&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Learning to Cook&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Cooking a regular meal on a day of a week&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Keeping the Family Close&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Eating dinner together every night&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>What have you avoided that you need to embrace in order to overcome it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Engineering Travel</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-engineering-travel.jpg" alt="Engineering Travel" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>This year our family has been &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/">focused on contentment&lt;/a> over consumerism. It all started with realizing that our children believed the lie that stuff was going to make them happy. Where on earth would they learn that behavior? It was probably from that school they went to. No, as we looked further they learned it from us, because we were living that way as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we started focusing on contentment, we realized it was a part of our whole lives. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t about just saving money on groceries and not eating out. Everything we did was a topic of conversation. And thus, the topic of travel went up, and we went through a bit of a transformation on how we see it. As I did in &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-laundry/">an earlier post&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through what I did and hope you get some ideas about how you can find more contentment in your travel choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="inherited-system">Inherited System&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The system we had gone with was similar to what most people in suburban middle-class America do:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We drove wherever we wanted.&lt;/strong> If we needed to go to the store, we drove. If we needed to go to Maryland, we drove. There was never a question &lt;em>if&lt;/em> we should be using a car. We drove.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Travel was a fixed expense.&lt;/strong> Travel expenses (gas, repairs, insurance) to us were almost the same as our mortgage payment. We just accepted the amount and moved on.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fuel Economy was a medium priority.&lt;/strong> When we shopped for cars, we took fuel economy into consideration, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t make it a priority. We had two cars that would fit our entire family in them, but of course we didn&amp;rsquo;t need that.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>We did have parts of our system that were a bit different than the norm:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We live and work locally.&lt;/strong> We are less than a ten minute drive from my work, our church, the kid&amp;rsquo;s schools, and grocery shopping. This was a huge priority to us when we moved a couple of years ago.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We drive used, paid off cars.&lt;/strong> We&amp;rsquo;re OK with the car not being a status symbol. We&amp;rsquo;ve always driven non-luxury, used cars.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>These last two elements are critical components for the new system outlined below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="problems-with-the-system">Problems with the System&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When we started looking at our lives and budget holistically, we saw a few problems with the system we had been living by:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We had a sedentary lifestyle that was setting us up for health problems.&lt;/strong> I had a desk job. Anytime we wanted to go &lt;em>anywhere&lt;/em> we went and sat on a metal-encased couch that launched us down a paved road. I was gaining a few pounds every few years. I went to the gym sometimes, but it was hard to fit it into my busy schedule.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We had a consumptive mindset.&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/" title="Achievable Contentment">a key to contentment&lt;/a> must be to think of yourself as a producer instead of a consumer. If you feel &lt;em>entitled&lt;/em> to consume, then nothing is ever good enough. When I produce as much as possible, the times when I do consume are wonderful, gracious experiences. Our system made us 100% consumers of our transportation, via the car.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="new-system">New System&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Our new system makes us producers as much as possible and leads us to a healthy lifestyle:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We walk or bike within five miles of our home.&lt;/strong> We don&amp;rsquo;t allow ourselves to get in a car if we need to go down to the grocery store; we bike. And, a magical thing happens: we get exercise! &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s such a transformation when fitness becomes a part of your life rather than a scheduled activity.&lt;/strong> What about the kids? They bike too! We have to focus on safety the whole time, but we do and they make it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We consciously use the car&lt;/strong>. When we are going to use the car to go somewhere &lt;em>more&lt;/em> than five miles away, we ask ourselves, &amp;ldquo;do I need anything else?&amp;rdquo; We try to consolidate trips because &lt;em>getting in the car is a special activity&lt;/em>. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to launch a couch down a paved road, I better have some good reasons for doing so.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>I periodically work from home.&lt;/strong> A day or two a week, I work from home. We&amp;rsquo;re creating an office for me, but for now I work at the kitchen table, or if the kids are there, I ride my bike down to the library. This helps me get focus to think about things, but it also keeps everything local and manageable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>I bike or ride a scooter to work.&lt;/strong> I haven&amp;rsquo;t purchased a scooter yet, but I will. I have been biking to work 80% of the days I work there.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We have one car.&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;m selling my Camry and we&amp;rsquo;ll only have a Sienna minivan. We really only need to take the family around in one car, so why do we need two? We don&amp;rsquo;t!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I absolutely love this new system. It has to be wrapped up in a mindset that convenience and comfort aren&amp;rsquo;t the most important things in life. This is definitely a more inconvenient and uncomfortable system. But those weren&amp;rsquo;t our goals; contentment and production were our goals. Living and working locally and minimizing our use of the automobile has left us more contented and productive than ever!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Increase Income by Negotiating</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/increase-income-by-negotiating/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/increase-income-by-negotiating/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-increase-income-by-negotiating.jpg" alt="Increase Income by Negotiating" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When one &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/">gets serious&lt;/a> about meeting their financial goals, the obvious immediate focus is &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/">to lower expenses&lt;/a>. If you want to get out of debt, stop going to Starbucks. And find a way to be content with not having it anymore. But there is another side of the equation as well: your income.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back in 2010 when I shifted my personal finance perspective, I decided to get serious about my income as well as my expenses. And I thankfully found the book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0931213207/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0931213207&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=W6BC6IOM726IEVJK">Negotiating Your Salary: How to Make $1000 a Minute&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://www.salarynegotiations.com/">Jack Chapman&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book changed my thinking in three important ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Everything is negotiable.&lt;/strong> Stop looking at things as fixed. They aren&amp;rsquo;t. You need to create more value for your company, and they will be willing to pay you more. Negotiate for the value that you are creating, and by all means &lt;em>work your butt off&lt;/em> to create the value. But don&amp;rsquo;t just passively go through life accepting whatever is given to you. Negotiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Be intentional.&lt;/strong> Don&amp;rsquo;t let performance reviews happen to you. Be intentional. Be clear about your goals and work with management to accomplish them. Don&amp;rsquo;t just accept what they&amp;rsquo;re telling you, but press in and make sure that they respect you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stop talking.&lt;/strong> When negotiating, the one who talks is the one who is losing. Be simple about your goals and stop talking. This is the part that I struggle with the most. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/speaking/">I can&amp;rsquo;t stop talking&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This turned a perceived static situation I had no control over into a dynamic situation where I increased my value to my employer and in return over time increased my income. It takes a while, but if your goals are realistic and if you work hard, you&amp;rsquo;ll get there. I know as a manager I love managing people who are intentional and motivated to work hard to create an outcome. I&amp;rsquo;ll always take that person over an unmotivated lazy person who is fine with their salary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lowering Expenses with Contentment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-lowering-expenses-with-contentment.jpg" alt="Lowering Expenses with Contentment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/">YNAB&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/">Dave Ramsey&lt;/a> entered our lives, we became an unstoppable force to meet our financial goals. Our original debt payoff forecasts were beat by a mile, largely because we got serious and focused all of our time, energy, and money to debt payoff. We had met some really great goals and were feeling great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there was a problem. After we met our debt payoff goal, the angels did not descend from the heavens and make everything better. And there was still an insatiable appetite for more stuff. The only difference was that now I had more money to spend on getting that stuff. It was like we had finished a long diet but did nothing about our love of ice cream.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we got more stuff for a few months. And I felt the same. Dave Ramsey has a saying, &amp;ldquo;Live like no one else, so that later you can live like no one else.&amp;rdquo; We had lived like no one else, so that later…we would get depressed about how meaningless it all is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the problem: you&amp;rsquo;ll never win with discontentment. You never find enough. You&amp;rsquo;re always wanting more. So in the long run, the &amp;ldquo;sacrifice now&amp;rdquo; will not lead to peace and balance later, because you&amp;rsquo;re training yourself for discontentment. Let&amp;rsquo;s illustrate this in other areas of life:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>With&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Live like no one else looks like&lt;/th>
&lt;th>But contenment looks like&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Dieting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to join crossfit and do that multiple times a week, and eat Paleo and judge everyone else who doesn&amp;rsquo;t as idiots&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn how to enjoy the calories I really need, appreciating that I&amp;rsquo;m swimming in a sea of cheap calories that kings of old didn&amp;rsquo;t have&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Work&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to make this happen and work Saturdays and drive everyone to do the same…this is going to launch my career into the stratosphere&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to really think about what and how I&amp;rsquo;m doing things, and make sure I do the right things with the right team, and do those things well&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Marriage&lt;/td>
&lt;td>We&amp;rsquo;re going to go to counseling, a marriage retreat, and then sit down every night and talk&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to give her a break and serve her and &lt;a title="Releasing Control" href="http://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">try to not control her&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Money&lt;/td>
&lt;td>If I get an extra job, I can pay off my debt and get an expensive car ten years from now&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I don&amp;rsquo;t need an expensive car. Or all this stuff. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop buying stuff and find that I have a lot of money left over that I can save. And wow, I&amp;rsquo;m happier!&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Sometimes the middle column is called for. But only temporarily, because discontentment leads to discontentment. It&amp;rsquo;s a neverending cycle. And the only way to get to where you want to go is through contentment. You may need to spend a few months moving the needle. Great. The focus though should be on finding contentment in your life, and creating a margin of time, money, and focus that will help you accomplish your goals long-term.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Move the Needle with Dave Ramsey</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 08:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey.jpg" alt="Move the Needle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We had &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">a failure that was the catalyst to change&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/">a tool that would help us change our relationship with money&lt;/a>. Now we needed to get out of debt. We needed to get serious. We needed &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1595555277/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1595555277&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=O5HAQUNJLACSUUTX">Dave Ramsey&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Full disclosure: our household has kind of moved away from some of Dave Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s ideas since 2010 when we drank the Koolaid. I&amp;rsquo;ll get into why in the next post, but for now I want to write what I appreciate about him and how he presented personal finance to us in a way that got us serious about getting out of debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dave Ramsey doesn&amp;rsquo;t do debt. He hates it. To him, the only reason one should get into debt is to buy a house, and he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even fully recommend that one. Most people think he&amp;rsquo;s extreme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s genius is that when it comes to being in debt, being extreme is exactly what is called for. The numbers aren&amp;rsquo;t the reason people aren&amp;rsquo;t getting out of debt; the psychology is. So when you get out debt the Dave Ramsey way, you sell everything. You don&amp;rsquo;t eat out. You think about it every day. You work extra. Maybe an extra job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You get sick and tired of being sick and tired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The principle here is &lt;em>Move the Needle&lt;/em>. Sometimes it makes sense to get crazy and move the needle in some area of your life. Make a change happen, possibly at the short-term sacrifice of other things, so you don&amp;rsquo;t quit. Once you accomplish something, quitting it is no longer an option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you&amp;rsquo;re needing to make a change and gut it out in the short term in order to create the environment where you can win in the long, term, have at it! I know with getting out of debt, this is the only way to go in order to actually do it. If you try to nickel and dime your way out of debt, you&amp;rsquo;ll never get there because you&amp;rsquo;ll get distracted and go after something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we got serious and decided to move the needle with getting out of debt, all the pieces fell into place and we got out of debt really quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is when this becomes a way of life. At some point, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to stop moving the needle. More on this in the next post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Month Ahead</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/month-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 08:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/month-ahead/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-month-ahead.jpg" alt="Month Ahead" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re at the mall, it&amp;rsquo;s the 12th of the month and you want to buy sunglasses. Do you have the money? If you&amp;rsquo;re living paycheck to paycheck, it depends on whether the mortgage will come before or after your paycheck. It might also depend on your checking account balance. This is normal for most Americans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best thing &lt;a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/C9FV2R2">YNAB&lt;/a> did for us is encourage us to get a month ahead in income (they call this &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/method/rule-four">Rule Four&lt;/a>). Paychecks we receive in June pay July&amp;rsquo;s expenses. But for most stuck in the paycheck to paycheck rat race, the idea itself seems like a fantasy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were there, definitely, but we got obsessed with getting a month ahead because we wanted to experience its benefits of simplicity, peace, and clarity. Here&amp;rsquo;s how we did it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We Took Advantage of Bi-Annual Three Paycheck Months.&lt;/strong> Luckily, January 2010 was a three paycheck month. We budgeted every month for two paychecks, so we were already halfway to our goal the very first month. If you&amp;rsquo;re paid biweekly, every six months is a golden opportunity to get ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We Drew a Line in the Sand.&lt;/strong> Before we started using YNAB, &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">we had used our credit card&lt;/a> and were in the process of paying it off. Normally that would have been our top priority, but instead of working on that, we made those off budget accounts and set them to the side and paid the minimum. This rerouted some cash that was planned on paying off a credit card balance to being a month ahead. This is how I recommend approaching YNAB:** what&amp;rsquo;s in the past is in the past; focus on creating a system that will work for your future and everything will fall into place.**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>All Margin Went to Rule Four.&lt;/strong> We had a few hundred dollars a month that we had extra every month. Sometimes it would go to something fun or to meet one of our goals. When we implemented YNAB, &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of our money went toward this one goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Moved End of Month Bills to the Next Month.&lt;/strong> We paid our car insurance every month. I called the insurance company and had them move the bill to be due from the 28th to the 2nd of the next month. To them it&amp;rsquo;s a few days. But in YNAB, it gets you out of the current month and into the next month…and closer to being a month ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Planned for a Lean First Month.&lt;/strong> We put everything into getting a month ahead, so it was OK if we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the &lt;em>full&lt;/em> set of monthly income for our first Rule Four month. We just needed to cover the necessities, and let a month pass. At that point we would be a &lt;em>full&lt;/em> month ahead on income. This is the time to have one of those &amp;ldquo;I won&amp;rsquo;t buy anything&amp;rdquo; months!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When we were close, we cautiously overrode Rule Three.&lt;/strong> Over the years I have really grown to appreciate the wisdom of &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/method/rule-three">Rule Three&lt;/a>: every month start over and budget the money you have available. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about making every month perfectly balance. When you override Rule Three by carrying a negative category balance, you run the risk of having to focus on your account balances and you lose many of the benefits of the YNAB system. When we were just getting started, and within hundreds of dollars of being able to make it through February on January&amp;rsquo;s income. We had to prepay our portion of a family vacation that would happen in the summer. Rather than wait another month or two to meet our goal, we had that category carry over a negative balance for the next month. We had done the steps before so there was no risk that our balances would get too low.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re a month ahead, if we&amp;rsquo;re at the mall and we want to buy something, we check the category balance. We don&amp;rsquo;t care about when the mortgage payment will go through, when I get paid, or the checking account balance. All of those variables have been removed because we are spending last month&amp;rsquo;s money this month. Now that we have clarity on just focusing on the category balance, we put our energy into making better decisions. And that for us has made all the difference in helping us go wherever we want to go financially.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Need a Budget</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 07:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-you-need-a-budget.jpg" alt="You Need a Budget" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I experienced &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">a financial tailspin&lt;/a> that got my attention enough to make some serious changes in my life. I needed to assemble a team that could help me meet my goals. &lt;a href="http://www.theprayerroomdfw.com/index.cfm?i=11234&amp;amp;mid=25&amp;amp;blogid=4177">A friend of mine&lt;/a> had told me about budgeting software that he had loved that fit with how I liked to budget. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken &lt;a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/C9FV2R2">You Need a Budget&lt;/a> (YNAB, pronounced why-nab) seriously until then, but now was the time to dive deeper into this tool to see if it would fit my needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I found was a great software tool created by a team that cared more about serving people and changing lives than making money. This is a critical piece of being on my team: you must be more dedicated to serving others than to enriching yourself. And the small team that created YNAB was dedicated to service over self. This software has changed my life in so many ways; I feel indebted to them to do whatever I can to make them successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what is so good about this software? A lot, but I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on four aspects:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Simple Enough for Non-Geeks.&lt;/strong> This was a requirement for me. I needed my wife to be involved and she isn&amp;rsquo;t a math nerd or a geek. YNAB presents budgeting in such a simple way that non-geeks, non financially saavy people can understand it with &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/support/training-and-education">minimal training&lt;/a> and make it happen. My wife&amp;rsquo;s involvement in our goals has been critical to our success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Focus is on the Right Goals.&lt;/strong> In other budgeting programs, you&amp;rsquo;re focused on account balances or fitting your life in the system. YNAB has great systems for keeping you focused on where you want your money to go, and forgetting about the timing of bills or keeping everything balanced perfectly. So now we think about what our goal is and how to meet that goal, month to month. And then we forget about it and live our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s Reality Focused.&lt;/strong> I was helping a friend set up YNAB, and he said to me, &amp;ldquo;I want to wait until next month to start this so I can buy a couple of iPhones.&amp;rdquo; I informed him that buying iPhones was as simple as allocating hundreds of dollars into a category and then spending it. YNAB doesn&amp;rsquo;t force you into a perfect situation or month. Those don&amp;rsquo;t exist! You simply tell it what you want to do with your money. That can even include blowing a lot of money on electronics; it&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It Plans for the Unexpected.&lt;/strong> it&amp;rsquo;s not expecting you to perfectly plan every cent and then rush to the software whenever something changes. It lets you easily change your plan, or just wait for the next month, where the available money will be adjusted to how well or bad you did the month before. A solid system must plan for noncompliance to the plan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Four and a half years later, YNAB is helping us meet our goals just as it did in the beginning. It is our constant companion through life, always helping us bring together our intentions and our actions. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for something to help you meet your financial goals, you owe it to yourself to look at &lt;a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/C9FV2R2">YNAB&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Failure the Catalyst</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 08:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-failure-the-catalyst.jpg" alt="Failure the Catalyst" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t take credit cards, only cash.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was November 2009, and I was locked into &amp;ldquo;Project: Have a Third Child&amp;rdquo;. Part of the deal I made with my wife is that we could offset some of the hardships of having another child by doing some things for ourselves. This translated partly into changing our half bath into a full bath and completely redoing the furniture and decorating of our master bedroom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As with most home projects, reality quickly surpassed our budget. That was OK. I was going to use my credit card. Nevermind that I promised myself I would never use it in this manner…this totally frivolous remodeling project was an emergency! I would pay it off, I promised. I just needed to get through this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.viperplumbing.com/">My plumber&lt;/a> dug a hole in our foundation, extended the toilet drain to what would be the shower, and charged me a hefty sum to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And he only took cash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As did &lt;a href="http://mastertilesetter.com/">the tile guys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://paulhedgpethpainting.blogspot.com/">the painter&lt;/a>. Crap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The inevitable occurred. I overdrafted our checking account and our finances went into a tailspin that took us a few weeks to get out of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My wife and I awoke to how totally out of control and useless our current financial system had been. Some major changes were on the horizon. But these changes had a beginning in failure. At the time failure seems so terrible, so awful, that nothing good can come out of it. But in reality failure is often a catalyst for change.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>When you fail by&lt;/th>
&lt;th>it is the catalyst for&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>losing your job&lt;/td>
&lt;td>putting yourself on the right path to meet your goals, with the options wide open&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a marital separation or affair&lt;/td>
&lt;td>finding or abandoning your true commitment to that person, which means there will no longer be a lukewarm relationship&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a project failure at work&lt;/td>
&lt;td>understanding what &lt;i>will not &lt;/i>work, so you can pursue what will work either for you or your organization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>gaining weight&lt;/td>
&lt;td>reanalyzing your relationship with food and an active lifestyle and making changes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Failure feels terrible at the moment, but it really is a wonderful blessing because it is the only catalyst I know of for real success. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been able to believe this enough to make failure suck any less, but it sure is nice to know while I&amp;rsquo;m going through it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Engineering Laundry</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-laundry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 08:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-laundry/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-engineering-laundry.jpg" alt="Engineering Laundry" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Before two weeks ago, &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">my wife&lt;/a> had an intense hatred she only shared with close friends. This was something she avoided; she abhorred. Something that trapped her in a life of anger and despair.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clothes. Worn and discarded. Washed. Dried. Put away. Repeat. Until death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of weeks ago, she asked me to reduce her workload by doing laundry. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t argue against helping her out with a job that I could do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I got to thinking about it, here&amp;rsquo;s what really intrigued me: laundry is a simple system that can be optimized, or engineered, for maximum efficiencies. As an engineer, I really love maximizing efficiencies. So I decided to tackle this problem of laundry using principles I&amp;rsquo;ve learned as an engineer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="inherited-system">Inherited &lt;strong>System&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The system I inherited went something like this, for our family of five:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Each room on the second floor has a clothes hamper (all of our sleeping rooms are on the second floor). When cleaning the room, put the clothes in the clothes hamper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you&amp;rsquo;re on the first floor, put the clothes in the laundry room which is on the first floor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once a week, on no particular day, take all the clothes from the rooms and pile it in the laundry room.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sort the clothes into loads of whites, colors, towels.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wash and dry the clothes (this takes two days).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When the clothes are dried, put the clothes that are to be hung up flat on top of the dryer. Put the clothes that are in dressers in a bag that hangs on the wall, one for each person. There is also a bag for kitchen towels and bathroom towels.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At some point take all bags upstairs, and put the clothes away in dressers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>At some point hang up the clothes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This entire process would begin as it was ending. In other words, laundry ended up being a neverending mess of never-done-ness.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="problems-with-the-system">Problems &lt;strong>with the System&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I looked at the system not as a household chore but as a system that I could maximize using principles I use at work. So looking at it that way, what were the problems with this system?&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Excessive Batching.&lt;/strong> Everything was piled up and done at once, and there was no flow. When there is so much work in progress, you can&amp;rsquo;t optimize the system because there are too many variables in it. It&amp;rsquo;s like trying to cook Thanksgiving Dinner…all at once. There has to be a clear process in place and simplicity at every step for any hope of true optimization.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Excessive Sorting.&lt;/strong> Laundry was sorted at least two times within a large set. There was a separation of &lt;em>all the laundry&lt;/em> into loads, and another separation of &lt;em>all the laundry&lt;/em> by who owned the laundry. This was especially difficult with the kids, whose sizes are remarkably similar and ever-changing, even though they insist it&amp;rsquo;s totally obvious that the shirt belongs to one or the other.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lack of Ownership.&lt;/strong> My wife was doing all the work. None of us wanted to do the job. So we were leaving valuable contributions from me and my sons on the table, which led to…&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Despair from Lack of Closure.&lt;/strong> The system didn&amp;rsquo;t give you a sense of being &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo;. In software terms there was no &amp;ldquo;release&amp;rdquo;. It was just always going.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="new-system">New System&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I did some internet searching and &lt;a href="http://lifeasmom.com/2013/04/kids-can-do-laundry.html">came across an article&lt;/a> that was extremely close to what I have implemented. It addresses all of the problems stated above. Here&amp;rsquo;s the system:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Every person in the house gets their own laundry basket except for parents who share theirs. Every person is responsible for putting their own clothes into &lt;em>only&lt;/em> their own basket.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is a basket downstairs that towels and linens go into.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Every basket is done by its owner on a particular day of the week. Someone helps too if that&amp;rsquo;s needed. Our schedule is:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Day&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Basket&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Owner&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Helper&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Monday&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Parents&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Mom&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dad&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Tuesday&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Oldest&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Oldest&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dad&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Wednesday&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Towels&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dad&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Mom&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Thursday&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Middle Child&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Middle Child&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dad&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Friday&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Youngest Child&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dad&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Dad&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="benefits-of-the-new-system">Benefits of the New System&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve done this system for a week now, and wow has it made a difference. Here&amp;rsquo;s why:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We&amp;rsquo;ve broken the whole system down into smaller, manageable chunks. That way there is a sense of progress, completion, and lack of despair. Since the laundry room is clean (other than a basket with towels), it is a place where you can create an outcome relatively quickly and get out. You&amp;rsquo;re done. There&amp;rsquo;s not a big scary laundry monster in there to kill you.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sorting has been drastically minimized. Now when we wash the youngest child&amp;rsquo;s clothes, it&amp;rsquo;s extremely clear whose clothes those are when they come out of the dryer. This knocks off the total time we spend on it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Everyone owns laundry. It&amp;rsquo;s not something that only Mom does. And she gets to do the part that is most important to her (her own clothes), so we win by me not accidentally shrinking her brand new sweater.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The problem that one might have with this system is that you are doing laundry &lt;em>every day&lt;/em>. But a different person is in charge of it, and it&amp;rsquo;s a mangable amount. It seems to be working out well for us so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The great thing I found through this process is how well management principles relate to so many other areas of life. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the things I want to explore in the future: taking wisdom from one area of life and applying it elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Do these principles apply to another area of your life?&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surprise</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-surprise.jpg" alt="Surprise" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/">the last post&lt;/a> I wrote about a mistake I made where I focused too much on The Grand Vision and not enough on solving small problems. At the time, I felt that accomplishing The Grand Vision was going to be awesome and would save the world, and would mean that there would be a parade for my entire team, and cheering, and wonderful speeches given for us all. It will be glorious, except, now I realize I totally screwed it up:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I left no room for surprise.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Surprise is when someone&amp;rsquo;s expectation is suddenly shifted into a totally new place in an instant. &lt;strong>Surprise has a way of changing the game immediately and causing your competitors to scramble.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When your competition expects an outcome, they have time to spin it as no big deal. Your flaws (and there will be flaws if you ship it) will be the surprises, not the big game-changing outcome that you created. People adjust to the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; reality over a period of months, when in fact the reality hasn&amp;rsquo;t even changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This lesson will be central to everything I do for the rest of my life. If I am trying to create an important outcome that makes a difference, I should focus &lt;em>first&lt;/em> on creating the outcome. &lt;strong>If it is as important as I think it is, surprise will be my ally.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Grand Vision</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 08:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-grand-vision.jpg" alt="The Grand Vision" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Late last year I started a new project that was dedicated to improving our delivery process and tools. I spent a few weeks talking to people throughout our organization about what the problems were and how we can best address them. And then I came up with &lt;strong>The Grand Vision.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grand Vision was an awesome elevator speech where I drew quadrants and arrows, talked about the main problems I was seeing and how to bring them together into one, totally awesome, unified structure that Would Save The World.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the meetings, a key leader I respect said to me, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s ambitious.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thanks,&amp;rdquo; I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a complement&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lesson I learned is that it&amp;rsquo;s important to map out the process and see how what you&amp;rsquo;re doing fits into the entire goal. &lt;em>But it&amp;rsquo;s also important to solve problems immediately that have a quick return on investment.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This kind of thinking happens all the time:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ambitious&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Should be&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get rid of all sugar in my house and go GLUTEN FREE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>On Fridays I eat donuts that people bring in the office. In June I&amp;rsquo;m not going to eat any.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a gym membership with personal training and wake up every day at 5:30AM and get RIPPED!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to bike anywhere within 5 miles of my house and do 20 pushups a night&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>We are going to a full week marriage conference in Aspen, Colorado so we can get our marriage back on track&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Let&amp;rsquo;s go on a date and not look at our phones&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to avoid the really tough problems in front of you by dreaming a big dream.&lt;/strong> I think many of us like to think if we can&amp;rsquo;t do it all, then why do it at all? The real battle is won when we drop that all or nothing thinking and get something done&amp;hellip;&lt;strong>today&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When have you let the grand vision distract you from what really needed to be done right then and there?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christmas with Russians</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-christmas-with-russians" alt="Christmas" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It was Christmas 2008, and the world was going to end. We didn&amp;rsquo;t know if there would be an economy or even civilization. And I had two weeks of vacation to end the year. I had an 18 month old who was mostly occupying himself with Christmas toys, and my wife was two months away from having my second child. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to take the vacation, but the policy at the time was &amp;ldquo;use it or lose it&amp;rdquo;, so I took it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could have done anything with those two weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I chose to set up &lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/articles/continuousIntegration.html">Continous Integration&lt;/a> for one of our largest products through &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/">TeamCity&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was something I was passionate about. I had &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0026772IS/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0026772IS&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=RJ6US3SXFLCWDTR5">read the literature&lt;/a> on how transformative Continuous Integration had been to organizations. This product was built twice a day by a homeade tool called bmcon.exe and some batch files. If the build broke, dozens of people stopped everything to try to get it working, with no clear feedback mechanism for knowing what went wrong, who did it, and whether it was being worked on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was my moral duty to fix this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it so happened that those working on TeamCity were going to take their Christmas holiday&amp;hellip;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas_in_Russia">on January 7&lt;/a>. They were Russian. So I took it upon myself to monitor the email and get the build working over the Christmas holidays. I remember on Christmas day &lt;a href="http://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/TW-6471">I was conversing with&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://de.linkedin.com/in/jonnyzzz">Eugene Pentrenko&lt;/a> across the world about how to deal with the complexities of TFS pulling thousands of files and then building them*.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Years later, almost all of our products build with TeamCity, and we have thousands of integration tests and tens of thousands unit tests that run on our 100+ build agents to make it happen. It is central to everything we do. And it all started one Christmas years ago when I had a &amp;ldquo;moral duty&amp;rdquo; to do something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008KPM424/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B008KPM424&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=52YQPMBZ7Z4IMUKU">Selling with Noble Purpose&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href="http://www.mcleodandmore.com/what-is-selling-with-noble-purpose/">Lisa McLeod&lt;/a> leads the reader through an exercise where the reader thinks about situations where one makes a difference with customers, in a different way than other people, while loving what they are doing. When I went through this exercise I was reminded of this story. Through the exercise I found my noble purpose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I share tools and insight for success&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what truly excites me, and why this blog exists. I want to share the tools and insights I&amp;rsquo;ve found to succeed. I want to help those who have given me tools and insights that have made me more effective by spreading them to others. And I want to properly define success so I can make sure to follow the path that will lead me there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next few posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about key elements of &lt;em>true&lt;/em> success. Success is one of those things that seems easy to see in others, but never seems recognizable in ourselves. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve found a few reasons why this is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>_* You can&amp;rsquo;t see it in the issue I link to above but Eugene was emailing me and went above and beyond, after his normal hours, to resolve the issue._&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>