<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ynab on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/ynab/</link><description>Recent content in ynab on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 08:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/ynab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Move the Needle with Dave Ramsey</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 08:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey.jpg" alt="Move the Needle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We had &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">a failure that was the catalyst to change&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/">a tool that would help us change our relationship with money&lt;/a>. Now we needed to get out of debt. We needed to get serious. We needed &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1595555277/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1595555277&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=O5HAQUNJLACSUUTX">Dave Ramsey&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Full disclosure: our household has kind of moved away from some of Dave Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s ideas since 2010 when we drank the Koolaid. I&amp;rsquo;ll get into why in the next post, but for now I want to write what I appreciate about him and how he presented personal finance to us in a way that got us serious about getting out of debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dave Ramsey doesn&amp;rsquo;t do debt. He hates it. To him, the only reason one should get into debt is to buy a house, and he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even fully recommend that one. Most people think he&amp;rsquo;s extreme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s genius is that when it comes to being in debt, being extreme is exactly what is called for. The numbers aren&amp;rsquo;t the reason people aren&amp;rsquo;t getting out of debt; the psychology is. So when you get out debt the Dave Ramsey way, you sell everything. You don&amp;rsquo;t eat out. You think about it every day. You work extra. Maybe an extra job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You get sick and tired of being sick and tired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The principle here is &lt;em>Move the Needle&lt;/em>. Sometimes it makes sense to get crazy and move the needle in some area of your life. Make a change happen, possibly at the short-term sacrifice of other things, so you don&amp;rsquo;t quit. Once you accomplish something, quitting it is no longer an option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you&amp;rsquo;re needing to make a change and gut it out in the short term in order to create the environment where you can win in the long, term, have at it! I know with getting out of debt, this is the only way to go in order to actually do it. If you try to nickel and dime your way out of debt, you&amp;rsquo;ll never get there because you&amp;rsquo;ll get distracted and go after something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we got serious and decided to move the needle with getting out of debt, all the pieces fell into place and we got out of debt really quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is when this becomes a way of life. At some point, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to stop moving the needle. More on this in the next post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Month Ahead</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/month-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 08:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/month-ahead/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-month-ahead.jpg" alt="Month Ahead" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re at the mall, it&amp;rsquo;s the 12th of the month and you want to buy sunglasses. Do you have the money? If you&amp;rsquo;re living paycheck to paycheck, it depends on whether the mortgage will come before or after your paycheck. It might also depend on your checking account balance. This is normal for most Americans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best thing &lt;a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/C9FV2R2">YNAB&lt;/a> did for us is encourage us to get a month ahead in income (they call this &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/method/rule-four">Rule Four&lt;/a>). Paychecks we receive in June pay July&amp;rsquo;s expenses. But for most stuck in the paycheck to paycheck rat race, the idea itself seems like a fantasy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were there, definitely, but we got obsessed with getting a month ahead because we wanted to experience its benefits of simplicity, peace, and clarity. Here&amp;rsquo;s how we did it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We Took Advantage of Bi-Annual Three Paycheck Months.&lt;/strong> Luckily, January 2010 was a three paycheck month. We budgeted every month for two paychecks, so we were already halfway to our goal the very first month. If you&amp;rsquo;re paid biweekly, every six months is a golden opportunity to get ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We Drew a Line in the Sand.&lt;/strong> Before we started using YNAB, &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">we had used our credit card&lt;/a> and were in the process of paying it off. Normally that would have been our top priority, but instead of working on that, we made those off budget accounts and set them to the side and paid the minimum. This rerouted some cash that was planned on paying off a credit card balance to being a month ahead. This is how I recommend approaching YNAB:** what&amp;rsquo;s in the past is in the past; focus on creating a system that will work for your future and everything will fall into place.**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>All Margin Went to Rule Four.&lt;/strong> We had a few hundred dollars a month that we had extra every month. Sometimes it would go to something fun or to meet one of our goals. When we implemented YNAB, &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of our money went toward this one goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Moved End of Month Bills to the Next Month.&lt;/strong> We paid our car insurance every month. I called the insurance company and had them move the bill to be due from the 28th to the 2nd of the next month. To them it&amp;rsquo;s a few days. But in YNAB, it gets you out of the current month and into the next month…and closer to being a month ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Planned for a Lean First Month.&lt;/strong> We put everything into getting a month ahead, so it was OK if we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the &lt;em>full&lt;/em> set of monthly income for our first Rule Four month. We just needed to cover the necessities, and let a month pass. At that point we would be a &lt;em>full&lt;/em> month ahead on income. This is the time to have one of those &amp;ldquo;I won&amp;rsquo;t buy anything&amp;rdquo; months!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When we were close, we cautiously overrode Rule Three.&lt;/strong> Over the years I have really grown to appreciate the wisdom of &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/method/rule-three">Rule Three&lt;/a>: every month start over and budget the money you have available. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about making every month perfectly balance. When you override Rule Three by carrying a negative category balance, you run the risk of having to focus on your account balances and you lose many of the benefits of the YNAB system. When we were just getting started, and within hundreds of dollars of being able to make it through February on January&amp;rsquo;s income. We had to prepay our portion of a family vacation that would happen in the summer. Rather than wait another month or two to meet our goal, we had that category carry over a negative balance for the next month. We had done the steps before so there was no risk that our balances would get too low.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re a month ahead, if we&amp;rsquo;re at the mall and we want to buy something, we check the category balance. We don&amp;rsquo;t care about when the mortgage payment will go through, when I get paid, or the checking account balance. All of those variables have been removed because we are spending last month&amp;rsquo;s money this month. Now that we have clarity on just focusing on the category balance, we put our energy into making better decisions. And that for us has made all the difference in helping us go wherever we want to go financially.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>