<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>contentment on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/contentment/</link><description>Recent content in contentment on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:00:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/contentment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lowering Expenses with Contentment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-lowering-expenses-with-contentment.jpg" alt="Lowering Expenses with Contentment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/">YNAB&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/">Dave Ramsey&lt;/a> entered our lives, we became an unstoppable force to meet our financial goals. Our original debt payoff forecasts were beat by a mile, largely because we got serious and focused all of our time, energy, and money to debt payoff. We had met some really great goals and were feeling great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there was a problem. After we met our debt payoff goal, the angels did not descend from the heavens and make everything better. And there was still an insatiable appetite for more stuff. The only difference was that now I had more money to spend on getting that stuff. It was like we had finished a long diet but did nothing about our love of ice cream.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we got more stuff for a few months. And I felt the same. Dave Ramsey has a saying, &amp;ldquo;Live like no one else, so that later you can live like no one else.&amp;rdquo; We had lived like no one else, so that later…we would get depressed about how meaningless it all is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the problem: you&amp;rsquo;ll never win with discontentment. You never find enough. You&amp;rsquo;re always wanting more. So in the long run, the &amp;ldquo;sacrifice now&amp;rdquo; will not lead to peace and balance later, because you&amp;rsquo;re training yourself for discontentment. Let&amp;rsquo;s illustrate this in other areas of life:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>With&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Live like no one else looks like&lt;/th>
&lt;th>But contenment looks like&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Dieting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to join crossfit and do that multiple times a week, and eat Paleo and judge everyone else who doesn&amp;rsquo;t as idiots&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn how to enjoy the calories I really need, appreciating that I&amp;rsquo;m swimming in a sea of cheap calories that kings of old didn&amp;rsquo;t have&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Work&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to make this happen and work Saturdays and drive everyone to do the same…this is going to launch my career into the stratosphere&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to really think about what and how I&amp;rsquo;m doing things, and make sure I do the right things with the right team, and do those things well&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Marriage&lt;/td>
&lt;td>We&amp;rsquo;re going to go to counseling, a marriage retreat, and then sit down every night and talk&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to give her a break and serve her and &lt;a title="Releasing Control" href="http://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">try to not control her&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Money&lt;/td>
&lt;td>If I get an extra job, I can pay off my debt and get an expensive car ten years from now&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I don&amp;rsquo;t need an expensive car. Or all this stuff. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop buying stuff and find that I have a lot of money left over that I can save. And wow, I&amp;rsquo;m happier!&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Sometimes the middle column is called for. But only temporarily, because discontentment leads to discontentment. It&amp;rsquo;s a neverending cycle. And the only way to get to where you want to go is through contentment. You may need to spend a few months moving the needle. Great. The focus though should be on finding contentment in your life, and creating a margin of time, money, and focus that will help you accomplish your goals long-term.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Achievable Contentment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 09:30:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-achievable-contentment.jpg" alt="Achievable Contentment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing great here, and you&amp;rsquo;re an asset to what we&amp;rsquo;re doing. We think you have a bright future with us.&amp;rdquo; My boss was obviously happy &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">with my performance&lt;/a> and was telling me about it in no uncertain terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s great, and I appreciate it, but when will I get promoted to Software Architect?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted more than anything at that point in my career to be a &lt;a href="http://money.cnn.com/magazines/moneymag/bestjobs/2010/snapshots/1.html">Software Architect&lt;/a>. The title comes with respect, a great salary, and a leadership position within a software development organization. Most people who knew my goal never questioned its efficacy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>…But I now see that it was the wrong goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A good goal is one that delivers what it promises: contentment and happiness.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contentment I envisioned after getting the promotion very quickly became discontentment wrapped around another, bigger goal. All of the sudden I wanted to be a Senior Software Architect. And then more. And more. This is insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a better way: goals that lead to contentment. Some examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>You&amp;rsquo;ll never be content with having&lt;/th>
&lt;th>But you will be content with&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>The next promotion&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Doing work that matters and being fairly rewarded for it&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A big raise&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Spending less than you make, whatever it is&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A new luxury car&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A car you can afford&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>The spouse of your dreams&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A marriage based on love, acceptance, and peace&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>In the left column, everything seems so deceptively simple. &amp;ldquo;All I want is a Mercedes.&amp;rdquo; Well, yes, but _what happens when you get the Mercedes? What &lt;strong>then?&lt;/strong> The left side is one in which you never end up at a destination. You are always striving, always anxious, always gunning for the next thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The left column is a series of steps in life that all follow a commonly accepted pattern of &amp;ldquo;going for the next thing&amp;rdquo;, but arriving nowhere important. These goals ultimately lead to misery and despair once one inevitably finds this out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s strange is that no one questions this path to success, even though there are so many examples of burned out, depressed, unhappy people who have followed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A better definition of success is on the right side. These are achievable goals, not in a few years but right now. The goals aren&amp;rsquo;t as measurable, and those around you won&amp;rsquo;t notice them as much as they would a new Mercedes. However, they deliver what they promise: achievable contentment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Success is achievable contentment through goals that have an end to them. The end of a truly success-oriented goal isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>another goal.&lt;/em> It is contentment and peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are your goals? Where will they lead?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>