<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>product management on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/product-management/</link><description>Recent content in product management on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 08:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/product-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Surprise</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-surprise.jpg" alt="Surprise" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/">the last post&lt;/a> I wrote about a mistake I made where I focused too much on The Grand Vision and not enough on solving small problems. At the time, I felt that accomplishing The Grand Vision was going to be awesome and would save the world, and would mean that there would be a parade for my entire team, and cheering, and wonderful speeches given for us all. It will be glorious, except, now I realize I totally screwed it up:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I left no room for surprise.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Surprise is when someone&amp;rsquo;s expectation is suddenly shifted into a totally new place in an instant. &lt;strong>Surprise has a way of changing the game immediately and causing your competitors to scramble.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When your competition expects an outcome, they have time to spin it as no big deal. Your flaws (and there will be flaws if you ship it) will be the surprises, not the big game-changing outcome that you created. People adjust to the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; reality over a period of months, when in fact the reality hasn&amp;rsquo;t even changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This lesson will be central to everything I do for the rest of my life. If I am trying to create an important outcome that makes a difference, I should focus &lt;em>first&lt;/em> on creating the outcome. &lt;strong>If it is as important as I think it is, surprise will be my ally.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Grand Vision</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 08:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-grand-vision.jpg" alt="The Grand Vision" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Late last year I started a new project that was dedicated to improving our delivery process and tools. I spent a few weeks talking to people throughout our organization about what the problems were and how we can best address them. And then I came up with &lt;strong>The Grand Vision.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grand Vision was an awesome elevator speech where I drew quadrants and arrows, talked about the main problems I was seeing and how to bring them together into one, totally awesome, unified structure that Would Save The World.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the meetings, a key leader I respect said to me, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s ambitious.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thanks,&amp;rdquo; I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a complement&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lesson I learned is that it&amp;rsquo;s important to map out the process and see how what you&amp;rsquo;re doing fits into the entire goal. &lt;em>But it&amp;rsquo;s also important to solve problems immediately that have a quick return on investment.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This kind of thinking happens all the time:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ambitious&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Should be&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get rid of all sugar in my house and go GLUTEN FREE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>On Fridays I eat donuts that people bring in the office. In June I&amp;rsquo;m not going to eat any.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a gym membership with personal training and wake up every day at 5:30AM and get RIPPED!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to bike anywhere within 5 miles of my house and do 20 pushups a night&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>We are going to a full week marriage conference in Aspen, Colorado so we can get our marriage back on track&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Let&amp;rsquo;s go on a date and not look at our phones&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to avoid the really tough problems in front of you by dreaming a big dream.&lt;/strong> I think many of us like to think if we can&amp;rsquo;t do it all, then why do it at all? The real battle is won when we drop that all or nothing thinking and get something done&amp;hellip;&lt;strong>today&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When have you let the grand vision distract you from what really needed to be done right then and there?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Safety Net</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/safety-net/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 08:00:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/safety-net/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-safety-net.jpg" alt="Failure Safety Net" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Late last year I began seriously working on improving how we deliver updates to our software to restaurants. One of the most interesting parts about my job is how many aspects of technology become incredibly difficult when you have a chef twenty feet away instead of a data center technician in a lab coat. Updates are no exception: the operation of the restaurant itself is at stake and we must get it right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do you improve something like that? Believe me, this was something that was keeping me up at night. The problem is the huge amount of risk involved in anything going wrong in the restaurant operations, but at the same time the huge operational benefit improving it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The insight we found was that &lt;em>before making a change that has risk, build a safety net to ensure that the change will have the desired effect&lt;/em>. &lt;strong>Build quality into the system, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to make the needed changes to the system.&lt;/strong> Otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;re dead when the first problem hits and you&amp;rsquo;ll never recover.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This insight relates to so many areas of life and business:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="table-responsive">
&lt;table style="width:100%; " class="table" border="0">
&lt;tr>
&lt;th >
When doing
&lt;/th>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> &amp;lt;th &amp;gt;
create safety with
&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
Software development
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
automated unit and integration tests
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
A budget
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.youneedabudget.com/method/rule-four&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;living on last month's income&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
A healthy marriage
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
going on a date and having fun together
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
A college class
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
a study group
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
A business idea
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;td &amp;gt;
seeing if it can be profitable on the side
&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A safety net is a critical aspect of any system I create today. The bigger the risk involved, the more I strive to include saftey in the solution we create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What safety nets have you created in your solutions? Have you ever created &lt;em>too much&lt;/em> of a safety net?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>