<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gtd on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/gtd/</link><description>Recent content in gtd on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 08:00:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/gtd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Things Done Action Plan</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-getting-things-done-action-plan.jpg" alt="GTD Action Plan" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>So you&amp;rsquo;ve been reading along and you want &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/mind-like-water/">to implement GTD&lt;/a> for yourself, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start. I&amp;rsquo;ve been there before. More than once. I&amp;rsquo;ve started, then stopped, then started again. What do I tell people to do?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First, Collect Everything.&lt;/strong> Go through your entire life: your email, mail, closet, garage…everything. Put it all in an inbox. Make a list of everything on your mind and put &lt;em>that&lt;/em> in your inbox. You want to get everything out of your mind and into your system. Now that you have it all in once place, you&amp;rsquo;ll:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Get All Inboxes Empty.&lt;/strong> Take everything off the top and process it as we went over in the process post. No exceptions. You may not pay that bill right now (but if it takes 2 minutes you should), but you&amp;rsquo;ll have it in your system to do it later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Decide Your Yes.&lt;/strong> you now have a big list. You were saying &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to quite a bit of that list, so it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be any different than it was before. Only now you&amp;rsquo;re going to be conscious about it. So what do you want to do someday? What do you want to do now? What are your focuses? Put the things you want to focus on in a list with your name. I have a michael list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Share and Delegate.&lt;/strong> Do you need to do everything? If not, create another list and share it with that person. Talk with them about your joint goals and get agreement on what to do next and when. Set due dates and follow up. I have a &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo; list for home projects with my wife, and a &amp;ldquo;money&amp;rdquo; list for financial stuff that needs to be done with my wife. At work I have a list for every project I&amp;rsquo;m working on and share with the people who are on that project. Not everyone updates or is involved, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been pleasantly surprised at how receptive people are to having a project plan right there for them to think about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Review Regularly.&lt;/strong> Set recurring tasks in &lt;a href="https://checkvist.com/">Checkvist&lt;/a> to review your lists or a calendar if you don&amp;rsquo;t think you&amp;rsquo;re going to check it. Reviewing is key to the GTD methodology so do something that will get you looking at it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Keep Saying No.&lt;/strong> Every day you&amp;rsquo;re going to say no to stuff. You should get comfortable with that. The minute you think &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that today&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s due today, change or remove the due date! &lt;strong>You have the power to make Checkvist show reality&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>by all means let it show you reality!&lt;/strong> Don&amp;rsquo;t settle with wishes when reality is just a few edits away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope you get as much out of GTD and Checkvist as I have. I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear how your implementation goes if you&amp;rsquo;re convinced that you need to try this. I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that GTD isn&amp;rsquo;t about the tool and so you can implement it any number of ways. However, Checkvist is the best one out there, hands down!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mind Like Water</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/mind-like-water/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 08:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/mind-like-water/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-mind-like-water.jpg" alt="Mind Like Water" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The result of &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/productivity/">Getting Things Done&lt;/a>, when implemented properly, is &amp;ldquo;Mind Like Water&amp;rdquo;. When I first heard the term, I thought it meant, &amp;ldquo;peaceful, still, quiet.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s pretty silly though because water is in many &lt;em>other&lt;/em> states as well, just as often!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What &lt;em>Mind Like Water&lt;/em> really means is that you &lt;em>appropriately&lt;/em> react to your world. If a small pebble is thrown into a pond, it makes a small splash. If a large boulder is hurled into that same pond, it&amp;rsquo;s going to make a huge splash. This is how our minds should work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The problem is we get tricked into reacting to pebbles as if they are boulders.&lt;/strong> How to get out of it? Let&amp;rsquo;s review the system:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Collect&lt;/strong> helps you know that you can get to it later, and focus on the things that are happening now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Process/Organize&lt;/strong> helps you get the small things off your plate so you can focus, and organize the large things into actionable steps you know you will come back to later.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Review&lt;/strong> is the essential piece where you start trusting that you will indeed remind yourself of things that you thought of before and take appropriate action. So for now, relax and focus!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Do you see a pattern? Everything in this system is oriented around you forgetting about everything around you and focusing on the next important thing. When a big thing comes along, you collect it, process it into your system, and do it. You appropriately react to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of the pieces of the system must be in place for you to reach this state of tranquility and productivity. And I only reached it when I used &lt;a href="https://checkvist.com/">Checkvist&lt;/a>, because that was the only system where I could get a good review workflow going and it is so adaptable because of its free form structure and keyboard centricity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The strange thing about GTD is the lack of focus on organizing what you do. Other systems will focus on prioritization, or assigning an &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; to the most important things. With Checkvist and GTD, once you organize your outcomes into actionable steps, and trust that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep juggling a million things, &lt;em>what you need to do becomes obvious.&lt;/em> What do I need to do today? Let me review my lists and the most important thing will pop out at me. I&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to all the rest by delegating them or saving them for later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is no need for priority codes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is no need to make it bold, or red, or flashing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system will work, and will tell you what to do. So get to work and get something done!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Review the Glue</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/review-the-glue/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/review-the-glue/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-review-the-glue.jpg" alt="Review the Glue" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It happened to me over and over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got sick and tired of being disorganized, of missing things, of not meeting my goals. &amp;ldquo;I am going to make a system.&amp;rdquo; I wrote everything I need to do down in a to-do list. I made sure my emails get processed correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And a few weeks later it was as if none of that ever happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why did this happen to me over and over again? Unlocking this secret was the key to actually implementing Getting Things Done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the key: &lt;strong>your system won&amp;rsquo;t work unless there is a place in it for you to review what you have processed.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about what we talked about earlier regarding your cluttered mind. You can&amp;rsquo;t tell your mind, &amp;ldquo;Stop thinking about that, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to it later&amp;rdquo; unless it can trust that you &lt;em>will&lt;/em> get to it later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think about the empty inbox. Are you &lt;em>really&lt;/em> going to put that important email in the @Actions folder if you don&amp;rsquo;t trust that you&amp;rsquo;ll keep it there? No. What you&amp;rsquo;ll do instead is keep the &lt;em>important&lt;/em> emails in your inbox because, really, you don&amp;rsquo;t have a review system in place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is where &lt;a href="https://checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a> really shines for me. I review items in Checkvist two ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Due Dates.&lt;/strong> If I need to get something done within a certain amount of time, I&amp;rsquo;ll set its due date. Every day I&amp;rsquo;ll check the &amp;ldquo;Due&amp;rdquo; screen (shortcut dd) and make sure I&amp;rsquo;m not missing anything. I&amp;rsquo;ll even set due dates on items that I &lt;em>commit&lt;/em> to doing by that time. For example no one is forcing me to read a book by August 1, but I put that as a due date to tell myself that is my goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Review Repeating Task.&lt;/strong> I set up a task called &amp;ldquo;Review [list]&amp;quot;* for every list I have that recurs as often as I need to review it. For example, I have a &amp;ldquo;Review money&amp;rdquo; task that recurs every Sunday and Wednesday with financial tasks on it. This is &amp;ldquo;Due&amp;rdquo; those days, so it will shows up in my due list that I&amp;rsquo;m checking from the above point. This way I only have to remember: every day look at my due list, which will tell me that I need to review my list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s my system. Other people can schedule meetings with themselves but that never worked for me. I need to review the areas of my life more regularly than that. And, as one who has tons of projects going on both personally and professionally, I have an even more complicated workflow that I&amp;rsquo;ll share in a future post regarding my reviews. But the above system I think works as well as anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bottom line is &lt;strong>make sure you have a system to review things, or else you don&amp;rsquo;t have a system.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hint: When you set up the review task, type &amp;ldquo;Review [lst:&amp;rdquo; and the list will pop up. Select the list and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to navigate to the list with the gg shortcut.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Process and Organize</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/process-and-organize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 08:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/process-and-organize/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-process-and-organize.jpg" alt="Process and Organize" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When I get home from work, I always go to my mailbox, take a few letters off of the top of my pile, open them, and put them back in the mailbox for later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Said no one ever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me though that is exactly what people do with email. This is insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order for you to have sanity in your life, you need a system that tells you, &amp;ldquo;What of my life have I put in my system to act on later, and what do I need to do so I can take action on them at the appropriate time?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the process and organize phase of Getting Things Done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how I do it: I go to each of the collection places I set up in the Collect Phase (physical inboxes, evernote, and email accounts), and follow this workflow:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Is this actionable? Is there anything I need to do with this at any conceivable point ever?&lt;/strong> If not I should delete it or store it for reference, but my experience with this item is GONE FOREVER. I will never see this again and it will not invade my life ever again.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Can I do it in two minutes or less?&lt;/strong> If I can then I do it. There&amp;rsquo;s no sense of creating a to-do list item for &amp;ldquo;Reply &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo; to email, &amp;ldquo;Are you coming tonight?&amp;rdquo; That would be silly. So keep it simple and get stuff out of the way that will just overload your system.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>What actions need to be taken for this to be done?&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not enough to say &amp;ldquo;Pool care&amp;rdquo; in your list. You have to have your list contain &lt;em>actions&lt;/em>, not just stuff. The action might be &amp;ldquo;Call the pool care company to schedule a filter cleaning.&amp;rdquo; Or it might even be &amp;ldquo;Search for a pool care company to help me with filter cleaning.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em>stuff&lt;/em>, it&amp;rsquo;s actions.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Add the actions into &lt;a href="http://www.checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong> I add whatever comes to my mind to finish what the item in my inbox represents into Checkvist. At first I recommend just having a &amp;ldquo;To Do&amp;rdquo; list in Checkvist and make it complicated later. You are dumping everything into that program because that is going to be your one-stop-shop for getting things done.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Archive the item.&lt;/strong> It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stay in the inbox. Archive it. Move it to a folder. Whatever. But you will never see this again unless you need to. In this system there is a clear distinction between &lt;em>what is processed&lt;/em> and &lt;em>what needs to be processed.&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Some more notes about this system:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I process my items from the top down, with few exceptions.&lt;/strong> This is important because in this workflow, you aren&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>doing&lt;/em> anything; you&amp;rsquo;re just processing your items. If you think, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get to this because it will take too long to do.&amp;rdquo; Well in that case, add the item to your list! I have an @Actions folder for these situations, so I know I can go to the email and write in a long response.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>My email inbox has zero items in it at some point every day.&lt;/strong> You think I&amp;rsquo;m crazy, I know. Believe me, once you do this workflow, you won&amp;rsquo;t ever go back. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told by people higher up than me that the email gets unbearable and that my workflow is impossible. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that it isn&amp;rsquo;t. I&amp;rsquo;ve already started forwarding emails to people on my team with short responses: &amp;ldquo;Yours&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Let me know if I need to do anything&amp;rdquo;. Most threads I&amp;rsquo;m copied on aren&amp;rsquo;t important. So I think that this should apply to everyone, and you &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to know what it is you need to get done in your life to have sanity in any way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The key to processing is translating &amp;ldquo;Stuff&amp;rdquo; into Actions.&lt;/strong> I can tell when someone really knows GTD by the items on their to-do list. &amp;ldquo;Set up blog&amp;rdquo; becomes &amp;ldquo;Buy domain on BlueHost&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Set up Genesis Theme on blog&amp;rdquo; and about fifty other things. How much faster do I burn through the fifty specific, actionable things, than my &amp;ldquo;Set up blog&amp;rdquo;? Honestly, for me &amp;ldquo;Set up Blog&amp;rdquo; goes nowhere, because &amp;ldquo;watch episode of Biggest Loser&amp;rdquo; is much more actionable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you think inbox zero will work in your situation? If not, why not?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Collect for Sanity</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/collect-for-sanity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 08:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/collect-for-sanity/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-collect-for-sanity.jpg" alt="Collect for Sanity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We are inundated with stuff. Stuff we need to act on. Stuff we need to remember. Stuff we need to worry about later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of us are stressed out with the amount of stuff in our lives. What to do about it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system outlined in Getting Things Done starts with collection: &lt;strong>there needs to be a system in your life for putting things that need to be processed later.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when you&amp;rsquo;re driving down the road and think of something, what is your system for collecting that for later? When you get a bill in the mail, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to pay it, what is your system for that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without this system &lt;strong>your mind will always be reminding you about everything.&lt;/strong> And you will never find peace. You will constantly be running from thing to thing and never able to say to yourself, &amp;ldquo;Relax, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to it later.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>Because your mind knows you won&amp;rsquo;t, because you don&amp;rsquo;t have a system for it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is where I collect things to be processed later:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Inbox at home.&lt;/strong> All my mail, bills, go here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Inbox at work.&lt;/strong> All my physical meeting notes, receipts go here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Evernote.&lt;/strong> all my digital meeting notes go here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Gmail Inbox.&lt;/strong> All my personal email goes here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Outlook Inbox.&lt;/strong> All my work email goes here&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If I want something to be processed in my life, they &lt;em>must&lt;/em> go here. If I put them here, I can forget about them, because I have a system to deal with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out a system for yet, but want to: daydreaming away from my computer. For this system to &lt;em>really&lt;/em> work, you have to empty your mind of all your stuff into a system. Anything that you ignore will come back over and over again. In the process phase you can say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to those things, but the key is that you tell your mind, &amp;ldquo;Forget about it. It&amp;rsquo;s in the system. Trust me.&amp;rdquo; This frees you up to &lt;em>truly focus.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right now I have no system for when I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in the car and realize, &amp;ldquo;I need to organize my closet.&amp;rdquo; Normally I forget about it by the time I arrive at my destination, and my mind gets stuck in a loop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The obvious solution to this would be my phone, but a lot of times it&amp;rsquo;s locked and difficult to get to. Another solution might be a portable recording device. I think I might experiment with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Has anyone come up with a good system for dealing with these times when you&amp;rsquo;re away from your inboxes or computers?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Planned Thinking</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/planned-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/planned-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-planned-thinking.jpg" alt="Planned Thinking" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In 2012 our efforts to add automated integrated testing to our central Point-of-Sale product were showing great results. We &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">were finding 20-40%&lt;/a> of all defects found in the software, many of which were found within hours of those defects being introduced by the developer. It took years of hard work to get to this place, and I was feeling good about our accomplishments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there was a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was running everything on adrenaline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was working extra hours, reacting to everything, and doing the next best thing to be done. But I was neglecting other really big things. It was review time and my boss wanted me to take my capabilities to another level. His advice was among the more valuable I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a review:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You need to stop at least once a week and think about things. You just need to stop and think&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My goodness he was right. And I knew better than this. Years ago I read the book Getting Things Done (GTD for short), which revolutionized how I did things. My problem was that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t developed a system for GTD principles. In the last year and a half I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on growing this area. I&amp;rsquo;m so excited to share with you my system, because I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great one that illustrates the concepts in GTD that I have only recently taken to the next level. If you read the book you get a good overview of the system. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe you really understand it until you see a system in practice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The center of my GTD system is &lt;a href="http://www.checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a>. I met the creator a Checkvist a little over two years ago at Jetbrains when I was discussing TeamCity with them. Kirill was taking notes in Checkvist and copied me on it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the tool seriously until after the review at the start of 2013. This tool is the single biggest reason for my success in the last 18 months. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine life without Checkvist. In fact, this blog is managed through Checkvist and helped me create a workable plan that I could execute on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are five phases of Getting Things Done that I will cover in detail in four posts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Collect:&lt;/strong> how do you take the things in your life and put them in places that you know you&amp;rsquo;ll get to when you have time?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Process/Organize:&lt;/strong> Now that you have time, how do you take the things you have collected and put them in a system that you trust you will come back to later?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Review:&lt;/strong> what is your system for coming back to the things you&amp;rsquo;ve put in your system?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Do:&lt;/strong> when you&amp;rsquo;re going to do something, what is your system for knowing what is best?&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet checked out Checkvist. I encourage you to do so and follow along in the next couple of weeks to get yourself organized. I&amp;rsquo;m here to help!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Growth Got Me Organized and Productive</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/productivity/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-productivity.jpg" alt="Productivity" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If you keep learning and growing every day over the course of many years, you will be astounded by how far it will take you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>As I read this in the introduction of John Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1599953668/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1599953668&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20">12 Indisputable Laws of Growth&lt;/a>, I realized how &lt;strong>low my expectations were&lt;/strong>. At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t believe Maxwell. My focus at the time was more on keeping it together and making the &amp;ldquo;next logical step&amp;rdquo; than on reaching a destination I didn&amp;rsquo;t previously think was possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I took Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s advice and have focused on growth ever since. I&amp;rsquo;ve read books. I got a mentor. I pressed into my work and made things happen. I built my team so it isn&amp;rsquo;t just me anymore having to do the major things; it is&amp;quot;we&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>After two years of intentional growth, I can see Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s wisdom firsthand.&lt;/strong> I have grown so much in these two years and feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve only begun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The biggest area of growth is with my &lt;strong>productivity and organization&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other day I reviewed everything that was going on and took an action on one of my many projects. I went to talk with person, who was on the phone, so I stopped to say hi to a friend of mine. He was questioning out loud how much my team had taken on and how it seemed impossible. Two years ago it would have been impossible. But now it is working, because I have focused on growing as a leader and because I have focused on creating a system within which I can manage what needs to happen in my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week I have six different projects at work going at the same time (and one project itself has three different subprojects). At home we are going through an amazing amount of change that is planned based on our newfound desire for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/" title="Achievable Contentment">contentment&lt;/a>. On the surface it feels like I have five different jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortunately, I have a secret weapon I use to keep my sanity: &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://www.checkvist.com">Checkvist&lt;/a> and the Getting Things Done methodology.&lt;/strong> This will be the focus of the next couple of weeks. But for now, open your mind to the possibility that if you intentionally grow over time, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to do things you previously thought weren&amp;rsquo;t even possible. All that&amp;rsquo;s needed is that you start.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>