<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>books on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/books/</link><description>Recent content in books on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 08:00:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Phoenix Project Book Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-phoenix-project-book-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2015 08:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-phoenix-project-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-phoenix-project-book-review.jpg" alt="Phoenix Project" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>As I&amp;rsquo;ve looked into devops more and more over the past few months, the book &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1AinIdB">The Phoenix Project&lt;/a> has come up over and over. I finally bought it when Matt Stratton at chef basically insisted on it in &lt;a href="http://www.mattstratton.com/tech/devops">his very awesome reading list&lt;/a> to ramp yourself up on devops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been into fiction very much, but over the summer I read &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zx9aT7">A Man in Full&lt;/a> as a means of integrating stoicism into my own philosophy. That book lit up my imagination and helped me absorb the stoic themes in a way that would be difficult had I just read an outline of stoicism. I was awakened to the reality of how fiction can transform your mind deeply by awakening all aspects of the mind during learning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I was very excited to read the book. And the book did not disappoint in changing my outlook on my own career and what is possible for those around me. It taught me a few basic lessons that I believe will transform my behavior in the future:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Have a respect for the system.&lt;/strong> Up until I read this book I treated a inefficient system like it was garbage. Let&amp;rsquo;s get rid of the inefficiency! This is dumb! What I realized by reading the book is that in order for you to effectively and profitably change a system, you must have a respect and understanding of why it is the way it is. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know why it is this way, you can realize that it is an inefficient system, but you will not effectively change it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">Measure, Measure, Measure&lt;/a>.&lt;/strong> The main character in the book has a great respect for measurement. People say you can&amp;rsquo;t manage what you don&amp;rsquo;t measure. I think that can be taken too far, but there is a reality in it: if I can&amp;rsquo;t measure the reality of the system, it will be very difficult for me to (1) convince people that a more efficient change is needed, and (2) know that the changes I am making are having their desired effect.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Take a Breath and Count to 2.&lt;/strong> One of the nice things about the book that taught me a lesson is when the main character interacts with various antagonists, who are obviously being reckless, dumb, and incendiary, the main character will take a breath and count to 2. Then respond. And when he responds, it&amp;rsquo;s with facts and an attitude of doing what&amp;rsquo;s best for everyone. I desperately want to exhibit this kind of tact and patience. I get so passionate about my ideas that I can forget to have patience, be calm, and move the ball forward.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Find the Bottleneck Constraint.&lt;/strong> In the book there is a legendary character named Brent. Brent can do everything. He can fix problems in seconds that everyone has spent days trying to understand. He knows why this server is the way it is, and the answer lies in activities from 2002. Brent has everyone asking him for everything and the business is at it&amp;rsquo;s knees due to Brent&amp;rsquo;s inability to clone himself into fifty other people. In the book, the main focus was on getting Brent isolated and his work properly documented, prioritized, and managed. Brent remained a hugely valuable member of the team, but they couldn&amp;rsquo;t grow until his workload was under control. And once Brent had his priorities under control, he was able to do some special things for the company.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed the Phoenix Project and recommend it to anyone wanting to lead change in their organization using lean principles. It reaches the reader in a way that a nonfiction book can&amp;rsquo;t: you can feel the tension. You drop the F-bombs right there with the reader. You feel the desperation as the core concepts come to life. And therefore when you face similar situations, you have a whole new world of awesome manufacturing theory available to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This book was one of the best software-related books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. If you want to be a leader, please get a copy and read it. Then invite me to lunch and let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it; maybe we can change the world together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Programming Ruby (Pickaxe) Book Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/programming-ruby-pickaxe-book-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 08:00:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/programming-ruby-pickaxe-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-programming-ruby-pickaxe-book-review.jpg" alt="Ruby Pickaxe" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When I started &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/">learning Chef&lt;/a> in earnest I realized quickly that my need to know what was happening was leading me to need to dive into a book on Ruby and figure out what all the magic I was seeing in Chef was really about. Chef has an amazing way of being usable for those who don&amp;rsquo;t know much Ruby, but I&amp;rsquo;m the curious type that just needs to know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started out with &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/13QZz1v">The Ruby Programming Language&lt;/a> but found it to be too much of a reference work that basically stated facts about the language instead of walking the reader through the learning process. I was delighted to find &lt;a href="http://ruby-doc.com/docs/ProgrammingRuby/">Programming Ruby&lt;/a> to be exactly that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was able to get through the book in a few days. It starts you out with objects, which for Ruby is the right place to start out. As I&amp;rsquo;m teaching my son how to program, the concept of objects is very easy for him to pick up. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to start with primitives, then control flow, then objects for people to learn. Learning is less logically structured than that. People don&amp;rsquo;t think like computers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Each chapter in the book is about fifteen to twenty minutes of time investment and walks you through an example that you can easily code on your own. I find that when learning these things, I can&amp;rsquo;t just read it and know it. I need to &lt;em>do&lt;/em> something as well. This book did a great job at keeping me engaged with my ruby interpreter as well as with my mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In November I set a goal to be working with Ruby every day by February. This book did a great job at making the goal possible. It demystified how Chef was doing its magic, but it has done so much more. It has opened me up to a whole new world of possibilities by quickly being able to script a solution to a problem without having to go through all the hoops of a statically typed programming language. While I still love C# and will use it for certain problems, Ruby is not a part of my life, thanks partly to this excellent book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Customizing Chef Book Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/customizing-chef-book-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 08:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/customizing-chef-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-customizing-chef-book-review.jpg" alt="Customizing Chef" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When I was stuck trying to understand simple concepts about Chef, I bought two books: &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1wHMEZb">Learning Chef&lt;/a> (read the review) and &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1Ajtt8G">Customizing Chef&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://jonliv.es/">Jon Cowie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning Chef gave me the basic concepts, but Customizing Chef gave me the deep understanding I needed to evaluate the tool for my large, complicated organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the closed-source Microsoft world, you figure out what the thing can do and just accept it. The book opened my eyes that Chef allows me to use a skill (reading code) that I&amp;rsquo;ve built up for over ten years. This leads to a much deeper understanding of how it works than just &amp;ldquo;trust us this feature does X&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s not the best thing about the book though. The thing I appreciated the most was the ability to learn from the author who implemented a world class deployment solution for &lt;a href="https://codeascraft.com/">Etsy&lt;/a> using chef. The examples he provided were real world. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a textbook exposition on chef. You could tell that this was the real deal. Learning from him in this way reinforced the idea that chef was something I could implement in my complicated organization and that with every problem that arises I have options because of chef&amp;rsquo;s extensibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The author did a wonderful job at explaining that extensibility with examples at every level. I learned how to customize chef&amp;rsquo;s notification customizations, cookbooks, and even knife itself. Every explanation of a customization didn&amp;rsquo;t merely explain it; it started with the code and took the reader through a series of examples to build up understanding of the customization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Customizing Chef isn&amp;rsquo;t for someone who is just starting chef. For that I would recommend the tutorials or the book Learning Chef. For someone who is tasked with implementing it in a complicated organization or someone who has been using it for months and has come across some scaling challenges, this book is a life-saver.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning Chef Book Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-learning-chef-book-review.jpg" alt="Learning Chef Book Review" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A couple of months ago I found myself drowning in the learning curve that was &lt;a href="http://chef.io">chef&lt;/a>. I had great support from them, but I&amp;rsquo;m the type of person who needs to know a technology in order to appropriately evaluate it. I could tell that chef was a nice technology, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went through &lt;a href="https://learn.chef.io/">the tutorials&lt;/a> but they weren&amp;rsquo;t adequate for me to understand the solution. Then I found the book &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1Ajqayd">Learning Chef&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning Chef is an excellent first step in understanding the chef universe in order to get started on the right foot with the tool. I absolutely loved the tutorial, incremental approach that &lt;a href="http://misheska.com/">the&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://sethvargo.com/">authors&lt;/a> take to go from running a recipe on your own machine to running tests on locally available virtual machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which leads me to my other pleasant surprise of this book: it lays out the techniques you can use with chef in order to test what you&amp;rsquo;re doing so you know that it works. That is what separates chef from many other solutions I&amp;rsquo;ve seen: &lt;a href="http://kitchen.ci/">they bake testing into the process itself&lt;/a>. If you&amp;rsquo;re going to treat infrastructure as code then you &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to test it as a part of your deployment pipeline. Fortunately this introductory book doesn&amp;rsquo;t skimp on this core aspect of chef.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third great thing about this book is that it is very approachable to those of us who have built their careers programming in the Windows environment. Every command has a hint at what you would do on a windows box. This really increased my comfort level with learning chef by allowing me to learn it in &lt;em>my own&lt;/em> development environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book is not for people who want a quick, few hour understanding of chef to get up and running. For example if I bring a new team on board with Chef, I probably won&amp;rsquo;t hand them this book; I&amp;rsquo;ll probably do a couple of day class with them to teach them the basics. If they&amp;rsquo;re the type of person (like me) who wants to dig deeper though and learns by doing, this book is a fabulous step in becoming proficient at using chef.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Focus with the Amazon Kindle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-focus-with-the-amazon-kindle.jpg" alt="Focus with the Kindle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/" title="Life is Art">focusing on what matters&lt;/a> lately by &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">making good choices&lt;/a> with how and what you consume. Some things are just a complete waste of time like the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">local news&lt;/a>. Other things have a good alternative, like &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/">reading the Economist&lt;/a> instead of going to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/escaping-with-the-news/">news sites&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I wrote last time, though, in this mobile world that isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. You have to make sure your smartphone is serving you and not enslaving you. And beyond that I&amp;rsquo;m convinced &lt;strong>to lead a life of growth and meaning you need to read.&lt;/strong> Probably more than you are right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So how do we do that? The solutions that come to mind immediately are: on our smartphone, a paper book, or a tablet. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about a better way to read books: through the Amazon Kindle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few years back &lt;a href="http://www.chrisdikes.com/">my friend Chris&lt;/a> asked me what I thought about the Kindle, and my opinion to him as of July 16, 2010 was: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>It seems like having a book would be better.&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo; Well, thankfully Chris didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to my awful advice and bought one, told me about it, changed my mind, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s so great about the Kindle:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Distractionless:&lt;/strong> yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a feature and not a bug. I like it that there aren&amp;rsquo;t pop ups telling me all about the emails I&amp;rsquo;m not reading or the cool Facebook posts that I need to be looking into. I&amp;rsquo;m here to read. The Kindle helps me read.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Battery Life:&lt;/strong> I don&amp;rsquo;t have to be preoccupied with powering the stupid thing while I&amp;rsquo;m using it. I can read. I have to charge it every once and a while. It&amp;rsquo;s not like the power sucking smartphone or tablet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Position Independent:&lt;/strong> this may seem small to some, but I like reading while I&amp;rsquo;m laying down. And I get comfortable holding a book in one hand. Then I read fast and get to the other side of the book. So I have to move to read the other section. It seems like a small thing, and admittedly a first-world problem, but I love how I can read the Kindle with one hand laying on the same side for as long as it is comfortable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sleep Friendly Lighting:&lt;/strong> I have the Kindle paperwhite that doesn&amp;rsquo;t blast light into my eyes and keep me up. I can do a little nighttime reading with a very small amount of light. It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t distract my wife.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Borrower Capable:&lt;/strong> I have learned to take advantage of my library&amp;rsquo;s borrower privileges on the Kindle. This is easy once you figure it out. I do admit to buying more books than I would have before, but I think that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing as long as I read them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Keeps Your Place:&lt;/strong> I pick up the book and read exactly where I left off. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it. I just go.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Read More:&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve read much more than before. If I&amp;rsquo;m interested in a topic, I can get a book on that topic and read through it quickly while I have a passion and interest in the book.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Portable:&lt;/strong> I admit to not doing it very often, but if I want to, I can read on my smartphone or even my computer to continue my reading.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I highly recommend going for a Kindle. You need to read to meet your goals, and in my mind there is no better way to do so than with the Kindle.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>