<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>strategy on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/strategy/</link><description>Recent content in strategy on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 08:02:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solve Problems by Isolating Them</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/solve-problems-by-isolating-them/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 08:02:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/solve-problems-by-isolating-them/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-solve-problems-by-isolating-them.jpg" alt="Isolate Problems" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out there is a [My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out there is a &lt;a href="http://www.legolanddiscoverycenter.com/dallasfw/">Legoland Discovery center&lt;/a> nearby. The other day they went to a birthday party there. The kids had an absolute blast. Legos, legos everywhere. It was totally awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also turns out that we have a &lt;a href="https://www.sixflags.com/overtexas">Six Flags&lt;/a> nearby. Fast roller coasters. Every amusement park craziness imaginable. We spent last summer doing that, and let me tell you, mom and I really got sick of it. But the kids absolutely loved it. They even wanted to do it again this summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So DFW area: lego land: check. amusement park: check. &lt;a href="http://california.legoland.com/">lego amusement park&lt;/a>? That will be a trip to California and $4000 please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how &lt;strong>the solution to a problem gets a lot more complicated and a lot more expensive when you combine it with another problem.&lt;/strong> I come across this a lot at work. I ruthlessly go through a project and eliminate anything that isn&amp;rsquo;t needed, because I want to ship it as quickly as possible and I know every little thing just adds to the time and complexity and makes the project that much more unrealistic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So are we going to the LegoLand California Resort? If we do it, it will be with [My kids have been drawn into the world of Legos. They love &lt;a href="http://www.lego.com/en-us/ninjago">Ninjago&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1490017/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Problem Owner is Solution Owner</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/problem-owner-is-solution-owner/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 08:07:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/problem-owner-is-solution-owner/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-problem-owner-is-solution-owner.jpg" alt="Problem Owner" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The room was standing room only. I was playing &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o1tj2zJ2Wvg">Welcome to the Jungle&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; as loud as my company-issued laptop would play. There was a considerable buzz in the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/speaking/">speaking at a conference session&lt;/a> entitled &amp;ldquo;The New Diagnostic Utility.&amp;rdquo; This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a Get Rich Quick with Flipping Real Estate conference session. This was The Diagnostic Utility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What was so jarring about this experience was the lackluster response I had gotten to this tool up until this point. The idea came &lt;a href="www.linkedin.com/in/nicolemillspmp">from a colleague&lt;/a> that dealt with diagnosing environmental issues in sites. She and her team were excited about it. I understood the need. But no one else seemed to be enthused. Why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The conference I was at was full of people who install our software at restaurants all over North America. They had issues that needed to be diagnosed. The title &amp;ldquo;The Diagnostic Utility&amp;rdquo; was translated to them like &amp;ldquo;Save Yourself Hours of Time Making Sure You Did Everything Right&amp;rdquo;. This was the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/safety-net/">safety net&lt;/a> they needed. Their attendance and enthusiasm confirmed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is probably the most valuable lesson I&amp;rsquo;ve learned this year: &lt;strong>a solution is only effective when it is &lt;em>in the hands&lt;/em> of the one that has a problem.&lt;/strong> Not the one that &lt;em>knows&lt;/em> about the problem. Not even the one who is &lt;em>losing money&lt;/em> on the problem. &lt;strong>The one who has the problem.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when your kid doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to get to school on time, the solution is waking up earlier, but it&amp;rsquo;s only effective when your kid &lt;em>wants&lt;/em> to be on time to school to avoid a consequence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a project is proposed but the people who own that process don&amp;rsquo;t believe there&amp;rsquo;s a problem, you don&amp;rsquo;t do the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you&amp;rsquo;re getting frustrated that a customer isn&amp;rsquo;t responsive enough to your solution, perhaps they don&amp;rsquo;t see there is a problem and perhaps you need to find another customer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was the case for The New Diagnostic Utility. Once I found the right audience, everything fell into place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surprise</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/surprise/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-surprise.jpg" alt="Surprise" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/">the last post&lt;/a> I wrote about a mistake I made where I focused too much on The Grand Vision and not enough on solving small problems. At the time, I felt that accomplishing The Grand Vision was going to be awesome and would save the world, and would mean that there would be a parade for my entire team, and cheering, and wonderful speeches given for us all. It will be glorious, except, now I realize I totally screwed it up:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I left no room for surprise.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Surprise is when someone&amp;rsquo;s expectation is suddenly shifted into a totally new place in an instant. &lt;strong>Surprise has a way of changing the game immediately and causing your competitors to scramble.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When your competition expects an outcome, they have time to spin it as no big deal. Your flaws (and there will be flaws if you ship it) will be the surprises, not the big game-changing outcome that you created. People adjust to the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; reality over a period of months, when in fact the reality hasn&amp;rsquo;t even changed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This lesson will be central to everything I do for the rest of my life. If I am trying to create an important outcome that makes a difference, I should focus &lt;em>first&lt;/em> on creating the outcome. &lt;strong>If it is as important as I think it is, surprise will be my ally.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Grand Vision</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 08:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-grand-vision.jpg" alt="The Grand Vision" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Late last year I started a new project that was dedicated to improving our delivery process and tools. I spent a few weeks talking to people throughout our organization about what the problems were and how we can best address them. And then I came up with &lt;strong>The Grand Vision.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grand Vision was an awesome elevator speech where I drew quadrants and arrows, talked about the main problems I was seeing and how to bring them together into one, totally awesome, unified structure that Would Save The World.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the meetings, a key leader I respect said to me, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s ambitious.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thanks,&amp;rdquo; I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a complement&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lesson I learned is that it&amp;rsquo;s important to map out the process and see how what you&amp;rsquo;re doing fits into the entire goal. &lt;em>But it&amp;rsquo;s also important to solve problems immediately that have a quick return on investment.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This kind of thinking happens all the time:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ambitious&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Should be&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get rid of all sugar in my house and go GLUTEN FREE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>On Fridays I eat donuts that people bring in the office. In June I&amp;rsquo;m not going to eat any.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a gym membership with personal training and wake up every day at 5:30AM and get RIPPED!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to bike anywhere within 5 miles of my house and do 20 pushups a night&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>We are going to a full week marriage conference in Aspen, Colorado so we can get our marriage back on track&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Let&amp;rsquo;s go on a date and not look at our phones&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to avoid the really tough problems in front of you by dreaming a big dream.&lt;/strong> I think many of us like to think if we can&amp;rsquo;t do it all, then why do it at all? The real battle is won when we drop that all or nothing thinking and get something done&amp;hellip;&lt;strong>today&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When have you let the grand vision distract you from what really needed to be done right then and there?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>