<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>smartphone on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/smartphone/</link><description>Recent content in smartphone on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 08:00:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/smartphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sanitize Your Smartphone with Republic Wireless</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 08:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless.jpg" alt="Sanitize Smartphone" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The invention of the iPhone will probably be one of the key technological events of my lifetime. It changed the game from quirky Blackberry kind-of-phones, to a new experience that delivered a whole set of new capabilities in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. It has changed &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">the businesses I serve&lt;/a> and will continue to change our lives for years to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I finally got an iPhone it took over my life. This coincided with the birth of my children, so I spent a lot of time on the iPhone while they were at the park, or sleeping, or messing around at our house.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Then I realized that I will never get those moments back.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I realized that the promise of convenience and greater efficiency does not line up with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">my personal goals&lt;/a> because my personal goals are to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">live a life of meaning, love, and connection&lt;/a>, especially with my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To put it more simply, &lt;strong>I was on my phone and ignoring my family.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What to do about this? I considered going away from a smartphone. That didn&amp;rsquo;t seem possible because there were times where it really did serve me. I tried to make a few rules like, &amp;ldquo;Stop ignoring my children&amp;rdquo;, but those didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work when the siren song of Facebook and email came singing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, I was spending over a thousand dollars a year on this habit that wasn&amp;rsquo;t serving me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Then I learned about a better way: Republic Wireless.&lt;/strong> With Republic Wireless, I bought a phone for $300* and now spend $10 a month on my mobile phone. I get data through Wi-Fi, which, by the way, exists at home and at work. I don&amp;rsquo;t get data on the way home from work. If I&amp;rsquo;m traveling, I get the option to change to the $25 a month plan that has data. I can even change it back to the $10 plan when I get home and only pay for the $25 plan prorated for the amount of days I used it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means that I don&amp;rsquo;t instinctively go for the phone when I&amp;rsquo;m out and about. It&amp;rsquo;s a tool; it&amp;rsquo;s not my master. It also means if I need it to direct me somewhere I can type in directions before I leave when I&amp;rsquo;m on Wi-Fi, and the smartphone will get me there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like I have the best of both worlds. Combine that with my $10/month landline, I now have no excuse to be on my phone…ever. &lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s an accessory. It&amp;rsquo;s not my whole life.&lt;/strong> Now I can live with the best elements of it and leave the rest alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in freeing your life from the insane addiction from the smartphone, you can get $10 off of Republic Wireless (as well as give me $10 off on my bill) by going &lt;a href="http://rwshar.es/6lhy">here&lt;/a>. Enjoy!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can get them even cheaper for $99 for an off-contract phone. Do the math and you&amp;rsquo;ll save a bundle while being able to spend less time on your phone. It&amp;rsquo;s a win-win!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>