<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>workout on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/workout/</link><description>Recent content in workout on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 08:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/workout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mornings</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/mornings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/mornings/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-mornings.jpg" alt="Mornings" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>On the bad mornings, I begin by rolling over and checking my phone. I cycle through &lt;a href="http://www.espndallas.com">ESPN Dallas&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.wfaa.com">WFAA&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com">CNN&lt;/a>, and look at my &lt;a href="http://feedly.com/">feedly feed&lt;/a>, personal and work email. The work email in particular, since I work with Czechs who are well into their day, causes me to start thinking about work. My mind races to the world&amp;rsquo;s problems, the world&amp;rsquo;s drama, and problems I&amp;rsquo;ll need to solve in a couple of hours that began a half a world away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thirty minutes later I get out of bed, make a breakfast, talk to my kids, and then I am late for work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the good mornings, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/sanitize-your-smartphone-with-republic-wireless/">my phone is in another room&lt;/a>. I wake up, do a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shovelglove">14 minute workout&lt;/a>, read a little on the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/">Kindle&lt;/a> or the &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-economist-keeps-it-real/">Economist&lt;/a>, have some time for meditation/introspection. I think about my life as a whole and how I&amp;rsquo;m contributing to my goals today in realistic ways. I think about how I want to love and serve others in very real and tangible ways. I eat breakfast, and get to work on time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have as much time on the good mornings as the bad mornings. The key is being intentional and staying off the phone.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>