<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>management on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/management/</link><description>Recent content in management on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 08:00:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kanban Standup Meetings: A Way Out of Standup Hell?</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/kanban-standup-meetings-a-way-out-of-standup-hell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/kanban-standup-meetings-a-way-out-of-standup-hell/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-kanban-standup-meetings-a-way-out-of-standup-hell.jpg" alt="Kanban Standup" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In every Agile project, you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to have a daily standup meeting to facilitate communication and collective ownership. Intentions are always great at the beginning, but for me they have always descended into a tolerable mess. Can the &lt;a href="defining-the-kanban-input-queue/">Kanban method&lt;/a> teach us anything about how to do them better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.mountaingoatsoftware.com/agile/scrum/daily-scrum">If you&amp;rsquo;re following the Scrum process&lt;/a>, the meeting should last 10-15 minutes and everyone should go around the room talking about what they accomplished yesterday, what they plan on doing today, and what, if anything, is blocking them. Every software development methodology I have read tells you to do them; I&amp;rsquo;ve even seen people have success with them on waterfall projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone is excited about doing the standups correctly, and then someone gets tired and &lt;a href="http://www.batimes.com/articles/seven-common-mistakes-with-the-daily-stand-up-meeting.html">everyone sits down&lt;/a>. Eventually what tends to happen on my team is that everyone reports to &lt;em>me&lt;/em>, the leader, what they intend on doing today and I give them about 10-30 seconds of comment to help them along. While I&amp;rsquo;m engaging with each person, the others are thinking about other things. There is no collective ownership.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is by no means a functional standup meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What to do about this? &lt;a href="http://www.djaa.com/">David Anderson&lt;/a> has some suggestions in his &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1yaebV5">Kanban book&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The need to go around the room and ask the three questions is obviated by the card wall. The wall contains all the information about who is working on what. Attendees who come regularly can see what has changed since yesterday and whether something is blocked or is not visually evident. So standups take a different format with a Kanban system. &lt;strong>The focus is on the flow of work.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve done these types before, and it is very effective. The question is now, &amp;ldquo;What needs to happen today to move things forward?&amp;rdquo; and everyone participates. This becomes an obvious group exercise, not a task reporting meeting to management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So in the new standup, you start with the board on the right side and talk about every card. The team collectively identifies the actions taken that day to move it forward. Items that are blocked are highlighted and the team plans for a course of action. While it is driven by a leader, the person driving it can change and everyone is engaged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also this way of doing standups scales well. Anderson writes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Daniel Vacanti ran a successful standup with more than 50 people at a project at Corbis in 2007 where, despite the large size of the team, the meeting was completed in around 10 minutes every morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A ten minute meeting with fifty people; that&amp;rsquo;s amazing! I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to getting my standups out of standup hell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The One Metric that Matters</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 08:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-one-metric-that-matters/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-one-metric-that-matters.jpg" alt="Metric that Matters" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The more I measure &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">the more successful I am&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve known this for a while, but I realize that the lack of measurement is still the thing that is holding my career back. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written about how measurement is key to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">The Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a> of using the scientific method to find innovation in your organization. So I&amp;rsquo;m hooked with this idea, but I desperately want to implement it in a good way. I want to have a breakthrough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;em>Lean Enterprise&lt;/em> book cites the &lt;em>Lean Analytics&lt;/em> book concept of &lt;strong>The One Metric That Matters (OMTM):&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>OMTM is a single metric that we prioritize as the most important to drive decisions depending on the stage of our product lifecycle and our business model…We focus on One Metric that Matters to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Answer the most pressing question we have by linking it to the assumptions in the hypothesis we want to test&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create focus, conversation, and thought to identify problems and simulate improvement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide transparency and a shared understanding across the team and wider organization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support a culture of experimentation by basing it on rates or ratios, not averages or totals, relevant to our historical data set&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When I started out my current project in 2008, my boss for a very short time was &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeff-hughes/3/720/3a3">Jeff Hughes&lt;/a>, who is a genius at innovating software. The project I was doing was related to software quality, so Jeff gave me a metric for the first year: make defect containment go up, as defined by the percentage of software defects found inside the company related to the software defects found by our customers. He gave me the one metric that matters, and with that direction I was able to take the project in the direction it needed to go. At first we thought that we were going to stick with testing just customer situations, but we ended up having a mixture of customer situations and vanilla, or regression, situations. Without that &amp;ldquo;one metric that matters&amp;rdquo;, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the freedom to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fast forward to last year, I started a project to improve the installation experience for all of our products that get installed in restaurants. Everyone seemed to want this to be better so I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop and create the one metric that matters. I rushed ahead and started on the solution. My one metric that mattered internally was lowered cycle time from a release to working software. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to define where we were before I started, and how my changes had improved the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This led to a lot of unnecessary drama. People would question &lt;em>why&lt;/em> we were taking a particular approach. People would question whether an improvement was warranted in the first place (even after agreeing that it was warranted before). It&amp;rsquo;s easy to point fingers and talk about how people don&amp;rsquo;t understand or care, but they do understand and they do care. I just didn&amp;rsquo;t take the time to create a metric that would measure what outcome I&amp;rsquo;m trying to create.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is not a lesson &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">I will soon forget&lt;/a>. I hope that I will be able to fundamentally transform my approach to include measurement as one of the key aspects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progression of Responsibility</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-progression-of-responsibility.jpg" alt="Progression of Responsibility" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>While reading &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zxdulv">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, I&amp;rsquo;m coming up with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/">a lot of great ideas&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">improvements for my organization&lt;/a>. Much of the book so far has been about how to properly execute portfolio management within an enterprise to make sure that (1) you maximize ROI, and (2) you don&amp;rsquo;t manage your existing proven products with an investment horizon of this year or this quarter the same way that you would manage innovation products that have a longer investment horizon. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something occurred to me though. In order to gain entry into the higher level strategic decisions, one must first master the lower level ones. Here&amp;rsquo;s a progression I can see, that I wish I knew about ten years ago:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Personal Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you take on work in an efficient, organized way? Do you have a system for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/" title="Getting Things Done Action Plan">getting things done&lt;/a>, a system for communicating with others, for follow-up, for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">what to do when things get difficult&lt;/a>? Do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/" title="Two Questions You Should Ask About Your Commitments">when you&amp;rsquo;re overcommitting&lt;/a>?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Planning Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you understand why we are doing what we are doing on this project? Do you measure things in terms of how they will profit your company or on some other, less meaningful way? Do you have a way to create value for your stakeholders quickly by strategically prioritizing certain things over others? Do you know what the short-term and long-term risks to the product and what can be done about them?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Management Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/" title="Measure for Reality">how to measure success&lt;/a>? Have you linked the measurement to profitability of the company? Are you able to iteratively create improvements to measurements in a fluid, changing situation? Are people motivated by your leadership and understand the parameters that you&amp;rsquo;ve set out that measures your team&amp;rsquo;s success?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Executive Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> are you able to create profitability for the various products in your portfolio in a way that respects their lifecycle? Are your established, older products increasing in quality and customer satisfaction? Have your newer innovative products succeeded in creating new markets, as measured by appropriate metrics? Has your team leadership received the appropriate amount of direction (not too detailed to constrain innovation and not too broad to create chaos)? Have you had innovation experiments that have failed in the past three months, that had minimal investment yet provided a valuable lesson for the leadership team?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Right now I&amp;rsquo;m at #3. It&amp;rsquo;s fun reading about #4 in the book, but I do realize the trap of trying to live in a place that is beyond your current capability:** If you live in a later stage than you&amp;rsquo;re at right now, you end up ignoring the key elements that are needed to progress to the next stage.** So I can start thinking a lot about portfolio management or how we would manage innovative products differently than our established products. But if I get too caught up in that, I avoid the reality for me right now: I need to find a measurement of success that leads to profitability of my company for every project that I&amp;rsquo;m doing, be able to communicate that to others, and manage its improvement with a team. That will be my focus over the next year or so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone comes to me about how we need to do a better job planning yet don&amp;rsquo;t have an established workflow for how they manage their own work, I quickly get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone wants to be a manager of a group but can&amp;rsquo;t see what that group is doing strategically and the trade-offs that exist in the group, I get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to master your current responsibilities before you can progress to others.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>