<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>now on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/now/</link><description>Recent content in now on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 08:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/now/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Escaping</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 08:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/escaping/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-escaping.jpg" alt="Escaping" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I get home &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">from work&lt;/a> and am daydreaming about a feature I need to add to my software as my son tells me about &lt;a href="https://minecraft.net/">Minecraft&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finally have a few moments of free time and spend them reading about movie stars and wars on the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At work I have something really important to work on but I read the latest tech news instead, and I get involved in a long conversation with a colleague about office politics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is going on here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think it&amp;rsquo;s simple: &lt;strong>real life is lived right here and right now with the choices you make.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s not at work when you&amp;rsquo;re at home. It&amp;rsquo;s not with movie stars. It&amp;rsquo;s not in office politics. It&amp;rsquo;s not even on Facebook. It&amp;rsquo;s in your own choices &lt;em>right now.&lt;/em>****&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our problem is that many of us don&amp;rsquo;t like or are scared of the choices we have in front of us. If we were really honest with ourselves we&amp;rsquo;d have to admit that we just don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with our &lt;em>true&lt;/em> lives. We really want an escape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I run away from my present choices and go somewhere else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At home I go to work or to the lives of famous people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At work I move away from important decisions to politics or the unimportant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When relating to others I am preoccupied with my Facebook or Twitter status.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or I keep thinking about how everything will be better in the future once my plans come to fruition.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do you want a &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">beautiful life&lt;/a> of meaning and purpose?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stop running away from it.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To do this you&amp;rsquo;ll need to set up a lifestyle that blocks out those distractions that keep you &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">from what truly matters&lt;/a>. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to figure out how to ignore the news. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to figure out how to stop checking your phone like a crack addict every five minutes. &lt;strong>You&amp;rsquo;ll have to learn how to live a life that is present in what is happening &lt;em>right now&lt;/em> in &lt;em>your life&lt;/em>.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the journey I&amp;rsquo;m on, and I&amp;rsquo;m by no means perfect at it. We&amp;rsquo;re in this together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are you running from? And what are you using to distract yourself from what really matters?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>