<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>time management on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/time-management/</link><description>Recent content in time management on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 08:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/time-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You Have Time</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/you-have-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 08:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/you-have-time/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-you-have-time.jpg" alt="You Have Time" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m taking a break from &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/rubbernecking-with-the-locals/">my hatred of all things&lt;/a> news to take a step back and write about &lt;em>why&lt;/em> I&amp;rsquo;ve been so negative in these recent posts about the news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not against entertainment. I think it serves a valuable role in our lives. I like watching a football game or hearing about things that are none of my business. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I just no longer fool myself into thinking that it matters.&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s just entertainment. This isn&amp;rsquo;t life or death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I read books so I can grow into a better person, that takes time. When I &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/">ride my bike&lt;/a> to work every day instead of driving a car, that takes time. When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/focus-with-the-amazon-kindle/">I read&lt;/a>, spend time with my family, volunteer, that all takes time. And our first reaction to changing things up in order &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">to live out our values is&lt;/a>: I don&amp;rsquo;t have time. I disagree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You have time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I said that right. &lt;strong>You have tons of time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you don&amp;rsquo;t have time to consume the news.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you never watch TV for anything ever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you don&amp;rsquo;t get a full night&amp;rsquo;s sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not having time means that you never do anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve feeding or sheltering your family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You have time.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My time waster is the news. I used to spend literally hours a day reading and thinking about it. Yours might be different. Whatever it is, see it for what it is, put things in perspective, and focus on what really matters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is not: When will I have enough time to do what matters?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The question is: &lt;strong>When will I stop doing what doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter so I&amp;rsquo;ll have enough time to do what matters?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That mindset change will change your life.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>