<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning Curve on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/learning-curve/</link><description>Recent content in Learning Curve on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 08:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/learning-curve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Customizing Chef Book Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/customizing-chef-book-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 08:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/customizing-chef-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-customizing-chef-book-review.jpg" alt="Customizing Chef" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When I was stuck trying to understand simple concepts about Chef, I bought two books: &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1wHMEZb">Learning Chef&lt;/a> (read the review) and &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1Ajtt8G">Customizing Chef&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://jonliv.es/">Jon Cowie&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning Chef gave me the basic concepts, but Customizing Chef gave me the deep understanding I needed to evaluate the tool for my large, complicated organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the closed-source Microsoft world, you figure out what the thing can do and just accept it. The book opened my eyes that Chef allows me to use a skill (reading code) that I&amp;rsquo;ve built up for over ten years. This leads to a much deeper understanding of how it works than just &amp;ldquo;trust us this feature does X&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s not the best thing about the book though. The thing I appreciated the most was the ability to learn from the author who implemented a world class deployment solution for &lt;a href="https://codeascraft.com/">Etsy&lt;/a> using chef. The examples he provided were real world. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t a textbook exposition on chef. You could tell that this was the real deal. Learning from him in this way reinforced the idea that chef was something I could implement in my complicated organization and that with every problem that arises I have options because of chef&amp;rsquo;s extensibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The author did a wonderful job at explaining that extensibility with examples at every level. I learned how to customize chef&amp;rsquo;s notification customizations, cookbooks, and even knife itself. Every explanation of a customization didn&amp;rsquo;t merely explain it; it started with the code and took the reader through a series of examples to build up understanding of the customization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Customizing Chef isn&amp;rsquo;t for someone who is just starting chef. For that I would recommend the tutorials or the book Learning Chef. For someone who is tasked with implementing it in a complicated organization or someone who has been using it for months and has come across some scaling challenges, this book is a life-saver.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning Chef Book Review</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-learning-chef-book-review.jpg" alt="Learning Chef Book Review" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A couple of months ago I found myself drowning in the learning curve that was &lt;a href="http://chef.io">chef&lt;/a>. I had great support from them, but I&amp;rsquo;m the type of person who needs to know a technology in order to appropriately evaluate it. I could tell that chef was a nice technology, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went through &lt;a href="https://learn.chef.io/">the tutorials&lt;/a> but they weren&amp;rsquo;t adequate for me to understand the solution. Then I found the book &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1Ajqayd">Learning Chef&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Learning Chef is an excellent first step in understanding the chef universe in order to get started on the right foot with the tool. I absolutely loved the tutorial, incremental approach that &lt;a href="http://misheska.com/">the&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://sethvargo.com/">authors&lt;/a> take to go from running a recipe on your own machine to running tests on locally available virtual machines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which leads me to my other pleasant surprise of this book: it lays out the techniques you can use with chef in order to test what you&amp;rsquo;re doing so you know that it works. That is what separates chef from many other solutions I&amp;rsquo;ve seen: &lt;a href="http://kitchen.ci/">they bake testing into the process itself&lt;/a>. If you&amp;rsquo;re going to treat infrastructure as code then you &lt;em>have&lt;/em> to test it as a part of your deployment pipeline. Fortunately this introductory book doesn&amp;rsquo;t skimp on this core aspect of chef.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The third great thing about this book is that it is very approachable to those of us who have built their careers programming in the Windows environment. Every command has a hint at what you would do on a windows box. This really increased my comfort level with learning chef by allowing me to learn it in &lt;em>my own&lt;/em> development environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book is not for people who want a quick, few hour understanding of chef to get up and running. For example if I bring a new team on board with Chef, I probably won&amp;rsquo;t hand them this book; I&amp;rsquo;ll probably do a couple of day class with them to teach them the basics. If they&amp;rsquo;re the type of person (like me) who wants to dig deeper though and learns by doing, this book is a fabulous step in becoming proficient at using chef.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>