<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>budgeting on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/budgeting/</link><description>Recent content in budgeting on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:00:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/budgeting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lowering Expenses with Contentment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 08:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/lowering-expenses-with-contentment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-lowering-expenses-with-contentment.jpg" alt="Lowering Expenses with Contentment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/">YNAB&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/">Dave Ramsey&lt;/a> entered our lives, we became an unstoppable force to meet our financial goals. Our original debt payoff forecasts were beat by a mile, largely because we got serious and focused all of our time, energy, and money to debt payoff. We had met some really great goals and were feeling great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there was a problem. After we met our debt payoff goal, the angels did not descend from the heavens and make everything better. And there was still an insatiable appetite for more stuff. The only difference was that now I had more money to spend on getting that stuff. It was like we had finished a long diet but did nothing about our love of ice cream.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we got more stuff for a few months. And I felt the same. Dave Ramsey has a saying, &amp;ldquo;Live like no one else, so that later you can live like no one else.&amp;rdquo; We had lived like no one else, so that later…we would get depressed about how meaningless it all is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the problem: you&amp;rsquo;ll never win with discontentment. You never find enough. You&amp;rsquo;re always wanting more. So in the long run, the &amp;ldquo;sacrifice now&amp;rdquo; will not lead to peace and balance later, because you&amp;rsquo;re training yourself for discontentment. Let&amp;rsquo;s illustrate this in other areas of life:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>With&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Live like no one else looks like&lt;/th>
&lt;th>But contenment looks like&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Dieting&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to join crossfit and do that multiple times a week, and eat Paleo and judge everyone else who doesn&amp;rsquo;t as idiots&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn how to enjoy the calories I really need, appreciating that I&amp;rsquo;m swimming in a sea of cheap calories that kings of old didn&amp;rsquo;t have&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Work&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to make this happen and work Saturdays and drive everyone to do the same…this is going to launch my career into the stratosphere&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to really think about what and how I&amp;rsquo;m doing things, and make sure I do the right things with the right team, and do those things well&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Marriage&lt;/td>
&lt;td>We&amp;rsquo;re going to go to counseling, a marriage retreat, and then sit down every night and talk&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to give her a break and serve her and &lt;a title="Releasing Control" href="http://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">try to not control her&lt;/a>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Money&lt;/td>
&lt;td>If I get an extra job, I can pay off my debt and get an expensive car ten years from now&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I don&amp;rsquo;t need an expensive car. Or all this stuff. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop buying stuff and find that I have a lot of money left over that I can save. And wow, I&amp;rsquo;m happier!&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Sometimes the middle column is called for. But only temporarily, because discontentment leads to discontentment. It&amp;rsquo;s a neverending cycle. And the only way to get to where you want to go is through contentment. You may need to spend a few months moving the needle. Great. The focus though should be on finding contentment in your life, and creating a margin of time, money, and focus that will help you accomplish your goals long-term.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Move the Needle with Dave Ramsey</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 08:00:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-move-the-needle-with-dave-ramsey.jpg" alt="Move the Needle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We had &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">a failure that was the catalyst to change&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/">a tool that would help us change our relationship with money&lt;/a>. Now we needed to get out of debt. We needed to get serious. We needed &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1595555277/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1595555277&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=O5HAQUNJLACSUUTX">Dave Ramsey&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Full disclosure: our household has kind of moved away from some of Dave Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s ideas since 2010 when we drank the Koolaid. I&amp;rsquo;ll get into why in the next post, but for now I want to write what I appreciate about him and how he presented personal finance to us in a way that got us serious about getting out of debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dave Ramsey doesn&amp;rsquo;t do debt. He hates it. To him, the only reason one should get into debt is to buy a house, and he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even fully recommend that one. Most people think he&amp;rsquo;s extreme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s genius is that when it comes to being in debt, being extreme is exactly what is called for. The numbers aren&amp;rsquo;t the reason people aren&amp;rsquo;t getting out of debt; the psychology is. So when you get out debt the Dave Ramsey way, you sell everything. You don&amp;rsquo;t eat out. You think about it every day. You work extra. Maybe an extra job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You get sick and tired of being sick and tired.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The principle here is &lt;em>Move the Needle&lt;/em>. Sometimes it makes sense to get crazy and move the needle in some area of your life. Make a change happen, possibly at the short-term sacrifice of other things, so you don&amp;rsquo;t quit. Once you accomplish something, quitting it is no longer an option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you&amp;rsquo;re needing to make a change and gut it out in the short term in order to create the environment where you can win in the long, term, have at it! I know with getting out of debt, this is the only way to go in order to actually do it. If you try to nickel and dime your way out of debt, you&amp;rsquo;ll never get there because you&amp;rsquo;ll get distracted and go after something else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we got serious and decided to move the needle with getting out of debt, all the pieces fell into place and we got out of debt really quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem is when this becomes a way of life. At some point, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to stop moving the needle. More on this in the next post.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Month Ahead</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/month-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 08:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/month-ahead/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-month-ahead.jpg" alt="Month Ahead" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re at the mall, it&amp;rsquo;s the 12th of the month and you want to buy sunglasses. Do you have the money? If you&amp;rsquo;re living paycheck to paycheck, it depends on whether the mortgage will come before or after your paycheck. It might also depend on your checking account balance. This is normal for most Americans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is also insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best thing &lt;a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/C9FV2R2">YNAB&lt;/a> did for us is encourage us to get a month ahead in income (they call this &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/method/rule-four">Rule Four&lt;/a>). Paychecks we receive in June pay July&amp;rsquo;s expenses. But for most stuck in the paycheck to paycheck rat race, the idea itself seems like a fantasy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were there, definitely, but we got obsessed with getting a month ahead because we wanted to experience its benefits of simplicity, peace, and clarity. Here&amp;rsquo;s how we did it:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We Took Advantage of Bi-Annual Three Paycheck Months.&lt;/strong> Luckily, January 2010 was a three paycheck month. We budgeted every month for two paychecks, so we were already halfway to our goal the very first month. If you&amp;rsquo;re paid biweekly, every six months is a golden opportunity to get ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We Drew a Line in the Sand.&lt;/strong> Before we started using YNAB, &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">we had used our credit card&lt;/a> and were in the process of paying it off. Normally that would have been our top priority, but instead of working on that, we made those off budget accounts and set them to the side and paid the minimum. This rerouted some cash that was planned on paying off a credit card balance to being a month ahead. This is how I recommend approaching YNAB:** what&amp;rsquo;s in the past is in the past; focus on creating a system that will work for your future and everything will fall into place.**&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>All Margin Went to Rule Four.&lt;/strong> We had a few hundred dollars a month that we had extra every month. Sometimes it would go to something fun or to meet one of our goals. When we implemented YNAB, &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of our money went toward this one goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Moved End of Month Bills to the Next Month.&lt;/strong> We paid our car insurance every month. I called the insurance company and had them move the bill to be due from the 28th to the 2nd of the next month. To them it&amp;rsquo;s a few days. But in YNAB, it gets you out of the current month and into the next month…and closer to being a month ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Planned for a Lean First Month.&lt;/strong> We put everything into getting a month ahead, so it was OK if we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the &lt;em>full&lt;/em> set of monthly income for our first Rule Four month. We just needed to cover the necessities, and let a month pass. At that point we would be a &lt;em>full&lt;/em> month ahead on income. This is the time to have one of those &amp;ldquo;I won&amp;rsquo;t buy anything&amp;rdquo; months!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When we were close, we cautiously overrode Rule Three.&lt;/strong> Over the years I have really grown to appreciate the wisdom of &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/method/rule-three">Rule Three&lt;/a>: every month start over and budget the money you have available. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about making every month perfectly balance. When you override Rule Three by carrying a negative category balance, you run the risk of having to focus on your account balances and you lose many of the benefits of the YNAB system. When we were just getting started, and within hundreds of dollars of being able to make it through February on January&amp;rsquo;s income. We had to prepay our portion of a family vacation that would happen in the summer. Rather than wait another month or two to meet our goal, we had that category carry over a negative balance for the next month. We had done the steps before so there was no risk that our balances would get too low.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we&amp;rsquo;re a month ahead, if we&amp;rsquo;re at the mall and we want to buy something, we check the category balance. We don&amp;rsquo;t care about when the mortgage payment will go through, when I get paid, or the checking account balance. All of those variables have been removed because we are spending last month&amp;rsquo;s money this month. Now that we have clarity on just focusing on the category balance, we put our energy into making better decisions. And that for us has made all the difference in helping us go wherever we want to go financially.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Need a Budget</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 07:45:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/you-need-a-budget/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-you-need-a-budget.jpg" alt="You Need a Budget" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I experienced &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/">a financial tailspin&lt;/a> that got my attention enough to make some serious changes in my life. I needed to assemble a team that could help me meet my goals. &lt;a href="http://www.theprayerroomdfw.com/index.cfm?i=11234&amp;amp;mid=25&amp;amp;blogid=4177">A friend of mine&lt;/a> had told me about budgeting software that he had loved that fit with how I liked to budget. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken &lt;a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/C9FV2R2">You Need a Budget&lt;/a> (YNAB, pronounced why-nab) seriously until then, but now was the time to dive deeper into this tool to see if it would fit my needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I found was a great software tool created by a team that cared more about serving people and changing lives than making money. This is a critical piece of being on my team: you must be more dedicated to serving others than to enriching yourself. And the small team that created YNAB was dedicated to service over self. This software has changed my life in so many ways; I feel indebted to them to do whatever I can to make them successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what is so good about this software? A lot, but I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on four aspects:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Simple Enough for Non-Geeks.&lt;/strong> This was a requirement for me. I needed my wife to be involved and she isn&amp;rsquo;t a math nerd or a geek. YNAB presents budgeting in such a simple way that non-geeks, non financially saavy people can understand it with &lt;a href="http://www.youneedabudget.com/support/training-and-education">minimal training&lt;/a> and make it happen. My wife&amp;rsquo;s involvement in our goals has been critical to our success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Focus is on the Right Goals.&lt;/strong> In other budgeting programs, you&amp;rsquo;re focused on account balances or fitting your life in the system. YNAB has great systems for keeping you focused on where you want your money to go, and forgetting about the timing of bills or keeping everything balanced perfectly. So now we think about what our goal is and how to meet that goal, month to month. And then we forget about it and live our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s Reality Focused.&lt;/strong> I was helping a friend set up YNAB, and he said to me, &amp;ldquo;I want to wait until next month to start this so I can buy a couple of iPhones.&amp;rdquo; I informed him that buying iPhones was as simple as allocating hundreds of dollars into a category and then spending it. YNAB doesn&amp;rsquo;t force you into a perfect situation or month. Those don&amp;rsquo;t exist! You simply tell it what you want to do with your money. That can even include blowing a lot of money on electronics; it&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It Plans for the Unexpected.&lt;/strong> it&amp;rsquo;s not expecting you to perfectly plan every cent and then rush to the software whenever something changes. It lets you easily change your plan, or just wait for the next month, where the available money will be adjusted to how well or bad you did the month before. A solid system must plan for noncompliance to the plan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Four and a half years later, YNAB is helping us meet our goals just as it did in the beginning. It is our constant companion through life, always helping us bring together our intentions and our actions. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for something to help you meet your financial goals, you owe it to yourself to look at &lt;a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/C9FV2R2">YNAB&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Failure the Catalyst</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 08:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-failure-the-catalyst.jpg" alt="Failure the Catalyst" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t take credit cards, only cash.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was November 2009, and I was locked into &amp;ldquo;Project: Have a Third Child&amp;rdquo;. Part of the deal I made with my wife is that we could offset some of the hardships of having another child by doing some things for ourselves. This translated partly into changing our half bath into a full bath and completely redoing the furniture and decorating of our master bedroom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As with most home projects, reality quickly surpassed our budget. That was OK. I was going to use my credit card. Nevermind that I promised myself I would never use it in this manner…this totally frivolous remodeling project was an emergency! I would pay it off, I promised. I just needed to get through this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.viperplumbing.com/">My plumber&lt;/a> dug a hole in our foundation, extended the toilet drain to what would be the shower, and charged me a hefty sum to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And he only took cash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As did &lt;a href="http://mastertilesetter.com/">the tile guys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://paulhedgpethpainting.blogspot.com/">the painter&lt;/a>. Crap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The inevitable occurred. I overdrafted our checking account and our finances went into a tailspin that took us a few weeks to get out of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My wife and I awoke to how totally out of control and useless our current financial system had been. Some major changes were on the horizon. But these changes had a beginning in failure. At the time failure seems so terrible, so awful, that nothing good can come out of it. But in reality failure is often a catalyst for change.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>When you fail by&lt;/th>
&lt;th>it is the catalyst for&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>losing your job&lt;/td>
&lt;td>putting yourself on the right path to meet your goals, with the options wide open&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a marital separation or affair&lt;/td>
&lt;td>finding or abandoning your true commitment to that person, which means there will no longer be a lukewarm relationship&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a project failure at work&lt;/td>
&lt;td>understanding what &lt;i>will not &lt;/i>work, so you can pursue what will work either for you or your organization&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>gaining weight&lt;/td>
&lt;td>reanalyzing your relationship with food and an active lifestyle and making changes&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>Failure feels terrible at the moment, but it really is a wonderful blessing because it is the only catalyst I know of for real success. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been able to believe this enough to make failure suck any less, but it sure is nice to know while I&amp;rsquo;m going through it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>