<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>children on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/children/</link><description>Recent content in children on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 08:00:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/children/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Empathy</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/empathy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 08:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/empathy/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-empathy.jpg" alt="Empathy" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>A few months ago we were at my mom&amp;rsquo;s house eating dinner. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know my mom, she&amp;rsquo;s an awesome cook. She had made one of my favorite meals of all time: meatloaf with green beans and mashed potatoes. I was in heaven.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh gross,&amp;rdquo; the middle child exclaimed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parental embarrassment ensued, and then we got to talking about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mom talked about how her dad&amp;rsquo;s rule as he was growing up was that no one complains about food. If you do, you&amp;rsquo;re just going to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">have to figure out&lt;/a> a way to make it to the next meal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That was my mom&amp;rsquo;s rule growing up. Complain and wait until the next meal to eat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And from that day onward that has been our rule. You don&amp;rsquo;t complain about food. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to like it. But be polite and don&amp;rsquo;t whine about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A couple of days ago we sat down to tamales, rice, and corn, and the middle child was being a pickle about the tamales. He stepped over the line and Mom said, &amp;ldquo;You may be excused&amp;rdquo;, which is code for, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not eating until breakfast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He sat there and cried and the look on his face of ‘I will not be eating for another 12 hours and I was already starting to feel hungry&amp;rsquo; was in full force.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I felt truly bad for him. He made a mistake.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that you can&amp;rsquo;t really relate to your children with love until you learn how to truly empathize with their mistakes. A few days ago I had a breakthrough in that. &lt;strong>My middle son needed to learn how to treat others. But he also had to deal with a bad situation.&lt;/strong> Taking away the consequence wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been empathetic: if there&amp;rsquo;s no pain in which to share, then there is no empathy. But also acting coldly towards him with a &amp;ldquo;this is how it is&amp;rdquo; attitude isn&amp;rsquo;t empathetic either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My wife saw that I had felt bad for my son, and she interpreted it as questioning her judgement on the consequence. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t it at all. &lt;strong>Empathy holds this strange place in between allowing consequences and loving others.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Empathy is when you share in someone&amp;rsquo;s suffering. It&amp;rsquo;s something I discovered a few days ago with my son and something that will transform my relationship with all three of them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>