<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>success on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/success/</link><description>Recent content in success on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 08:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our Culture's Script</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/our-cultures-script/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/our-cultures-script/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-our-cultures-script.jpg" alt="Our Culture Script" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We want our lives to be &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">a work of art&lt;/a> and reflect the beauty and meaning of our values. Most of us in search of meaning in our lives will naturally absorb our culture&amp;rsquo;s script for us:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>To create a beautiful work of art, you must feel good. To feel good, first you must make good money. You need to go to school and then get a good, stable job.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Once you get the job, start maximizing convenience. Pay for things you no longer want to do, including mowing the lawn, making meals, washing your car, fixing your house, going to the store. You work hard so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do these things.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Also, make sure you are as comfortable as possible. Get a nice big house you can be comfortable in, a nice, new car with leather seats that feel great, and stop at the ice cream store and give yourself a treat that makes you feel like a kid again. You deserve it because you work hard.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>You won&amp;rsquo;t be happy unless other people respect and want to be like you. So when you get a car, get something that will show everyone how hard you have worked. When you go on vacation, make sure it&amp;rsquo;s something totally awesome that will show how you have great taste and can afford the finer things in life. You want to be the best you can be. You&amp;rsquo;ve worked hard for this.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>You need to be happy. That&amp;rsquo;s what life is about. So make as much money as possible and spend that mainly on three things: convenience so you can focus on the things that really matter, comfort so you won&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by annoyances and pain and can focus on enjoying life, and respect so you can be validated that you have done something meaningful with your life.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with this? Well, nothing if it works. The problem is, when we think through this approach we don&amp;rsquo;t actually see anyone reaping its benefits. Instead we see millionaires that need more. Actors who are on drugs. Affairs. It&amp;rsquo;s an absolute mess out there. There&amp;rsquo;s never an end. There&amp;rsquo;s never enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t a good way to create a life of meaning and value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to sell stuff though.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This script does nothing about the biggest human problem: &lt;strong>no matter how much you have today, you always need more.&lt;/strong> Once you realize that, the above description becomes silly. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uEY58fiSK8E">You&amp;rsquo;ll never have too much convenience&lt;/a>. No matter how much comfort you have, you know people who have more and that makes you feel…uncomfortable. There will always be someone who gets more respect than you do. Your needs are &lt;em>insatiable.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is unavoidable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The solution? &lt;strong>Accept insatiability as a fact of life,&lt;/strong> dealing with it on a regular basis, and you will have a shot at sanity. How do you do this? Keep reading to find out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generosity with the Unexpected</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/generosity-with-the-unexpected/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 08:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/generosity-with-the-unexpected/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-generosity-with-the-unexpected.jpg" alt="Generosity with the Unexpected" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Every year we sit down and create a specific set of goals for my projects. The &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">goals are always aggressive&lt;/a>, and every year we wonder to ourselves how we are going to do it. Most years we spend the first few months trying to come up with a strategy for even making the goals possible. This is by no means an easy endeavor. And &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">achieving the goals&lt;/a> on this list is extremely important to me. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t tell the whole story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is not on the list is just as important to my future as what is on the list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the past five years &amp;ldquo;Getting a team set up on &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/">TeamCity&lt;/a> has never been an explicit goal. Neither has &amp;ldquo;introduce and administrate &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/youtrack/">YouTrack&lt;/a> to increase the maturity and efficiencies of teams.&amp;rdquo; Or &amp;ldquo;introduce &lt;a href="http://git-scm.com/">git&lt;/a> as a superior version control alternative to TFS and Subversion&amp;rdquo;. But to me, these things that don&amp;rsquo;t make the list are major contributors to my success because they foster an attitude of generosity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t believe success happens without generosity. Plans never explicitly state &amp;ldquo;be generous to others and solve problems.&amp;rdquo; But those who follow this path end up being lifted up by those whom they served, being served in return. I think this is a secret to my success: &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/">serve others generously&lt;/a>, which builds a community of generosity of which I am also a recipient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In contrast, the one who is stingy and focuses only on that which will advance one&amp;rsquo;s own intersts will end up hitting a ceiling of productivity. At some point those around her are alienated, aren&amp;rsquo;t growing enough to contribute at higher levels, or aren&amp;rsquo;t properly engaged in the vision of growth that is required for success to be achieved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a standing invitation for anyone to put thirty minutes on my calendar to get Continuous Integration (TeamCity), issue tracking (YouTrack), or distributed version control (git) set up on their project. Even though it isn&amp;rsquo;t on the list of my explicit goals, it is my pleasure to make the world a better place, and, in turn, it indirectly helps me reach my own goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In what ways has generosity led to success for you?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Releasing Control</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 08:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-releasing-control.jpg" alt="Releasing Control" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thank God we&amp;rsquo;re in marriage counseling so my wife can finally get her crap together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A thought that most people have when they enter the marriage counselor&amp;rsquo;s office. I came into the office that day of &lt;a href="http://www.drlescarter.com/">Les Carter&lt;/a>, with &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">my wonderful wife&lt;/a>, ready for some change. I had a list of things. She was this. She was that. Why can&amp;rsquo;t she just…?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we started I heard a similar tone from my wife. She had a similar list, where only the subject had changed. He is this. He is that. Why can&amp;rsquo;t he just…?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;OK, OK,&amp;rdquo; I thought. &amp;ldquo;I can play this game. So the one with the highest score at the end wins. I will &lt;em>definitely&lt;/em> have a higher score at the end of this one, honey, don&amp;rsquo;t you worry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Les wasn&amp;rsquo;t playing that game. Les gave us a nugget of wisdom that is now a mantra for us:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The more you try to control, the less you are in control. The less you try to control, the more you are in control&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Les was touching on a key element of success: &lt;strong>&lt;em>it&amp;rsquo;s not about creating the perfect level of control so you can have everything your way.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> It&amp;rsquo;s about serving, helping, and loving others. It&amp;rsquo;s about making others around you successful. Somehow when this happens, you end up having more success and control than ever. But it&amp;rsquo;s never about the control itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can be applied in many ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>When you want&lt;/th>
&lt;th>You must&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>a good marriage&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Chill out and let your spouse have some space&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>To be a good parent&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Give them freedom to be themselves, which does include structure, but also includes having their own personalities and interests&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A project at work to succeed&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Enable those around you to be the best they can be and believe in them as you let them work&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Financial security&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Accept that there will be ups and downs and you won&amp;rsquo;t know when those will be, so it&amp;rsquo;s best to be a long-term investor who doesn&amp;rsquo;t bail whenever the market is in trouble&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>When has giving up control given you more control in your life?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Failure Masquerading as Success</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 08:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-failure-masquerading-as-success.jpg" alt="Failure Masquerading as Success" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the grades I should have had in high school. My parents didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything saved up for college when I turned 18*. By living at home, under my mom&amp;rsquo;s insurance, and getting support from my dad, I was able to end my Junior year of college with a few thousand dollars of student loans and no credit card debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. I &lt;em>needed&lt;/em> to have a successful college life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I began believing that there was a real risk that I was going to look back at my college life as a failure. People in college are supposed to experience community, friends, fun, unfettered learning. Living with mommy and having a job was seriously impeding those goals. I had only one year to make things right. So I did what any idiotic 20-year-old would do: I quit my job waiting tables at an upscale restaurant in Dallas, moved into a dorm, and maxed out my student loans and credit cards to make it happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the next fourteen months I had a lot of fun. I hung out with interesting people, was in walking distance to most of my life, and expanded my mind through books and interesting classes. Based on the terms I had set out for myself, the year was a success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest with you: I spent many years paying off the tens of thousands of dollars I borrowed in that fourteen month period. The years of debt repayment that followed brought home an important truth:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>what felt like success for those fourteen months was really failure masquerading as success.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When success is real it flows to all areas of life, not just on the area that has the focus. It also flows into the future, not just the present.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When financial success turns a healthy, compatible, and loving marriage into a hate-fest, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success at work turns colleagues from respect and honor to anger and disdain, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success in marriage creates isolated, ignored children, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success on my project this quarter leads to years of rework and confusion, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I believe success does have tradeoffs. There are &lt;em>failures&lt;/em> that always &lt;em>accompany&lt;/em> success: having dinner with your family might mean someone else who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to do that will get promoted instead of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that a wise definition of success has collateral damage.&lt;/strong> I believe a life of peace and balance is possible. Anything else quickly becomes failure masquerading as success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Has failure ever masqueraded as success in your life?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What they did do though is tell me over and over again how important it was for me to go to college, something I am thankful for to this day&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Achievable Contentment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 09:30:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-achievable-contentment.jpg" alt="Achievable Contentment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing great here, and you&amp;rsquo;re an asset to what we&amp;rsquo;re doing. We think you have a bright future with us.&amp;rdquo; My boss was obviously happy &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">with my performance&lt;/a> and was telling me about it in no uncertain terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s great, and I appreciate it, but when will I get promoted to Software Architect?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted more than anything at that point in my career to be a &lt;a href="http://money.cnn.com/magazines/moneymag/bestjobs/2010/snapshots/1.html">Software Architect&lt;/a>. The title comes with respect, a great salary, and a leadership position within a software development organization. Most people who knew my goal never questioned its efficacy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>…But I now see that it was the wrong goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A good goal is one that delivers what it promises: contentment and happiness.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contentment I envisioned after getting the promotion very quickly became discontentment wrapped around another, bigger goal. All of the sudden I wanted to be a Senior Software Architect. And then more. And more. This is insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a better way: goals that lead to contentment. Some examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>You&amp;rsquo;ll never be content with having&lt;/th>
&lt;th>But you will be content with&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>The next promotion&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Doing work that matters and being fairly rewarded for it&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A big raise&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Spending less than you make, whatever it is&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A new luxury car&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A car you can afford&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>The spouse of your dreams&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A marriage based on love, acceptance, and peace&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>In the left column, everything seems so deceptively simple. &amp;ldquo;All I want is a Mercedes.&amp;rdquo; Well, yes, but _what happens when you get the Mercedes? What &lt;strong>then?&lt;/strong> The left side is one in which you never end up at a destination. You are always striving, always anxious, always gunning for the next thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The left column is a series of steps in life that all follow a commonly accepted pattern of &amp;ldquo;going for the next thing&amp;rdquo;, but arriving nowhere important. These goals ultimately lead to misery and despair once one inevitably finds this out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s strange is that no one questions this path to success, even though there are so many examples of burned out, depressed, unhappy people who have followed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A better definition of success is on the right side. These are achievable goals, not in a few years but right now. The goals aren&amp;rsquo;t as measurable, and those around you won&amp;rsquo;t notice them as much as they would a new Mercedes. However, they deliver what they promise: achievable contentment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Success is achievable contentment through goals that have an end to them. The end of a truly success-oriented goal isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>another goal.&lt;/em> It is contentment and peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are your goals? Where will they lead?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christmas with Russians</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/christmas-with-russians/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-christmas-with-russians" alt="Christmas" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>It was Christmas 2008, and the world was going to end. We didn&amp;rsquo;t know if there would be an economy or even civilization. And I had two weeks of vacation to end the year. I had an 18 month old who was mostly occupying himself with Christmas toys, and my wife was two months away from having my second child. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to take the vacation, but the policy at the time was &amp;ldquo;use it or lose it&amp;rdquo;, so I took it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could have done anything with those two weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I chose to set up &lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/articles/continuousIntegration.html">Continous Integration&lt;/a> for one of our largest products through &lt;a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/teamcity/">TeamCity&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was something I was passionate about. I had &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0026772IS/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0026772IS&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=RJ6US3SXFLCWDTR5">read the literature&lt;/a> on how transformative Continuous Integration had been to organizations. This product was built twice a day by a homeade tool called bmcon.exe and some batch files. If the build broke, dozens of people stopped everything to try to get it working, with no clear feedback mechanism for knowing what went wrong, who did it, and whether it was being worked on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was my moral duty to fix this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it so happened that those working on TeamCity were going to take their Christmas holiday&amp;hellip;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas_in_Russia">on January 7&lt;/a>. They were Russian. So I took it upon myself to monitor the email and get the build working over the Christmas holidays. I remember on Christmas day &lt;a href="http://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/TW-6471">I was conversing with&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://de.linkedin.com/in/jonnyzzz">Eugene Pentrenko&lt;/a> across the world about how to deal with the complexities of TFS pulling thousands of files and then building them*.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Years later, almost all of our products build with TeamCity, and we have thousands of integration tests and tens of thousands unit tests that run on our 100+ build agents to make it happen. It is central to everything we do. And it all started one Christmas years ago when I had a &amp;ldquo;moral duty&amp;rdquo; to do something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008KPM424/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B008KPM424&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=hedgeopscom-20&amp;amp;linkId=52YQPMBZ7Z4IMUKU">Selling with Noble Purpose&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href="http://www.mcleodandmore.com/what-is-selling-with-noble-purpose/">Lisa McLeod&lt;/a> leads the reader through an exercise where the reader thinks about situations where one makes a difference with customers, in a different way than other people, while loving what they are doing. When I went through this exercise I was reminded of this story. Through the exercise I found my noble purpose:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>I share tools and insight for success&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is what truly excites me, and why this blog exists. I want to share the tools and insights I&amp;rsquo;ve found to succeed. I want to help those who have given me tools and insights that have made me more effective by spreading them to others. And I want to properly define success so I can make sure to follow the path that will lead me there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the next few posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about key elements of &lt;em>true&lt;/em> success. Success is one of those things that seems easy to see in others, but never seems recognizable in ourselves. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve found a few reasons why this is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>_* You can&amp;rsquo;t see it in the issue I link to above but Eugene was emailing me and went above and beyond, after his normal hours, to resolve the issue._&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>