<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tolerance on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/tolerance/</link><description>Recent content in tolerance on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/tolerance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ultimate Test of Tolerance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 08:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-ultimate-test-of-tolerance.jpg" alt="Tolerance" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I am fortunate to be married &lt;a href="http://reclaimed.house">to someone&lt;/a> who shares many of &lt;a href="http://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">my values and passions&lt;/a>. For the things we disagree with, though, I have to find a way &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/releasing-control/">to not control her&lt;/a> and to let her be her own person. This is the ultimate expression of tolerance: she is welcome in my personal space, influences my future, and is free to &amp;ldquo;ruin&amp;rdquo; it with her own dreams and values.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The key to making it work is giving her freedom and working hard to connect so values and goals can be shared as much as possible. It won&amp;rsquo;t always work, but if it does, then it is the start of a lifestyle of this, which opens up so many wonderful relationships in all areas of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We like to think of tolerance as something that happens with people who are drastically different than us. With people from other political parties, religions, or backgrounds. I&amp;rsquo;ve found over the years that tolerance really begins with those who are closest to me: &lt;strong>do I try to control them or do I let them freely be themselves?&lt;/strong> That&amp;rsquo;s ultimately the question that is asked of all of our relationships. The less we control, the better the relationships are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Assumption of Agreement</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/assumption-of-agreement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/assumption-of-agreement/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-assumption-of-agreement.jpg" alt="Assumption of Agreement" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We were having a great time with our new friends from California on a gogi-berry farm in New Mexico. The family loves nature like us, and we had great conversations about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/engineering-travel/">biking&lt;/a>, hiking, &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">living simply&lt;/a>, and cooking naturally. At one point the lady told us that they would love to have us back next summer and that they were pleasantly surprised to find out that there were liberals from Dallas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was eating dinner at my church on a Wednesday night with other members, and one member starts talking about how evil Wendy Davis is and how Obama has ruined everything. I sat there quietly as the whole table seemed to being railing on how dumb the Democrats were and how the world was going to end because of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s the common thread? It&amp;rsquo;s what I call the&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.chrisdikes.com/2013/05/30/the-ever-changing-idea-of-god/">Chris Dikes Assumption of Agreement Hypothesis&lt;/a>. From his post:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One common thread I&amp;rsquo;ve found is this:  people want, sometimes even insist, for you to agree with them and what they think about God/religion.  Divergence of opinion and differing ideas are seen as a threat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t get that.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well said, Chris. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it, either. I think this extends to politics and lifestyle, as well. We all assume that everyone in our group will think of us as being intelligent and on the right path. Anyone who thinks we&amp;rsquo;re not on the right path is obviously a threat to that and must be silenced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want to grow, influence others, and sharpen our thinking we need to grow past this. &lt;strong>Disagreement isn&amp;rsquo;t a threat&lt;/strong>. &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/">Everyone doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to agree with us&lt;/a>. In fact, if we&amp;rsquo;re truly honest with ourselves, &lt;strong>&lt;em>people who disagree with us are much more effective at changing our perspective when we let them.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> We can never get there if we&amp;rsquo;re not open to the assumption that there are pleasant people with whom we have a lot in common that fundamentally disagree with some of our religious, political, or cultural views.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Litmus Test for Tolerance</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-litmus-test-for-tolerance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-litmus-test-for-tolerance/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-litmus-test-for-tolerance.jpg" alt="Litmus Test" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>About ten years ago, &lt;a href="http://www.anniehedgie.com">my wife&lt;/a> and I were deeply involved in a church that claimed to be evangelistic and desperately wanted to lead people to God. We devoted ourselves to The Cause and poured hours and hours of our labor into its programs. At one point (I kid you not), I was doing the music on Sunday mornings, keeping track of our procedure for keeping and maintaining new members, leading youth group on Sunday mornings and Wednesday nights, attending another small group Bible study, and taking a graduate level Seminary class. All of this while having a full time job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s the problem, looking back on it: I wasn&amp;rsquo;t growing. Why not? I believe a simple litmus test could have exposed it for me very quickly. It&amp;rsquo;s a test I have run through my life quite extensively since this experience:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>In the past three months, how many people have been in my home that can and will openly but respectfully disagree with my political, religious, or cultural views?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my overcommitted church days, that was no one outside of my extended family. I was a part of a giant echo chamber. I suppose this is true of a lot of people at church. You hear over and over again in those environments that the key is to be outwardly focused, but then when you actually survey those within the organization itself, &lt;strong>&lt;em>many have absolutely no personal contact with those outside of their political, cultural, and religious beliefs.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So do you think of yourself as someone who is growing and tolerant of others? Test out that thought by inviting someone over who doesn&amp;rsquo;t share your political beliefs, or was born outside of the United States. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, doing so will open up a whole new realm of fulfillment and growth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Proper Understanding of the Opposition</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-proper-understanding-of-the-opposition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-proper-understanding-of-the-opposition/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-proper-understanding-of-the-opposition.jpg" alt="Opposition" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun exercise: first read the first five headlines on &lt;a href="http://www.dailykos.com/">DailyKOS&lt;/a>. Next read the first five headlines on &lt;a href="http://www.lucianne.com/">Lucianne&lt;/a>. See any patterns?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On DailyKOS&lt;/strong> you get the feeling that Republicans are heartless idiots with half a brain, and that our world&amp;rsquo;s problems would be solved if they would just get out of the way of progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>On Lucianne,&lt;/strong> you get the feeling that Democrats are heartless idiots with half a brain and that our world&amp;rsquo;s problems would be solved if they would just get out of the way of progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re the typical American, you probably relate to one site and not to another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve only recently recognized how destructive this is to my life, my thinking, and my relationships.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to pursue &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">a life of meaning and purpose&lt;/a>, I need to be constantly open to the reality that &lt;strong>&lt;em>I don&amp;rsquo;t have all the answers&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> and pursue growth in all areas. If I&amp;rsquo;m doing this right this means that I will learn from people with drastically different perspectives than me. If I was only a part of the American Political echo chamber on either side, I would in effect cut myself off of half of the country&amp;rsquo;s ideas and thoughts. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a recipe for growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to deepen my ability to think about tough, difficult issues the world faces, I need to be constantly open to the reality that &lt;em>&lt;strong>tough issues cannot be reduced to simple soundbite answers those from the media on both sides provide.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> If I go through life just listening to one side and thinking that if the other side would just grow half a brain we&amp;rsquo;d all move past these elementary problems, I end up being mentally lazy. And I don&amp;rsquo;t grow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I want to have people in my life that I can influence, I need to constantly be open to the reality that &lt;em>&lt;strong>I can never influence people who totally agree with me.&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> That&amp;rsquo;s an impossibility built on a perfectionistic lie that the only think keeping people from succeeding is their idiotic ideas that you have obviously moved passed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So if you&amp;rsquo;re a Republican and meet a Democrat and think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;What a tool of the liberal media elite&amp;rdquo;, you&amp;rsquo;re killing the relationship right then and there. You may still spend time with this person and some of it may be enjoyable. But if you think that someone in terms of a tool and not a thinking breathing person, they will notice this and they will not listen to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Growth in meaning, thinking, and relationships begin with accepting that you don&amp;rsquo;t know everything and thus could be wrong. It then follows that you accept all types of people in your life to sharpen and grow your perspective. Following this path is much more rewarding than stewing for years and years about Obama, or Bush, or the Iraq war, or whatever else you might get upset about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A European Education</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/a-european-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 22:14:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/a-european-education/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-a-european-education.jpg" alt="European Education" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Yesterday I was at lunch with a Czech friend of mine talking about education. His daughter just started the first grade and this week they had their initial teacher conferences. The teacher informed him and his wife that the daughter had a hard time focusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Of course she can&amp;rsquo;t focus; they have her there from 8AM to 3PM. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t focus at that age either!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It never occurred to me that there was anything out of place about the duration of the American elementary public school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I asked him how long school was in the Czech Republic. He said that first graders would be out by 11:30 AM. Wow, what a way to solve the problem of so many kids who are diagnosed with ADHD but may just need to run around and climb a few trees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our exchange student last year brought some perspective as well. She explained that when kids in Czech are in the fourth grade, they separate the &amp;ldquo;academic&amp;rdquo; ones from the non-academic ones. The academic ones are prepared for the university. The non-academic ones are prepared for a vocation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So instead of forcing a bunch of people into a mountain of student loan debt that puts them in a career or job that they don&amp;rsquo;t perform in, we could train them to &lt;em>not&lt;/em> go to college, save a ton of money, get back years of earning instead of going to school, and live much more confident and productive lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of labelling kids as being bad because they can&amp;rsquo;t (unnaturally) sit in a room for seven hours with a few breaks in between, we could limit the amount of time young students spend in school.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I absolutely love having friends with different perspectives and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/" title="Life is Art">life experiences&lt;/a>. The American system is not the only good system; it&amp;rsquo;s not even the best in most things. Without my European friends, I would never see that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Life is Art</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 08:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/life-is-art/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-life-is-art.jpg" alt="Life is Art" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Earlier this year, I was pretty excited about some &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/">drastic changes&lt;/a> we had made in our lifestyle. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m excited about something, I must tell someone and my friend at a dinner party at my house was no exception. I excitedly pointed out all the ways that simplicity has led us to a life of greater contentment and tranquility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could sense my friend becoming increasingly uncomfortable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Well, not everyone can live that way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My friend assumed that I view life as a science; that there are certain rules that &lt;em>must&lt;/em> be followed and a right and wrong way to do things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I completely disagree with that notion. To me &lt;strong>life is more like a work of art.&lt;/strong> You have a canvas on which to paint decisions, consequences, and ultimately meaning. Every life is as different as every work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When a painter presents her painting, she is expressing herself in a unique way that is unlike anyone else. The painter has &lt;em>her&lt;/em> way of painting. To her it &lt;em>feels&lt;/em> like the right way, because, of course, she did it that way. Another painter may do it totally differently. A wonderful and mysterious thing happens in the gallery: &lt;strong>each painter admires the brilliance and beauty in the other&amp;rsquo;s work of art.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I am creating a work of art that I hope to be beautiful and meaningful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the entrepreneur who spends her nights and weekends creating a groundbreaking service that improves the lives of millions of people. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the philanthropist who travels the world to find a way to cure malaria worldwide. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of the video game developer who works for two solid years to create a game that captures the imagination of a teenager who stays out of trouble because he has something to do when he&amp;rsquo;s out of school. But I can appreciate his work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not creating a life of a hospice nurse who works the night shift helping dying patients find dignity and meaning in their final days. But I can appreciate her work of art.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m creating a life of tranquility, meaning, and purpose. I do this through simplifying life in every facet, achieving in the marketplace through a fearless pursuit of adding value, and creating margin in my life to build a legacy with those around me, especially my family.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is my work of art. This is the journey I will share with you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It isn&amp;rsquo;t the only way.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I want it to be beautiful, and I want to share it with you because I hope we can inspire each other to make our lives a beautiful work of art.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>