<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lean enterprise on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/lean-enterprise/</link><description>Recent content in lean enterprise on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 09:30:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/lean-enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning from Ebola Healthcare Workers with Enterprise Problem Solving</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 09:30:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-learning-from-ebola-healthcare-workers-with-enterprise-problem-solving.jpg" alt="Learning from Ebola" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In a large enterprise it can be difficult to implement large meaningful change. On many days I have ended up frustrated while sitting down to a margarita during &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/">one of my quarterly retrospectives&lt;/a>. How do I get through all the opinions and politics to create real, lasting change? After reading about &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">the Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a>, I have a new way of thinking about it, which starts with healthcare workers in West Africa &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/news/international/21625813-ebola-epidemic-west-africa-poses-catastrophic-threat-region-and-could-yet">fighting Ebola&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When these brave individuals arrive to risk their lives and help others, they are met with a striking contrast to the first world. As you have probably learned, there are entire tribes of people in West Africa who celebrate the recently deceased within an elaborate ceremony where the entire tribe drinks after the deceased loved one in a shared cup. Science certainly had nothing to do with it, but science does tell us that when the deceased person has Ebola, this is a surefire way of getting the whole village infected. Couple this with the cultural norm that those who are sick should travel large distances to medicine men who will heal them, and you have an epidemic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, faced with such a terrible situation of men, women, and children dying every day due to a horrible disease, what do I imagine is the reaction of these healthcare workers? Do they pound their fists and whine, &amp;ldquo;We could change this situation if these people weren&amp;rsquo;t being so &lt;em>stupid?&amp;quot;&lt;/em> Do they clock in and out, thinking that the problem is just too large and that they will just collect a paycheck so that they can support their family? In other words, is their primary approach to the situation that of &lt;em>frustration&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think they certainly feel frustration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, these people are professional scientists, and they probably follow &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_method">a much different formula&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>First, they start with a hypothesis.&lt;/strong> They ask themselves, maybe if we visit the tribal leaders we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to convince them that this practice is dangerous and that will stop the spread of this disease. If the leaders cannot be convince, then they may say that the tribes are a lost cause and that maybe they should lock down the entrances to the cities. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are hundreds of ideas that they come up, all without despair, but with a genuine hope that something can be done to improve the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Next, they test the most promising hypothesis.&lt;/strong> The team may decide to educate the tribal leaders. They then create a short-term way to test their hypothesis. They decide to go to one village and talk to the tribal leaders then pay an informant to record the activities of the next funeral, which is likely to happen in the coming days. They try this with ten villages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Finally, they measure the results of the test.&lt;/strong> Out of the ten villages, only two changed their practices. While many of us might view this as a failure, the scientists see this as success. We now know what &lt;em>wouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> be helpful. Now we can come up with a better hypothesis and start the process all over again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method is what got us technology, medicine, and progress. &lt;strong>Why aren&amp;rsquo;t we using it in the enterprise?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is Continuous Delivery Needed in Our Organization?</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/is-continuous-delivery-needed-in-our-organization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 08:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/is-continuous-delivery-needed-in-our-organization/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-is-continuous-delivery-needed-in-our-organization.jpg" alt="Continuous Delivery" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Continuous Delivery sounds wonderful when &lt;a href="http://www.infoq.com/interviews/jez-humble-lean-enterprise">you&amp;rsquo;re at a conference&lt;/a>. You hear about companies like &lt;a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/netflix-continuous-delivery">Netflix&lt;/a> that deploy to production many times per day. When &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/learning-chef-book-review/">learning Chef&lt;/a>, people often ask me if we really need something that will enable us to deploy that often. Some of them are on projects that take many months to deliver, and the customer would have it no other way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I answer this problem by splitting it up into two questions:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How quickly does a customer want a Severity 1 defect fixed in production?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d say the answer to this is usually, regardless of the tooling used, within a few hours. If there is a critical defect affecting operations, no one is talking about how we&amp;rsquo;ll have that delivered in a few months. People are on phones, developers are doing what it takes to get done, and something happens. So I&amp;rsquo;d say in this situation it&amp;rsquo;s a great investment to automate your delivery so the emergency situation is as tested as the non emergency situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>How quickly does a customer want a feature in production?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a trickier question. We can separate the answer into what the customer &lt;em>wants&lt;/em> and what the customer &lt;em>expects&lt;/em>. The customer &lt;em>wants&lt;/em> to have the feature in production right now. Otherwise they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have told you about it. I have never heard a user make a request for change in software and say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just letting you know, I&amp;rsquo;d rather have it six months from now.&amp;rdquo; Now is always better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, our customers have a business to run, so they&amp;rsquo;re not going to be foolish with updates. They want us to &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/safety-net/">fully test and properly deliver the software&lt;/a>. So I believe their answer to this question would be: &lt;strong>as quickly as you can safely get it to me.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a flexible arrangement based on the trust we create from automating our delivery and testing process. The better job we do, the more they trust us and the quicker they get their software. It will probably never be _today_that they get updates, but also if we&amp;rsquo;re taking this seriously it also shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a long time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So even for us, with real customers that are paying us to get it right, there is room for continuous delivery and Chef.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progression of Responsibility</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 08:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/progression-of-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-progression-of-responsibility.jpg" alt="Progression of Responsibility" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>While reading &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zxdulv">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, I&amp;rsquo;m coming up with &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/">a lot of great ideas&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/">improvements for my organization&lt;/a>. Much of the book so far has been about how to properly execute portfolio management within an enterprise to make sure that (1) you maximize ROI, and (2) you don&amp;rsquo;t manage your existing proven products with an investment horizon of this year or this quarter the same way that you would manage innovation products that have a longer investment horizon. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something occurred to me though. In order to gain entry into the higher level strategic decisions, one must first master the lower level ones. Here&amp;rsquo;s a progression I can see, that I wish I knew about ten years ago:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Personal Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you take on work in an efficient, organized way? Do you have a system for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/getting-things-done-action-plan/" title="Getting Things Done Action Plan">getting things done&lt;/a>, a system for communicating with others, for follow-up, for &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/failure-the-catalyst/" title="Failure the Catalyst">what to do when things get difficult&lt;/a>? Do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/two-questions-about-commitments/" title="Two Questions You Should Ask About Your Commitments">when you&amp;rsquo;re overcommitting&lt;/a>?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Planning Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you understand why we are doing what we are doing on this project? Do you measure things in terms of how they will profit your company or on some other, less meaningful way? Do you have a way to create value for your stakeholders quickly by strategically prioritizing certain things over others? Do you know what the short-term and long-term risks to the product and what can be done about them?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Management Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> do you know &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/measure-for-reality/" title="Measure for Reality">how to measure success&lt;/a>? Have you linked the measurement to profitability of the company? Are you able to iteratively create improvements to measurements in a fluid, changing situation? Are people motivated by your leadership and understand the parameters that you&amp;rsquo;ve set out that measures your team&amp;rsquo;s success?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Executive Effectiveness:&lt;/strong> are you able to create profitability for the various products in your portfolio in a way that respects their lifecycle? Are your established, older products increasing in quality and customer satisfaction? Have your newer innovative products succeeded in creating new markets, as measured by appropriate metrics? Has your team leadership received the appropriate amount of direction (not too detailed to constrain innovation and not too broad to create chaos)? Have you had innovation experiments that have failed in the past three months, that had minimal investment yet provided a valuable lesson for the leadership team?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Right now I&amp;rsquo;m at #3. It&amp;rsquo;s fun reading about #4 in the book, but I do realize the trap of trying to live in a place that is beyond your current capability:** If you live in a later stage than you&amp;rsquo;re at right now, you end up ignoring the key elements that are needed to progress to the next stage.** So I can start thinking a lot about portfolio management or how we would manage innovative products differently than our established products. But if I get too caught up in that, I avoid the reality for me right now: I need to find a measurement of success that leads to profitability of my company for every project that I&amp;rsquo;m doing, be able to communicate that to others, and manage its improvement with a team. That will be my focus over the next year or so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone comes to me about how we need to do a better job planning yet don&amp;rsquo;t have an established workflow for how they manage their own work, I quickly get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone wants to be a manager of a group but can&amp;rsquo;t see what that group is doing strategically and the trade-offs that exist in the group, I get them focused on that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to master your current responsibilities before you can progress to others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Lean Startup Cycle</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 08:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-lean-startup-cycle/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-lean-startup-cycle.jpg" alt="Lean Startup Cycle" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>When &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hermann_Hauser">Herman Hauser&lt;/a> created a team to create the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARM_architecture">ARM processor&lt;/a>, now the processor that runs most of the mobile devices you know and love, &lt;a href="http://www.pcpro.co.uk/features/358750/whatever-happened-to-hermann-hauser">he remarked&lt;/a>*:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When we decided to do a microprocessor, in hindsight, I think I made two great decisions. I trusted the team and gave them two things that Intel and Motorola had never given their people: the first was no money and the second was no people. They had to keep it simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When you start a project the normal course of action is to try to get as many people as possible so you will be able to have enough resources to accomplish the goal. In &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1HdjuUt">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>, the authors advocate another way, what they call &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_startup">the Lean Startup Cycle&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Working out what we need to &lt;em>learn&lt;/em> by creating a value hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Decide what to &lt;em>measure&lt;/em> in order to test that hypothesis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Design an experiment, called the &lt;em>minimum viable product&lt;/em>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Build&lt;/em> the minimum viable product to gather the necessary data from real customers to determine if we have a good product/market fit.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The authors continue:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trick is to invest a minimum of work to go through this cycle. Since we are operating in conditions of extreme uncertainty, we expect that our value hypothesis will be incorrect. At this point we &lt;em>pivot&lt;/em>, coming up with a new value hypothesis based on what we have learned, and go through this process again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I love this idea. Instead of wasting years of time and money on an idea, let&amp;rsquo;s realize that we don&amp;rsquo;t know everything and use the scientific method to get us to the right idea. Let&amp;rsquo;s not be afraid of failure; you can&amp;rsquo;t have innovation without failure. &lt;strong>The key to innovation isn&amp;rsquo;t avoiding failure; the key is reacting to failure earlier than the competition.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method also calls into question the annual budget cycle. If all you have is once chance a year to respond to reality, you&amp;rsquo;ll end up clamoring for more people and avoid the simple, early, scientific method laid out above. A better way is to start small, provide some runway to solve a problem, and scale only when the solution shows its value in the real world.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I got this quote from Lean Enterprise as well, but cite the original source as they did.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mission Command</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 08:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/mission-command/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-mission-command.jpg" alt="Mission Command" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>In the past whenever I found myself micromanaged, I complained that I&amp;rsquo;m not in the military, and I should have freedom to operate in my best judgement to solve the problem. I viewed the military as a command and control environment where orders were specifically given and followed to the T. I then reasoned that this is not how successful organizations operate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The excellent book &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1zGXBeP">Lean Enterprise&lt;/a>&lt;/em> has debunked this myth with a concept of Mission Command that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you. From the book*:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In reality, command and control has not been fashionable in military circles since 1806 when the Prussian Army, a classic plan-driven organization, was decisively defeated by Napoleon&amp;rsquo;s decentralized, highly motivated forces.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Sounds a lot like a startup vs. a large company. Except this is two hundred years ago. The authors continue:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Napoleon used a style of war known as &lt;em>maneuver warfare&lt;/em> to defeat, larger, better-trained armies. In maneuver warfare, the goal is to minimize the need for actual fighting by disrupting your enemy&amp;rsquo;s ability to act cohesively through the use of shock and surprise. A key element in maneuver warfare is beinig able to learn, make decisions, and act faster than your enemy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Once the Prussians were defeated, they studied what went wrong and how they needed to innovate their military strategy in order to regain dominance. Their thought leadership came up with the concept of &lt;em>Auftragstaktick&lt;/em>, or Mission Command:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In 1869, Helmuth von Moltke issued a directive titled &amp;ldquo;Guidance for Large Unit Commanders&amp;rdquo; which sets out how to lead a large organization under conditions of uncertainty. In this ducment, von Moltke notes that &amp;ldquo;in war, circumstances change very rapidly, and this is rare indeed for directions which cover a long period of time in a lot of detail to be fully carried out.&amp;rdquo; He thus recommends &lt;strong>&amp;lsquo;not commanding more than is strictly necessary, nor planning beyond the circumstances you can foresee.'&lt;/strong> Instead he has this advice: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong>the higher the level of command, the shorter and more general the orders should be. The next level down should add whatever further specification it feels &lt;em>to be necessary&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> and the details of the execution are left to verbal instructions or perhaps a word of command.** This ensures that everyone retains the freedom of movement and decision within the bounds of their authority &amp;ldquo;**the rule to follow is that an order should contain all, but also only, what subordinates cannot determine for themselves to achieve a particular purpose.**&amp;rdquo; [emphasis mine]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So with lives on the line leaders implemented a sophisticated framework for implementing strategy while preserving freedom. This happened 150 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s still difficult to implement today, though. We either overdo it with too much control because &amp;ldquo;the leaders know best, that&amp;rsquo;s why they&amp;rsquo;re leaders.&amp;rdquo; Or we give everyone autonomy and everyone ends up going in different directions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These kinds of ideas are what I love about the &lt;em>Lean Enterprise&lt;/em> book in particular and the lean movement in general. Software seems so new to everyone, that you can get caught up in solving problems in new ways and giving crazy names to them, like scrum, agile, TDD, etc. But the lean movement says, &amp;ldquo;Hey, we&amp;rsquo;ve had a few hundred years of solving problems with technology and enlightened thinking. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably find a lot of answers from those who have gone before you.&amp;rdquo; This concept of Mission Control is a great example of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the book also credits The &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/1Hdelfn">Art of Action&lt;/a> for developing these ideas. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read this book but it&amp;rsquo;s on my short list.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>