<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>goals on Michael Hedgpeth</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/tags/goals/</link><description>Recent content in goals on Michael Hedgpeth</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>MIT</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 08:00:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hedge-ops.com/tags/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Grand Vision</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 08:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/the-grand-vision/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-the-grand-vision.jpg" alt="The Grand Vision" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Late last year I started a new project that was dedicated to improving our delivery process and tools. I spent a few weeks talking to people throughout our organization about what the problems were and how we can best address them. And then I came up with &lt;strong>The Grand Vision.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grand Vision was an awesome elevator speech where I drew quadrants and arrows, talked about the main problems I was seeing and how to bring them together into one, totally awesome, unified structure that Would Save The World.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In one of the meetings, a key leader I respect said to me, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s ambitious.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thanks,&amp;rdquo; I replied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a complement&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The lesson I learned is that it&amp;rsquo;s important to map out the process and see how what you&amp;rsquo;re doing fits into the entire goal. &lt;em>But it&amp;rsquo;s also important to solve problems immediately that have a quick return on investment.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This kind of thinking happens all the time:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Ambitious&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Should be&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get rid of all sugar in my house and go GLUTEN FREE&lt;/td>
&lt;td>On Fridays I eat donuts that people bring in the office. In June I&amp;rsquo;m not going to eat any.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to get a gym membership with personal training and wake up every day at 5:30AM and get RIPPED!&lt;/td>
&lt;td>I&amp;rsquo;m going to bike anywhere within 5 miles of my house and do 20 pushups a night&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>We are going to a full week marriage conference in Aspen, Colorado so we can get our marriage back on track&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Let&amp;rsquo;s go on a date and not look at our phones&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to avoid the really tough problems in front of you by dreaming a big dream.&lt;/strong> I think many of us like to think if we can&amp;rsquo;t do it all, then why do it at all? The real battle is won when we drop that all or nothing thinking and get something done&amp;hellip;&lt;strong>today&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When have you let the grand vision distract you from what really needed to be done right then and there?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Failure Masquerading as Success</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 08:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/failure-masquerading-as-success/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-failure-masquerading-as-success.jpg" alt="Failure Masquerading as Success" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the grades I should have had in high school. My parents didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything saved up for college when I turned 18*. By living at home, under my mom&amp;rsquo;s insurance, and getting support from my dad, I was able to end my Junior year of college with a few thousand dollars of student loans and no credit card debt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. I &lt;em>needed&lt;/em> to have a successful college life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I began believing that there was a real risk that I was going to look back at my college life as a failure. People in college are supposed to experience community, friends, fun, unfettered learning. Living with mommy and having a job was seriously impeding those goals. I had only one year to make things right. So I did what any idiotic 20-year-old would do: I quit my job waiting tables at an upscale restaurant in Dallas, moved into a dorm, and maxed out my student loans and credit cards to make it happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the next fourteen months I had a lot of fun. I hung out with interesting people, was in walking distance to most of my life, and expanded my mind through books and interesting classes. Based on the terms I had set out for myself, the year was a success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest with you: I spent many years paying off the tens of thousands of dollars I borrowed in that fourteen month period. The years of debt repayment that followed brought home an important truth:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>what felt like success for those fourteen months was really failure masquerading as success.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When success is real it flows to all areas of life, not just on the area that has the focus. It also flows into the future, not just the present.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When financial success turns a healthy, compatible, and loving marriage into a hate-fest, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success at work turns colleagues from respect and honor to anger and disdain, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success in marriage creates isolated, ignored children, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When success on my project this quarter leads to years of rework and confusion, &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s failure masquerading as success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I believe success does have tradeoffs. There are &lt;em>failures&lt;/em> that always &lt;em>accompany&lt;/em> success: having dinner with your family might mean someone else who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to do that will get promoted instead of you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that a wise definition of success has collateral damage.&lt;/strong> I believe a life of peace and balance is possible. Anything else quickly becomes failure masquerading as success.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Has failure ever masqueraded as success in your life?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What they did do though is tell me over and over again how important it was for me to go to college, something I am thankful for to this day&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Achievable Contentment</title><link>https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 09:30:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hedge-ops.com/achievable-contentment/</guid><description>&lt;div class="full-width">
&lt;img src="https://hedge-ops.com/images/feature-achievable-contentment.jpg" alt="Achievable Contentment" />
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing great here, and you&amp;rsquo;re an asset to what we&amp;rsquo;re doing. We think you have a bright future with us.&amp;rdquo; My boss was obviously happy &lt;a href="https://hedge-ops.com/ten-takeaways-from-the-last-10-years-at-radiantncr/">with my performance&lt;/a> and was telling me about it in no uncertain terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s great, and I appreciate it, but when will I get promoted to Software Architect?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted more than anything at that point in my career to be a &lt;a href="http://money.cnn.com/magazines/moneymag/bestjobs/2010/snapshots/1.html">Software Architect&lt;/a>. The title comes with respect, a great salary, and a leadership position within a software development organization. Most people who knew my goal never questioned its efficacy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>…But I now see that it was the wrong goal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A good goal is one that delivers what it promises: contentment and happiness.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contentment I envisioned after getting the promotion very quickly became discontentment wrapped around another, bigger goal. All of the sudden I wanted to be a Senior Software Architect. And then more. And more. This is insanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a better way: goals that lead to contentment. Some examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>You&amp;rsquo;ll never be content with having&lt;/th>
&lt;th>But you will be content with&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>The next promotion&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Doing work that matters and being fairly rewarded for it&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A big raise&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Spending less than you make, whatever it is&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A new luxury car&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A car you can afford&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>The spouse of your dreams&lt;/td>
&lt;td>A marriage based on love, acceptance, and peace&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>In the left column, everything seems so deceptively simple. &amp;ldquo;All I want is a Mercedes.&amp;rdquo; Well, yes, but _what happens when you get the Mercedes? What &lt;strong>then?&lt;/strong> The left side is one in which you never end up at a destination. You are always striving, always anxious, always gunning for the next thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The left column is a series of steps in life that all follow a commonly accepted pattern of &amp;ldquo;going for the next thing&amp;rdquo;, but arriving nowhere important. These goals ultimately lead to misery and despair once one inevitably finds this out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s strange is that no one questions this path to success, even though there are so many examples of burned out, depressed, unhappy people who have followed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A better definition of success is on the right side. These are achievable goals, not in a few years but right now. The goals aren&amp;rsquo;t as measurable, and those around you won&amp;rsquo;t notice them as much as they would a new Mercedes. However, they deliver what they promise: achievable contentment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Success is achievable contentment through goals that have an end to them. The end of a truly success-oriented goal isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>another goal.&lt;/em> It is contentment and peace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are your goals? Where will they lead?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>